<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>


	<string id="escape_lager_leader_hello_21">
		<text>Stalker. Wait, don't shoot! I'm not a zombie!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="escape_lager_leader_hello_11">
		<text>Stalker. Wait, don't shoot!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_lager_leader_hello_111">
		<text>What the hell?! Who the hell are you? Are you alive?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_lager_leader_hello_1111">
		<text>Alive. Heh. I don't know what to say to you. I'm alive, but I'm not.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_lager_leader_hello_11111">
		<text>What happened to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_lager_leader_hello_111111">
		<text>All I remember is a bright flash. It was about two, maybe three months ago. Maybe more. I woke up at the Doctor's, the one in the swamp. I was with him for about two weeks. He said I was hit by a massive blowout and miraculously escaped. Now I'm hiding out here. There's not a lot of people here, and there's no one here but dogs. There was a kind man in town. He was a journalist. I've seen him a couple times. He was looking for something. He had some documents with him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_lager_leader_hello_1111111">
		<text>Tell me more about him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_lager_leader_hello_11111111">
		<text>Listen, I've been here a week and I haven't eaten anything but rats. If you bring me some human food, say two loaves of bread, I'll tell you everything I know. I'd go myself, but the freedom fighters don't like me much. You understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_lager_leader_hello_111111111">
		<text>Alright.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_lager_leader_hello_1111112">
		<text>Bye.</text>
	</string>


 <string id="7_propusk_done">
    <text>To hell with them. Fucking heroes. You should've seen them, the fucking zone rescue team. Well, you've been doing a pretty good job lately. I don't say this to many people, but maybe you'll do some good. Anyway, I took a look at the paperwork you brought, and it looks like it's only part one. The second part, according to the documents, is here on Cordon. They're supposed to be taken to the Big Land soon. You know what I mean? We gotta take what's ours from the military, right? Yeah, one more thing. These heroes had some kind of base here on the cordon. They used to meet in the garages next to the boiler room. They were pretty good at encryption, so maybe they had a camouflaged entrance, so you'll see... but now let's get to it.</text>
   </string>



 <string id="rat_nov_1">
    <text>Oh, man, here's the story. I've heard a lot about the boiler room.
like a famous stalker died there. Local legend,
so to speak. There's an omen about this place: whoever goes into this place, they'll be haunted by bad luck. So.
I decided to visit the catacombs. I went in. I look up, and there's an entrance
under the ground somewhere. So I thought, let me see what's in there. Man,
you don't know how happy I am to see you. I ain't been out here for half a day. So I come down. I see there's a shitload of hallways and rooms.
and rooms. I go into one. I go into the second one. I went into a third.
My curiosity was piqued, wondering what this place was.
 I didn't know these catacombs were so complicated. Eventually,
I got lost. Hey, man, listen, I need you to get me out of here. Or at least
point me in the right direction. I'll never forget!</text>
   </string>



 <string id="rat_nov_2">
    <text>I'll give you directions, sure. Look, you go that way, and from there you turn left.
Go through the corridor, don't look in the rooms. There's nothing to do. You go down the hallway, and then you go up the stairs.
it's on the right. That's your exit.
</text>
   </string>


 <string id="rat_nov_3">
    <text> Hey, man, thanks. I'm gonna owe you for the rest of my life. Never
I'll go down in these goddamn dungeons again. Fuck 'em</text>
   </string>

 <string id="rat_nov_4">
    <text>Hey, you seen any live stalkers around here?
</text>
   </string>


 <string id="rat_nov_5">
    <text>Nah, man. No matter how many times I've been down here, I ain't seen nothing. Rats and skeletons.
Nothing else interesting. It's a shame. Man, thanks again. I'm outta here.
</text>
   </string>




<string id="jaba_start_phanrom_0">
        <text>You paged me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="jaba_start_phanrom_1">
        <text>Oh, he's here. Good job delivering the box. Appreciate it. So I talked to the Barkeep, and he needs time to figure out what's going on. you know, I guess. I got a case. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="jaba_start_phanrom_2">
        <text>What's the case?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="jaba_start_phanrom_3">
        <text>Well, there was this new guy I know about a week ago. He's not a rookie, but that's not the point. said, "Vovan, I'm going to the Lake Yantar." It was clear that he was dead... he disappeared on the way to the research institute. I never heard from him again, but one of my couriers said he'd seen him periodically under the bridge at night.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="jaba_start_phanrom_4">
        <text>What's that got to do with me?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="jaba_start_phanrom_5">
        <text>Because I got a report online that he's gone. I got a gut feeling something ain't right. I don't know what the hell happened to him. Maybe it's a glitch or-- well, you're the man of the hour, you go and see what's going on with him. He only shows up under the bridge at night. The point is, the locals know he's missing, and they're afraid to go there. I don't want that kind of damage. </text>
    </string>
    <string id="jaba_start_phanrom_6">
        <text>So what am I supposed to do?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="jaba_start_phanrom_7">
        <text>I don't know, I already told you, I don't want him here. Get rid of him. Any way you can. If you do, you can count on me to treat you well. And the loot, of course.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="jaba_start_phanrom_8">
        <text>Alright.</text>
    </string>


 <string id="han_3">
    <text>Only you'll have to get in touch with the Jackal - he knows where the stash left over from the Jolly Fox. an inheritance of sorts. You haven't forgotten that the bridge is now guarded by a sniper, have you? So you have to go through the tunnel to the left of the bridge. As the railroad embankment crossed, so contact and go out, but not for long, or dark stalkers will detect and then bye bye... Get in touch through your PDA contacts, and don't show your face there at all.</text>
   </string>


 <string id="han_2">
    <text>Why are you being so coy? Is there some kind of trick to it? Well, the hell with the catch, you're offering good money.</text>
   </string>

 
<string id="han_1">
    <text>Alright, you want to go ahead, I'll give you the bare minimum and you can go on your way. But you need money in the zone, too. Maybe I can be of some use to you with my feeble strength. There's a stash behind the railroad tracks. If you get the goods from there, I'll take care of it. And then we can go further afield if you're so eager. But you'll bring it, I'm sure you're an honest man. And I'll pay you for it... 500 rubles. Hmm?</text>
   </string>


 <string id="jasukkubys_sace_1">
    <text>About the Monolith? There's a lot of rumors about this thing, about the Monolith. All kinds of rumors.
Some stalker told me that Monolith is some kind of-- What did he say? The basis of all human aspirations and desires? Something unique that
to which man aspires. Quin-tez-sen-tsi-ya.</text>
   </string>

 <string id="jasukkubys_sace_2">
    <text>I'm going on, don't interrupt me. He said a lot of clever things back then.
I can't remember them all. I didn't really listen to him. I just wished he'd shut up and get the fuck out of the basement.
and get the fuck out of the basement. He was right about something. Everyone wants to go to the Monolith. Rumor has it
it's something extraterrestrial.</text>
   </string>


 <string id="jasukkubys_sace_3">
    <text>I heard it landed next to the Sarcophagus,
or it punched through the roof of the Sarcophagus and into the fourth reactor, yeah. That's why a lot of people
a lot of people think he's the reason the Zone was created.</text>
   </string>


 <string id="jasukkubys_sace_4">
    <text>Ask around, they'll tell you more than I will.</text>
   </string>


 <string id="jabaarts_sace_1">
    <text>I have orders for artifacts from the Big Land, so to speak. They're the main currency here. Sometimes I need something for scientists, or religious people. it doesn't matter. You give me artifacts, I give you rubles. On special occasions, I can give you a gift.</text>
   </string>

 <string id="jabaarts_sace_2">
    <text>Huh, on earth, listen to me. Have you seen all the beasts roaming the neighborhood? You don't think they're any good, except to rip your suit off? No. Oddly enough, if one of these things gets caught in an anomaly, there's a good chance an artifact could be born. It's a miracle, isn't it? The local newbies don't know about it, so they're just sitting here guarding me, heh.</text>
   </string>


 <string id="jabaarts_sace_3">
    <text>You got it. Alright, let's get down to business. I need a weak gravity gun, and a medium gravity gun, I mean a regular gravity gun. Maybe you've seen one of these before. If you bring them in, I'll take them at a higher price. And if you get both, I'll give you another one of my own. Don't say no, you're always in need of money around here. Especially from me, huh.</text>
   </string>


 <string id="sukkubys_sace_1">
    <text>Hey, I found this case with a code lock on it, locked.</text>
   </string>

 <string id="sukkubys_sace_2">
    <text>Let me see it. Where?</text>
   </string>


 <string id="sukkubys_sace_3">
    <text>On the tower by the train cars where your artifact was.</text>
   </string>


 <string id="sukkubys_sace_4">
    <text>What the-- It's moving or something. Uh, maybe there's some artifacts in there. or maybe it's just junk or something. I'll give you 50 bucks for it. What do you say?</text>
   </string>

 <string id="sukkubys_sace_5">
    <text>No, I'll keep it for now, just in case.</text>
   </string>

<string id="sukkubys_sace_6">
    <text>Think about it, it's good money by local standards. And for a beginner, it's a treasure trove.</text>
   </string>


<string id="sukkubys_sace_7">
    <text>No. Tell me how to open it.</text>
   </string>

<string id="sukkubys_sace_8">
    <text>Well, try talking to the Informant at the bar, maybe he'll give you a hint. You shouldn't have kept it, Messer. I got a knack for this kind of thing.</text>
   </string>

<string id="sukkubys_sace_9">
    <text>Take it. I don't need it.</text>
   </string>



 <string id="nikeagogo">
    <text>Phew, thanks a lot, man. Thought you weren't coming back. One of the patrols spotted something near the bridge. They thought it was an artifact or something, but it was the size of an average person and it was glowing. It was like a phantom or something. We decided to get closer, and the object started to get farther away, so we didn't realize how we got here. We're gonna pack up and head back to our place.</text>
   </string>

 <string id="tips_and_voyaks">
    <text>Commander: Hey, stalker! Stop! Help us out, we're stuck here. Do you have a surge protector? Can you deactivate these fucking anomalies to get us out of here? It's going to take more than one discharger. We can't clear it with one. We've been trying to send an SOS signal for an hour, but the anomalies must be jamming the signal. Talk to me on your PDA, I'll tell you what you need to do!</text>
   </string>


 <string id="tips_esc_trader_about_anomalies_and_voyaks">
    <text>Toad: Careful in this place, there's a lot of anomalous activity. A step sideways and you're dead. Don't forget the bolts. By the way, I'm picking up a strange signal near the railroad tunnel. It's like SOS, but it's distorted or something. Why don't you go check it out?</text>
   </string>


 <string id="jabina_peredachka_name">
    <text>Package from the Stalker Bar.</text>
   </string>

 <string id="jabina_peredachka_desc">
    <text>It's a closed container, pretty heavy. It says on the side, "To Toad, from Rat." #138.</text>
   </string>



  <string id="jhooo_baby">
    <text>Looks like the bandits gave him a bath. In the well. Here's your box, you heavy devil.</text>
   </string>

  <string id="jhooo_baby_2">
    <text>You know, they're humorless dudes after all. That stalker smelled so bad, they had to chase the flies out of the bunker. Yeah. Alright, give him to me, and here's for your work.</text>
   </string>




  <string id="hooo_zzz0">
    <text>I was at your locomotive.</text>
   </string>

  <string id="hooo_zzz1">
    <text>Well? What happened?</text>
   </string>

  <string id="hooo_zzz2">
    <text>There was a mutant on the train. I calmed him down, so I don't think we'll have any trouble getting through.</text>
   </string>

  <string id="hooo_zzz3">
    <text>Yeah. That's it? You didn't see any artifacts? Alright, alright. It's a no-no. Here's the suit, I hope it holds up to the radiation.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="hooo_zzz23">
    <text>There was a weird artifact and a mutant. I calmed him down, but here's the artifact, take it.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="hooo_zzz33">
    <text>Wow, you killed the monster, that's fine. Good for you. But this thing is interesting. Very interesting. Give it to me. Okay. I'll tell you something about this artifact. It's rumored to be able to fly with great force at a nearby stalker or monster. yeah, yeah, you heard me. In theory, even kill... Very mysterious stuff, you know?</text>
   </string>




        <string id="esc_trader_repair_0">
		<text>I've got a science suit for a trip to the research institute, but it doesn't seem very hermetic. Can you do anything with it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_trader_repair_1">
		<text>Yeah, I've got some tools here. I'm not much of a repairman, but at the bar, yeah, I'm more of a fixer, but whatever. So what do you got? Yeah.\n\nIt's gonna cost a lot:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_trader_repair_4">
		<text>Alright, we'll fix it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_trader_repair_5">
		<text>Shit, I don't have enough money. I'll come back later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_trader_repair_6">
		<text>Here, I think it's alright with him now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_trader_repair_7">
		<text>Here you go, everything you need is done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escesc_trader_repair_8">
		<text>Well, that's good. I think we're good.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_trader_repair_9">
		<text>Alright.</text>
	</string>



   <string id="dgonofnb_head_1">
    <text>Are we there yet?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="dgonofnb_head_2">
    <text>We're here. Okay, uh. check your gear again.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="dgonofnb_head_3">
    <text>Alright, shall we move on?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="dgonofnb_head_4">
    <text>There's a gate on the left, go through it, I'll follow you. I'm just going to change. Go on. I'll catch up with you, don't worry.</text>
   </string>
 
   <string id="dgonofnb_head_5">
    <text>I'll catch up with you, don't worry.</text>
   </string>




   <string id="gonofnb_head_1">
    <text>You ready to go?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="gonofnb_head_2">
    <text>Yeah, we can go. You've been to the dump before, right? You probably know the way, but it's best to stick together. So, you got your jumpsuit on you? If you do, we can get out of here. The trader's counting on us for this, so let's not get too heroic... Though we should pick up some loot if we can.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="gonofnb_head_3">
    <text>I think we're good to go.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="gonofnb_head_4">
    <text>Alright. You follow me, I've been there a few times, I know the way. Get behind me and cover me if you can. It's usually quiet here, but sometimes the worst of it can come from the middle of nowhere. Alright, gear's in place, let's move.</text>
   </string>
 
   <string id="gonofnb_head_5">
    <text>Let's go.</text>
   </string>



<string id="maopojanonb_head_1_k">
    <text>You got a science suit that's good enough to go to the research institute?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="maopojanonb_head_2_k">
    <text>Yeah, I got one. A stalker by the railroad tracks found it. It's beat up, but he spent a couple nights working on it, and now it's good as new.</text>
   </string>

  <string id="maopojanonb_head_3_k">
    <text>What do you want for it?</text>
   </string>

 <string id="maopojanonb_head_4_k">
    <text>There's a train that's been lying under a railroad embankment for about 30 years. A passing stalker detected a strange pulsation nearby. The assignment is to go check it out, and if it's an artifact, bring it to him. If you do, you get the suit... It's a nice, safe path, which is good for me. More visitors from the north. But there's a lot of anomalous activity. So I said go to the train wreck and see what happens there.</text>
   </string>



<string id="aopojanonb_head_1_k">
    <text>I don't feel like going on a raid with my partner. I'm more of a do-it-yourself kind of guy.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="aopojanonb_head_2_k">
    <text>I don't know. You'll be sorry you didn't have someone to watch your back. You sure?</text>
   </string>

  <string id="aopojanonb_head_3_k">
    <text>Yeah, I can handle it.</text>
   </string>

 <string id="aopojanonb_head_4_k">
    <text>Look, if you get into any shit, I won't send people to you for help.</text>
   </string>



<string id="pojanonb_head_1_k">
    <text>Ready for your beast in the village. Looks like he's dead.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="pojanonb_head_2_k">
    <text>Strange things are happening. first the controller, now some other shit has come to the village, I'm told. I don't know what's wrong with the zone, but I don't even remember it.</text>
   </string>

  <string id="pojanonb_head_3_k">
    <text>I thought you promised me a jumpsuit.</text>
   </string>

 <string id="pojanonb_head_4_k">
    <text>Yeah, yeah, here you go. And go back to the Research Institute, how much longer are you gonna be here?</text>
   </string>




  <string id="janonb_head_1_k">
    <text>My partner needs a stalker jumpsuit for a raid. Can you do something about that?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="janonb_head_2_k">
    <text>Wow, I've got a couple pieces, but I don't think you can afford them, though.</text>
   </string>

  <string id="janonb_head_3_k">
    <text>Let's get to the point.</text>
   </string>

 <string id="janonb_head_4_k">
    <text>There's a creature in a village just to the left of the bridge. Rare, but extremely bloodthirsty. Those stalkers who were there said that human guts were hanging on the branches, as if it was tearing up its victims. No one's ever seen what kind of creature it is. Anyway, heh, I see you're a brave guy, dashing, running back and forth all the time... yeah. So you kill the bastard, and the suit's yours. That's it.</text>
   </string>


  <string id="janonb_head_5_k">
    <text>I'll take a look. But no promises.</text>
   </string>




   <string id="janonb_head_1">
    <text>About my trip to the research institute.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="janonb_head_2">
    <text>Well? Is there a problem or something?</text>
   </string>


   <string id="janonb_head_3">
    <text>No, nothing. Forget it.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="janonb_head_4">
    <text>Go on then.</text>
   </string>




   <string id="jaba_samyy_start_0">
    <text>Hey! Are you okay? Are you awake? Can you talk? Or should I tell the guys to take you back to where they found you?</text>
   </string>



   <string id="kdenb_head_1">
    <text>Hi. What are you doing here?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="kdenb_head_2">
    <text>Stalker, help me. I was walking around the Cordon, and, uh. I met two guys from the Garbage. Gangsters, veterans. You can tell they're old school. I had an AK, just a regular 74. They just took it away from me. Good thing they didn't kill me, they just shot me in the leg, so I ran away.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="kdenb_head_3">
    <text>So what can I do for you?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="kdenb_head_4">
    <text>I followed them for a while, they went behind the factory. Listen. I've seen you walking around, why don't you give them a warm welcome? I just need a machine gun, that's all. I don't know if they still got one. Well, get me a 74 Kalashnikov. I won't be in debt. If you play around with it long enough to shoot it, when you take it away from them, I'll think you screwed me. Keep that in mind. Just don't forget you're gonna have to give it back, okay?</text>
   </string>



   <string id="nonb_head_1">
    <text>Hey, stalker. Got a question for you.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="nonb_head_2">
    <text>Hey, thanks for the gun again, by the way. What do you want?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="nonb_head_3">
    <text>I'm going on a raid on the MedPribor Research Institute, you ever heard of it? I'm looking for a good partner to back me up if I need to, you know. What do you say?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="nonb_head_4">
    <text>NRI, huh? Hmm, why not? But you see, my equipment's not very good. To go to the research institute, you need a stalker outfit at least. I've heard the radiation there is pretty bad. So let's do it this way. You get me a stalker suit, and then we'll go right away.</text>
   </string>



   <string id="skdenb_head_1">
    <text>About your machine gun.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="skdenb_head_2">
    <text>What about it?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="skdenb_head_3">
    <text>Yeah. Here you go.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="skdenb_head_4">
    <text>Thanks a lot, buddy. I'm going to the village. You come by sometime. Maybe we can work something out together. I'm thinking of going to the dump soon.</text>
   </string>



   <string id="tnonb_head_1">
    <text>I got a jumpsuit for you.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="tnonb_head_2">
    <text>Oh, that's great. I'll just change at the Garbage. We can move right now.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="tnonb_head_3">
    <text>You know how to handle a gun, right?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="tnonb_head_4">
    <text>Huh, you ask me that? I've done things to scumbags you wouldn't even dream of. So... don't forget your overalls, and we'll move right away.</text>
   </string>




   <string id="btnonb_head_1">
    <text>Listen... do you want to raid the MedPribor Research Institute?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="btnonb_head_2">
    <text>What? A raid? With you? So you can put another bullet in me?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="btnonb_head_3">
    <text>Yeah.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="btnonb_head_4">
    <text>Get outta here before I give you a bullet.</text>
   </string>




   <string id="skdenb_head_3_u">
    <text>I got one, but it's a shortened one. You want it?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="skdenb_head_4_u">
    <text>Shit. I guess the bastards drank it. The shortened one's not bad, but it's got more range. It could cost you your life. Alright, come on. Thank you.</text>
   </string>


   <string id="skdenb_head_3_s">
    <text>You know what? I think I'm gonna keep it.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="skdenb_head_4_s">
    <text>Yeah, you asked for help. Well, go on, go on. I'll see you around.</text>
   </string>


   <string id="skdenb_head_3_n">
    <text>I haven't found it yet.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="skdenb_head_4_n">
    <text>There's a bunch of bastards behind the factory. Give them a good kicking, huh?</text>
   </string>



   <string id="skdenb_head_3_s_u">
    <text>I found it. The short one. You know, I think I'm gonna keep it.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="skdenb_head_4_s_u">
    <text>Yeah, you asked for help. Well, go on, go on. I'll see you around.</text>
   </string>







   <string id="pjaba_esli_alarm_0">
    <text>Who the hell are you?</text>
   </string>


   <string id="pjaba_esli_alarm_1">
    <text>This is our place. What are you doing here?</text>
   </string>


   <string id="pjaba_esli_alarm_2">
    <text>Uh, business. I have an assignment, some papers.</text>
   </string>


   <string id="pjaba_esli_alarm_3">
    <text>Papers? Hmm. We don't need them. But we do have something. Shotgun. It's right here, right next to it. It's our work. You can have it, but only if you help us. Some stalker wandered into our lab here, right where we want to build our new sanctuary. But there's a warehouse of big crates we can't move. Take this, it'll help with the heavy lifting. Remove the rubble and chase him away. Come back afterward, we'll talk.</text>
   </string>


   <string id="pjaba_esli_alarm_4">
    <text>So what exactly do you want from me?</text>
   </string>


   <string id="pjaba_esli_alarm_5">
    <text>Clear the rubble and chase the stalker away. The mark is now showing up on your computer.</text>
   </string>




   <string id="zdenb_head_1">
    <text>Well, I think we're all set.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="zdenb_head_2">
    <text>Yeah, we're good now. Well, we'll keep our word. Apparently. you can be trusted. And trust me with something.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="zdenb_head_3">
    <text>The stalker said he came here through the MedPribor Research Institute. He--</text>
   </string>

   <string id="zdenb_head_4">
    <text>Here, take it. Now leave us alone. Wait, here's something else. This pendant is of great value to us. Keep it safe, and you'll always have good luck. Now leave us.</text>
   </string>







   <string id="denb_head_1">
    <text>Hello. How's it going?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="denb_head_2">
    <text>Messer, phew! Yeah, I'm fine! I made it to the bar pretty good. Told people you're a good guy. Oh, by the way, I saw some dudes in weird jumpsuits coming out of the lab, but they didn't seem to notice me. Yeah, and I saw some thug at the entrance. I had to give him one artifact to get out of the lab, you know? Those thugs are fucking crazy!</text>
   </string>

   <string id="denb_head_3">
    <text>Okay, you're welcome. The three guys in blue gear seem interesting.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="denb_head_4">
    <text>Thank you. Trust me, an honest stalker's reputation is worth more than his loot.</text>
   </string>





   <string id="den_head_1">
    <text>Hey. I'm here to see you.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="den_head_2">
    <text>What the hell? Stalker! Shit! I thought I was done for. I found the entrance to a tunnel at the MedPribor Research Institute. I walked for a long time, maybe a day or two, I don't remember. And somehow I came across a door. I thought I was saved, but it was nothing. I climbed in, the door closed from where I came, as if on purpose! And this room was sealed by random clutter. Where the hell are we?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="den_head_3">
    <text>It doesn't matter. What matters is you need to get out of here as soon as possible if you want to live. The way out of the lab is upstairs. I've cleared the way up, the rubble's cleared, you're good to go.</text>
   </string>

   <string id="den_head_4">
    <text>Yes... I'll never forget it, buddy. Thank you. I'm gonna head to the bar now. You get there if you need me. I'll tell everyone you helped me out.</text>
   </string>





   <string id="fuck_you_asshole_grehone">
    <text>Fuck you!</text>
   </string>


   <string id="grena_gm94">
    <text>Thermobaric grenade for the GM-94 grenade launcher.</text>
   </string>


   <string id="wp_grr94">
    <text>The GM-94 hand-held multi-round grenade launcher was developed by the Tula Instrument Design Bureau in the early 1990s. The main purpose of the new weapon was to provide fire support for infantry in close combat, especially in urban areas, as well as for police special operations. A variety of 43mm unitary rounds were developed specifically for the GM-94, including high-explosive fragmentationless grenades, tear gas grenades, and rubber bullet rounds.</text>
   </string>



   <string id="blyaaa_head_1">
    <text>My head is killing me...</text>
   </string>

   <string id="blyaaa_head_2">
    <text>What, you're still here? What are you standing there for?</text>
   </string>

   <string id="blyaaa_head_3">
    <text>...</text>
   </string>

   <string id="blyaaa_head_4">
    <text>Where's my box? Hurry up!</text>
   </string>



   <string id="jaba_esli_alarm_0">
    <text>Phew... I think I got it!</text>
   </string>


   <string id="jaba_esli_alarm_1">
    <text>Messer! What the fuck!</text>
   </string>


   <string id="jaba_esli_alarm_2">
    <text>What's going on?</text>
   </string>


   <string id="jaba_esli_alarm_3">
    <text>Holy shit! You're gonna get me in serious trouble! I told you to be quiet! So you're gonna make up for it! And don't talk back, there's no way out!</text>
   </string>


   <string id="jaba_esli_alarm_4">
    <text>It's just something that happened, you know.</text>
   </string>


   <string id="jaba_esli_alarm_5">
    <text>Shit. Looks like we're gonna have to shut this place down.</text>
   </string>




   <string id="huli_tebe">
    <text>What do you want?</text>
   </string>


   <string id="hooo_zzz">
    <text>Yes! That's it! Thank you, stalker. I'll finally be able to raid the research institute.</text>
   </string>


   <string id="hooo_zzzza">
    <text>Listen, this eye was made for me by a stalker, one of the first in the Zone. He's still alive and living in the Swamp. I vaguely remember his house, but I know I was there. He helps everybody, and everybody calls him the Swamp Doctor. He literally picks up stalkers and mutants in pieces. I mean, it's more like a legend. But I've been there. Take this file. I just don't have anything else to give you. The first time I was at the research institute, I went into a bunker, and there was some kind of lab in the bunker. There was a bunch of junk, like safes or something, and that's where I found her. It's some kind of documentation, maybe it'll come in handy. I mean, information's the most valuable thing in the zone.</text>
   </string>


   <string id="hooo_zzzz">
    <text>No problem. I'm off.</text>
   </string>





   <string id="hooo_baby">
    <text>Interesting. What do you want me to do?</text>
   </string>


  <string id="hooo_baby_2">
    <text>We need to take it away from him. I tried that myself when he was here. He says I'm not offering enough money, he's asking for more. I'd make some money, and there's artifacts here at the Garbage, but-- Look, why don't you go see him? He's hanging out at the Duty checkpoint north of the Garbage. Put some pressure on him, I think he'll be more cooperative with you.</text>
  </string> 




<!--Simulation-->
 <string id="sim_dialog9_0">
    <text>Can you tell me where I can find some artifacts?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog9_1">
    <text>Do you need house keys and bank account numbers?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog9_2">
    <text>That'd be nice.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog9_3">
    <text>You got a point? Go ahead, go ahead, go ahead. There aren't enough artifacts these days, not enough! I remember a month ago, when there was almost no one here, there were artifacts everywhere. And now there's a flood of greenbacks. And it's even cheaper!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog9_4">
    <text>And if you think about it?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog9_5">
    <text>Well, I've noticed a strange thing. They show up in secluded places where there are no people. Look in nooks and crannies, houses, basements, construction sites.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog9_6">
    <text>Thank you.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog8_0">
    <text>Why so shocked?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog8_1">
    <text>Ah? Uh, nothing. nothing.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog8_2">
    <text>Come on, say it.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog8_11">
    <text>No, it's okay.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog8_3">
    <text>There's a story. I was talking to a guy, and he said: How can you not notice Elektra?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog8_4">
    <text>So? Really, how can you not notice?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog8_5">
    <text>So. We talked, I stayed where I was, and he went and hid behind a pile of garbage. A few seconds later I hear the sound of a discharge, I run up there, and there's only a charred corpse, and Elektra next to it.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog8_6">
    <text>How did that happen?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog8_7">
    <text>So that's what I'm getting at... The zone can do things like this sometimes, so don't be rude to it. After all, she can hear you, believe me.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog8_8">
    <text>Then I take it back, if it ain't too late.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog8_9">
    <text>It's just bad luck, that's all.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog7_0">
    <text>What are you doing?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog7_1">
    <text>Do you even care?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog7_2">
    <text>I'm trying to make a living, like most people around here. What else can I do, look at nature, pick mushrooms?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog7_21">
    <text>Why, boil them and they'll be fine, I guess.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog7_211">
    <text>Yeah, and then suffer from ulcers. No.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog7_2111">
    <text>Well, I'll be off then.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog7_11">
    <text>You're a little rowdy, aren't you?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog7_111">
    <text>Back off, stalker!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog7_1111">
    <text>Alright, I'm leaving.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog7_1112">
    <text>I want to do it the hard way!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog7_11121">
    <text>That's it, I'm sick of you! I'm gonna roll you on the ground!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog7_111211">
    <text>I'm leaving, cool it!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog7_111212">
    <text>Try it!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog6_0">
    <text>Why don't you tell me a story?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog6_1">
    <text>You've come to the right place. Have you ever seen a ghost?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog6_2">
    <text>No.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog6_666">
    <text>Yes.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog6_6661">
    <text>Wh-wh-what?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog6_66611">
    <text>I'm kidding, I haven't.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog6_666111">
    <text>You're kidding me! I did! I was walking along a forest belt, and I saw an abandoned house, so I went there for the night. I went inside, checked everything was clean. I just wanted to start the meal, then I hear the door open! My heart went instantly to the heels, I grabbed the barrel and pointed it at the doorway. I feel the cold smell so disgusting that it makes me shiver. And then a transparent figure of an old man emerges from the other room. It stomped around and flew away. Naturally, I didn't need such a night's lodging, so I grabbed my things and rushed away. Now I don't go to such shacks at all...</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog6_3">
    <text>I've seen it! I was walking along a forest belt, and I saw an abandoned house, so I went there for the night. I went inside, checked everything was clean. I just wanted to start the meal, then I hear the door open! My heart went instantly to the heels, I grabbed the barrel and pointed it at the doorway. I feel the cold smell so disgusting that it makes me shiver. Herak, a transparent figure of an old man emerges from the other room. It stomped around and flew away. Naturally, I didn't want to spend the night, so I grabbed my things and ran away. Now I don't go to such shacks at all...</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog6_4">
    <text>Wow! I wonder what kind of power this is.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog6_5">
    <text>You're lying, storyteller!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog5_0">
    <text>Why are you so lethargic?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog5_1">
    <text>Do you have a pill? My head hurts.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog5_2">
    <text>Yes, there should be. Here you go.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog5_10">
    <text>I've got some, but I won't give it to you, you're in short supply.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog5_101">
    <text>Stingy... But nothing, the Zone will remember everything!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog5_3">
    <text>Thanks, stalker! No, just think about it! We were going on a raid with a friend, and we got hit right in our hideout. My friend got hit in the head, but he was lucky not to pass out, so he pretended to pass out, and I didn't have to pretend. They cleaned it all out, assholes! Now I don't know what to do. I spent the last hundred on food yesterday.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog5_31">
    <text>Keep another hundred and you'll figure out how to make money.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog5_4">
    <text>Yeah, it's sad. Well, hang in there. Have a good haul, stalker.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog5_311">
    <text>Wow, thanks a lot. Man, you're awesome! Klondike and good luck, stalker!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog5_11">
    <text>Sorry, I got nothing.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog5_111">
    <text>Oh, man. That sucks! Well, there's no judgment!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog4_0">
    <text>Hello.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog4_1">
    <text>Hello! What are we drinking to?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog4_2">
    <text>Were we gonna drink?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog4_3">
    <text>Uh-uh-uh... no. Well, don't be shy, it's my treat! So what are we drinking to?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog4_4">
    <text>We're drinking to success. in our stalking endeavors.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog4_5">
    <text>You said it well, let's have a drink!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog4_6">
    <text>That's good! And look, do you know anything about bandits? Because one stalker told me about some dark ones, so I didn't believe him, and to check, you know, I don't feel like it...</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog4_7">
    <text>Well, you found someone to ask. You think I wanted to check, don't you?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog4_8">
    <text>No, I know what you mean. A guy I know told me they're assholes and they ain't even human. They're in the Garbage, so watch your step.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog4_9">
    <text>Okay, we'll figure it out. Thanks for the vodka, but I have to get going. Good luck.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog3_0">
    <text>Why are you so happy?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog3_1">
    <text>I had a big fortune with the artifacts, stalker. Interesting?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog3_2">
    <text>Well, in a way, yeah.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog3_3">
    <text>And it wasn't a Klondike, it was an anomaly.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog3_4">
    <text>What, what anomaly? Tell me more about that.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog3_5">
    <text>It's just a gravity anomaly, like, I didn't check it out, you know. Anyway, I found it in the Garbage, near the road to the bar. I was walking along, and then I saw a pile of artifacts lying there, all glowing like a Christmas tree. So I collected them neatly and gave them to the Barkeep. A couple of hours later I decided to go check, and there are more artifacts! So I bought myself a normal suit. It's not comfortable to walk around the Zone in a tattered jacket.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog3_6">
    <text>You're lying to me.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog3_7">
    <text>I bet there's one in there.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog3_8">
    <text>Alright, let's see.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog2_0">
    <text>Why are you so wrinkled?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog2_1">
    <text>Shit. Stalker, go away. My head's already splitting.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog2_2">
    <text>Alright, I'll leave you alone.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog2_3">
    <text>But wait. Imagine, I was walking calmly through the Dark Valley, and then my eyes suddenly went black! When I woke up, I saw that I was already in a bar... what the hell is this, do you know?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog2_4">
    <text>Maybe I do, maybe I don't. I heard somewhere about controllers, that's what they can do. I can't think of anything else.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog2_5">
    <text>About the co-- co-what?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog2_6">
    <text>Controllers.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog2_7">
    <text>I'll have to ask the guys what kind of bastard they are.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog2_8">
    <text>Vodka won't help you, I guess. Well, that's up to you to decide. Come on.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog1_0">
    <text>What interesting stories?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog1_1">
    <text>Stalker, have you heard anything about dwarfs?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog1_2">
    <text>I have. Sure I have.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog1_3">
    <text>A guy I know came back to me the other day. He says he tried to break into some abandoned lab on a raid with his squad. They got in through the ventilation shafts and almost immediately ran into these creatures.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog1_4">
    <text>Why would they want to get into the lab?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog1_5">
    <text>Well, I don't know, but that's not the point. They were wandering around, and they came upon a room. They look, and there is a pile of junk lying there, on top of which one of them is sitting, and others are stomping around, muttering.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog1_6">
    <text>Creepy. Wait, how did they get out of the lab, did these mutants did not smell them?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog1_7">
    <text>Yes, they did! They just kicked back in, they don't remember how they got out!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog1_8">
    <text>Interesting.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog1_9">
    <text>Why are you lying?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog1_10">
    <text>I'm not lying, stalker! Here's a cross for you!</text>
 </string>
 <string id="sim_dialog1_11">
    <text>I won't believe it until I see it for myself. So long.</text>
 </string>




   <string id="derzzx_dialog_0">
     <text>Last mission, you say? Well, I'm listening to you.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="derzzx_dialog_1">
     <text>Last assignment. Map the anomalous zones in the area from the roadblock to the railroad and beyond. It's a simple building, you've already covered that area, there's only a small farm on the right of the highway, where you met Ferret.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="derzzx_dialog_2">
     <text>What's next?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="derzzx_dialog_3">
     <text>There might be a patrol under the bridge, so I wouldn't go there. There's probably a sniper in the tower. You can imagine the risk of a conflict with the military.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="derzzx_dialog_4">
    <text>So how do you take measurements?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="derzzx_dialog_5">
    <text>It's simple. Here, take this device. It measures the activity of anomalous fields. So you approach the anomaly, activate the device, wait a while, then get the results. You got it? Yes, you must only take the measurements in the order I tell you to. Otherwise you won't get anywhere. You'll only mess up the detector.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="derzzx_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="derzzx_dialog_7">
    <text>You get the results, you get your reward. Go.</text>
  </string> 




        <string id="olr_jaba_kill_contrlr">
            <text>Kill the controller</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_jaba_kill_contrlr">
            <text>Where do controllers come from? We'll find out someday, but first let's get rid of them. There's one in the factory. Can you handle it?</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_jaba_kill_contrlr">
            <text>Toad's ordered the controllers killed.</text>
        </string>


        <string id="olr_jaba_one_monstr">
            <text>Kill the bloodsucker</text>
        </string>
        <string id="text_olr_jaba_one_monstr">
            <text>There's a bloodsucker near the bridge. It's not afraid of anyone, it attacks everything, it's already torn many stalkers to shreds. Kill him sometime and we're even.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="desc_olr_jaba_one_monstr">
            <text>Toad ordered the killing of a rabid bloodsucker.</text>
        </string>


 <string id="pr99_0"> 
 <text>So, how long you gonna be here?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pr99_1"> 
 <text>I don't know. The military's right under my nose, it's kind of creepy. Maybe I'll go to the Garbage. By the way, I heard there's a special forces unit missing. Yeah! And you know, they saw a burer at the dump, sometimes he hangs around the hangars, they say he was juggling some corpses, you know? I heard they come from the dungeons in the Dark Valley. Our guys don't go there, they're afraid. I think there's some stalkers down there, but I don't know much about it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pr99_2"> 
 <text>Burer? Good to know.</text> 
 </string> 




 <!--NEW-->
 <string id="esc_about_art_spiral_0">
    <text>Who's the Jackal? I was trapped by his message in the catacombs.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="esc_about_art_spiral_1">
    <text>The Jackal? What's the matter? Well, there was this guy. Interested in going downtown, big guy. He was ex-military.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="esc_about_art_spiral_2">
    <text>He's dead, and there were darkies waiting for me.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="esc_about_art_spiral_3">
    <text>Dark stalkers? Already here? Shit, I can't believe they came through the dungeons to get here. You probably haven't heard, but the whole zone is covered by a post-demonic network of structures. No one's really explored them, and no one knows what's going on down there. I'll tell you, it sucks. Maybe they used him as bait to get to you. You didn't have a conversation last time. But why would they want you? Maybe they were interested in you in your previous life, so they're chasing you now. Yeah.</text>
 </string>

 <string id="esc_about_art_spiral_4">
    <text>Maybe we'll see each other again.</text>
 </string>





 <string id="esc_about_bar_0">
    <text>Is there anything else you can tell me about Bar?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="esc_about_bar_1">
    <text>You can't tell from the way they christened the place, can you? Well, I'll explain it for the special ones. Basically, Bar is the area near the Rostok factory, where the houses of the people who once worked there stand. Well, as you can imagine, they're not there now. In the houses is located the establishment itself, where many people can buy what they need, talk and drink. There's also a base for the Duty faction - strict guys.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="esc_about_bar_2">
    <text>A drink, you say. That's fine, but I'm going there on business. Is there anything I can find out about who Strelok was?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="esc_about_bar_3">
    <text>Strelok. hmm. He must have been there, who knows, maybe he had a base there. There's a lot of abandoned apartments, and not just apartments. Why don't you poke around, see what you can find?</text>
 </string>
 <string id="esc_about_bar_4">
    <text>Alright.</text>
 </string>
 <string id="pr122_0"> 
 <text>So, did you find out anything about those documents I found?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pr122_1"> 
 <text>Yeah, it was a report from a group of military men fleeing the center. The thing is, after the first big explosion that started the whole damn thing, the military decided to launch a large-scale operation behind the power plant, to the north. The operation had over a thousand soldiers and several divisions of equipment. It says that after all this armada approached a certain area with unknown installations, there was a second explosion... The report contains a report that the remnants of this faction have settled all over the Zone. The documents also have a schedule of anomalous fields, this is very valuable information.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pr122_2"> 
 <text>Good.</text> 
 </string> 


 <string id="pr1_0"> 
 <text>I found some interesting documents. Talked to Toad, he said I should come to you.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pr1_1"> 
 <text>So here we are. Wow! This information is very valuable. The information about the military breaking through to the power plant. Leave them with me, I'll show them to my informant, he'll tell me what I can do with them.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pr1_2"> 
 <text>Here.</text> 
 </string> 


 <string id="pr_0"> 
 <text>Toad, I found some documents in that hangar at the Garbage. It says there's a large-scale military operation in the center of the Zone.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pr_1"> 
 <text>What?! No one's seen you?! Do you have them with you?  Hell, if the military finds out, you and I could be in trouble. Look, I don't need those documents, but the Barkeep at Stalker's might be interested. Talk to him when you get to the bar!</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="pr_2"> 
 <text>Alright, alright. I'll talk to him.</text> 
 </string> 




   <string id="der_dialog_0">
     <text>I found the artifact.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="der_dialog_1">
     <text>Great, did you see anything else unusual?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="der_dialog_2">
     <text>There were some military guys. Apparently, they were looking for something out there.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="der_dialog_3">
     <text>That's interesting. I heard that the military was making some kind of breakthrough to the center.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="der_dialog_4">
    <text>Can you elaborate on that?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="der_dialog_5">
    <text>No, I don't know much about that. But I think they can tell you more about it in Bar.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="der_dialog_6">
    <text>We'll see. Here's the artifact.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="der_dialog_7">
    <text>Well done, Messer. Good job.</text>
  </string> 





   <string id="stader_dialog_0">
     <text>What's wrong with me? My head is killing me. Where am I? What do I owe you?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_dialog_1">
     <text>What can I take from you? Besides, you don't remember a damn thing - you don't know who you are, or where you are.Who you are, where you are. You're in the Zone, my boy!</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_dialog_2">
     <text>I'm not a boy, and I'm not yours!</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_dialog_3">
     <text>Yes, you are! Until you've worked your ass off... and food and medicine, and you need to be armed... at least for starters.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_dialog_4">
    <text>What kind of weapons will you give me?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, kid, at first you can get by with a knife. You've got a suit of some kind, it won't protect you from radiation, but it'll be useful against acid things and rat teeth... It's not a resort. And about you, boy - the Zone will judge! Although, if you're still alive... Does the nickname Strelok mean anything to you?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="stader_dialog_6">
    <text>No.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="stader_dialog_7">
    <text>Alright, then. First, why don't you head over to the roadblock? It's not far from here. Take the sealed metal box and leave it under the barbed wire, the place is marked on the map, and from there you'll take the other one... Don't bother the soldiers, they'll pretend they don't know, and they'll try your skin for strength... Do you agree?</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="stader_dialog_8">
    <text>Do I have a choice?</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="stader_dialog_9">
    <text>I guess not.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="stader_dialog_10">
    <text>Then give me your box and let's get this therapy talk over with.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="stader_dialog_11">
    <text>It's right behind you. I only have one question left.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="stader_dialog_12">
    <text>Well?</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="stader_dialog_13">
    <text>What should I call you, because there's a lot of stalkers.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="stader_dialog_14">
    <text>You can call me whatever you want, though. since you can't give me anything better than a knife, call me Messer.</text>
  </string> 









 <string id="stader_0"> 
 <text>Here's your box.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="stader_1"> 
 <text>Well, you're a survivor, kid. Maybe the legends are true, and a three-time survivor of the Death Truck will change the world. We'll just have to wait and see. You didn't happen to look in it, did you?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="stader_2"> 
 <text>Should I have?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="stader_3"> 
 <text>Okay, don't be mad. This is just the beginning, buddy.</text>  
 </string>





<string id="bar_ohran_propusk_0">
<text>Anything else?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_ohran_propusk_1">
<text>Okay, you've done your first task, great. Now, the next one. There's a fun artifact that's been sitting on a tower on a railroad bridge for a while now. Stalkers do not want to go there - quite strong anomalous activities there, but I see that you're an experienced guy, so you will be able to do it...</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_ohran_propusk_2">
<text>So what do I have to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_ohran_propusk_3">
<text>Get me that artifact. Here, take some anti-rads, just in case. Oh, and I think you're gonna need a detector. It's a little low on juice. but it's good enough for one trip into an anomalous field. You should know that it only works on the belt. And it discharges, too. Alright, go on, don't bother your eyes.</text>
</string>


<string id="bar_friend_propusk_0">
<text>I got the artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_propusk_1">
<text>Okay. You survived. You're definitely not new to the Zone, kid.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_propusk_2">
<text>Maybe, but I don't remember anything.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_friend_propusk_3">
<text>Alright, let's not get philosophical. Take what you deserve. Whoa. step aside. Goplit came from the research institute.</text>
</string>


<string id="3_dialog_0">
     <text>I need a gun. What do you want for a real gun?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="3_dialog_1">
     <text>A gun? Huh. What, you're gonna shoot some of the local animals?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="3_dialog_2">
     <text>Well, I think it's foolish to be out here with just a knife.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="3_dialog_3">
     <text>What, you scared of dogs? Or crows?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="3_dialog_4">
    <text>Look, let's cut to the chase. I'm not gonna listen to you lecture me, alright?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="3_dialog_5">
    <text>Okay. you're not gonna-- Digger's back from the Garbage, he's only been in the Zone two months, but he's been doing well, and he's been filling artifact orders. So, I'll contact him now, let him give you a little shooting session. I've got some free weapons for you, but they're not exactly new. A drunk guy came by the other day and forgot them. Here you go. Digger's waiting for you in the underpass under the road.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="3_dialog_6">
    <text>I'm going to go to him.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="3_dialog_7">
    <text>Go on, run, smart ass.</text>
  </string> 



 <string id="3_tader_0"> 
 <text>I came from Toad. He said you could help me shoot.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="3_tader_1"> 
 <text>Hey, let's say I can. Listen to me. There's a flesh on the factory floor. We sneak up on her quietly, and then we take her out, you understand?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="3_tader_2"> 
 <text>Yes.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="3_tader_3"> 
 <text>Just follow me, and when we get close to the mutant, shoot it.</text>  
 </string>





 <string id="33_tader_0"> 
 <text>I met Digger. The factory had a flesh. That's where the gun came in handy.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="33_tader_1"> 
 <text>I know. Okay, so you can handle a gun. You said a flesh was there. hmm, strange. It's a pretty rare animal. They don't usually live here. I've heard of herds of them in a town up north, but here... Alright.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="33_tader_2"> 
 <text>A town? Here? Interesting. people live there?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="33_tader_3"> 
 <text>Yeah, they do. not too lively. Yeah... By the way. I have a case.</text>  
 </string>





<string id="4_dialog_0">
     <text>What kind of case?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="4_dialog_1">
     <text>There's a military raid going on, and the thing is, the last patrol went missing just a couple hours ago in the factory district. I'm getting a clear signal from one of the PDAs, which means someone's still alive out there.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="4_dialog_2">
     <text>You're not saying I have to go check it out, are you?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="4_dialog_3">
     <text>You don't want to walk around the Zone naked, do you? I'm getting an SOS from their commander. Go and see what's going on out there.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="4_dialog_4">
    <text>Okay, what about weapons? You don't know what happened to that patrol, do you?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="4_dialog_5">
    <text>Sorry, things are a little tight right now. Of course I don't know. I don't even leave my bunker. So, let's do it this way - keep a grenade just in case, I think you know how to use it - put it in your suit pocket so you don't have to go into the backpack, and a first aid kit, just in case... You know, there's been some zombies around the plant lately. They're probably being controlled by someone, so be careful out there.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="4_dialog_6">
    <text>Controlling them? What does that mean?</text>
   </string>
  <string id="4_dialog_7">
    <text>Maybe! Listen, if you help me with this military thing, trust me, you can count on a bigger assortment from me. Alright, go.</text>
  </string> 




<string id="44_tader_0"> 
 <text>Are you the commander? What's up?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="44_tader_1"> 
 <text>Ahh... shit... stalker. how did he get here?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="44_tader_2"> 
 <text>Who showed up?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="44_tader_3"> 
 <text>The Controller! He's here! He's up there! We need to see if our lieutenant's alive, he went up-- oh, shit.</text>  
 </string>






<string id="444_tader_0"> 
 <text>I think their squad was attacked by a controller. That's what the commander told me.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="444_tader_1"> 
 <text>Yeah, I got confirmation on the radio. Thank you, Messer. A controller? How the hell would he be here? This is weird.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="444_tader_2"> 
 <text>Looks like he's been wounded. From the looks of him. Can you tell me what he's doing to my brain? Sometimes it's like I can't control my arms when I'm around him. Anyway, listen, you promised you'd share information.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="444_tader_3"> 
 <text>Here, here's a present. I got some provisions in here and a couple cans of jelly. I wouldn't eat it, though. Heh-heh-heh. I don't know if you've seen this anomaly before or not... it's worse than any acid! If you ask how to use it, you take the jar in your hands and throw it in front of you. A new anomaly will form on the spot! Just don't throw them here in the village, understand? Right, now I've got a few things to sort out, so go for a walk for five or six hours. Take a walk around the neighborhood. I'll be in touch. About the controller's influence, who says what? Some people say that you can't even get your hands in the trigger to fire a shot near it... or pull the bolt. Alright, why don't you go ahead. I'll call you. Uh, hold on. Poopy and Blue came from the Garbage on some business of their own. and they're in the village. If you want, try talking to them, see if they can tell you anything about your Strelok. Or tell you about the Garbage. you're gonna go there sooner or later anyway,</text>  
 </string>







<string id="55_tader_0"> 
 <text>Any other errands?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="55_tader_1"> 
 <text>Now you need to go to the bridge. The client, Ferret, is waiting for a delivery and he will pay on the spot. I think he's back from a raid, or maybe he just stole it from someone... Either way, he'll give the money. Don't flick your beak, Ferret is a clever guy, if you hesitate, he'll put you back in the truck where you were found... But this time, I don't think anyone's gonna be able to pump you out. We need to give him ammo, and in return, we need to take what he gives us.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="55_tader_2"> 
 <text>Okay, I'll take care of it.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="55_tader_3"> 
 <text>He's in the single abandoned house near the bridge.</text>  
 </string>






<string id="555_tader_0"> 
 <text>Toad sent me. Here's the ammo. Who's that military guy?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="555_tader_1"> 
 <text>He's from a patrol. He must have gotten away. They've been drinking so much stalker blood, bitches. Next time, they'll know how to organize punitive operations. By the way, is it true you're the only survivor of the death truck?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="555_tader_2"> 
 <text>That's a lie, I'm not really dead.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="555_tader_3"> 
 <text>Relax, I don't want to hurt you. If I wanted to kill you, I could have done it back when you were playing the old Indian on the approach... Look around, you see the view and you can't see me. If you're so tough, you could have figured it out yourself. Is it true about the trucks?</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="555_tader_4"> 
 <text>It's true.</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="555_tader_5"> 
 <text>They say you wanted to kill Strelok?</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="555_tader_6"> 
 <text>Did Toad put the word out?</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="555_tader_7"> 
 <text>Just a rumor.</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="555_tader_8"> 
 <text>I don't know no Strelok.</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="555_tader_9"> 
 <text>You're pretty banged up, kid.</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="555_tader_10"> 
 <text>Who's Strelok?</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="555_tader_11"> 
 <text>He used to be around here, but I haven't seen him in a while. Let's just cut to the chase. I've been here long enough as it is. You better stay put. I wouldn't last a day in the Zone if I wasn't alert every second. I'll leave the backpack, and we'll part ways peacefully. It's not worth it to me to slap you, but I'd like to see how this whole thing plays out. I don't care about Strelok, and I don't care about you. And tell Toad I said hello!</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="555_tader_12"> 
 <text>...</text>  
 </string>



<string id="5555_tader_0"> 
 <text>I took the backpack from the stalker behind the bridge. Here it is.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="5555_tader_1"> 
 <text>You didn't look in it either?</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="5555_tader_2"> 
 <text>No.</text> 
 </string> 
 <string id="5555_tader_3"> 
 <text>Do you have any idea what's in there?</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="5555_tader_4"> 
 <text>It's artifacts.</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="5555_tader_5"> 
 <text>You still don't remember your name or who Strelok is?</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="5555_tader_6"> 
 <text>No.</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="5555_tader_7"> 
 <text>And how you got on the death truck?</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="5555_tader_8"> 
 <text>No.</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="5555_tader_9"> 
 <text>Well, God be with you. I'll have one more mission for you, and you're free to go wherever you want.</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="5555_tader_10"> 
 <text>Aren't you afraid I'll--</text>  
 </string>
 <string id="5555_tader_11"> 
 <text>I'm not afraid. You need me. Without me, you'll have no food, no ammo, no medicine. And if you're stupid enough to slap me, you'll be dead behind every bump, every tree.</text>  
 </string>



<string id="6_dialog_0">
     <text>What do you suggest?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="6_dialog_1">
     <text>I got a tip that there are some documents on the MedPribor Research Institute that can help us get to the center of the Zone. It's a rough area. few people have been there since the big emission.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="6_dialog_2">
     <text>The center of the Zone?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="6_dialog_3">
     <text>A legendary place. Rumored artifact troves and other wonders are all there. I can't leave it out, as you can imagine... There's even a legend of a wish granter, aka the Black Monolith. but that's more of a rumor. I don't really believe in that stuff. They say a certain Strelok managed to get into the center and disappeared. The same Strelok you're looking for, boy.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="6_dialog_4">
    <text>Strelok was at the center?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="6_dialog_5">
    <text>Yeah, although I don't really believe it. There's some legend about some thrice-born that's gonna change the Zone or something, whatever. let's just cut to the chase. So this is your first serious task. You need to find some documents at the research institute and bring them to me. I don't know what they look like, but it seems to be an ordinary white case, in which military men give me something... you've already brought one of these. Yes... and you probably shouldn't go in there alone. Find a partner in the village. Ask around, see if any of the guys will do it. There's a big pack of dogs at the dump, it's not peaceful, and you won't last long there alone... There have been cases. Fucking heroes. Yeah. You got it? Yeah, I promised you the minimum equipment. here. Yeah, grab a couple cans of concentrate you might need.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="6_dialog_6">
    <text>I think I can handle it.</text>
   </string>
  <string id="6_dialog_7">
    <text>Businesslike. Anyway, you go north, you'll come to the Garbage. Be careful. There are two roads leading west from the Garbage to the research institute, one hole in the fence and the main road just north of it. The crossing paths are marked on your mini-map. Ah, yes. most importantly. the surrounding areas of the research institute are almost all contaminated with deadly radiation. The radiation is such that in a minute you'll be glowing like a Christmas tree in your stalker jacket. Anyway, it means that without a special kind of protective gear there's nothing to do there - you'll burn up in no time. So to go to the research institute, you need protection. Perhaps it would help to have a simple gas mask, stalkers walked and walk with a good old respirator and nothing... well, relatively nothing. Well, you don't want to take any chances, do you? Also, of course, the suit must be in good condition, otherwise it will be useless... Prepare yourself thoroughly for the trip. It's going to be a serious sortie, you know... By the way, the sniper from the bridge is gone, you can pass there safely...</text>
  </string> 



<string id="6_propusk_0">
<text>I'm back. I think I found what I need.</text>
</string>
<string id="6_propusk_1">
<text>Okay. That's them. You look like you've been-- I don't know. Alright, I'm gonna need some time to see what's going on here. Why don't you come back to my place in an hour and we'll figure out what to do next.</text>
</string>
<string id="6_propusk_2">
<text>Alright, but I'm a little rusty after that hike.</text>
</string>
<string id="6_propusk_3">
<text>Oh, yeah, here's yours. Now leave me alone with the paperwork. Come back in an hour. That's it.</text>
</string>





<string id="7_katakomby_0">
<text>What is it?</text>
</string>

<string id="7_katakomby_1">
<text>Okay, wait a minute. There's something I need to do. Remember those documents you brought me from the roof of the factory?
</text>
</string>

<string id="7_katakomby_2">
<text>I do.</text>
</string>

<string id="7_katakomby_3">
<text>Don't interrupt me. Anyway, it was about the underground utilities on the outskirts
of the Zone. I mean, right here on Cordon. I don't know what the hell they were built for,
to get supplies into the Zone before the crash, or maybe they used them as a communication point. That's not
 the point. The point is that the documents show one of the entrances to these catacombs.</text>
</string>

<string id="7_katakomby_4">
<text>And you want me to go there?
</text>
</string>

<string id="7_katakomby_5">
<text>Don't interrupt me, Messer. I don't like being interrupted, or didn't you get it the first time?
I sent a group of diggers down there while you were chilling on MedPribor.
Five of them. I sent them out three days ago, and they haven't checked in for a day. But, uh.
they're green, and you're more experienced than those sparrows. Why don't you go and see what's going on.
 Take anything of value you can find and bring it back here. I guarantee you a reward.
The jumpsuit's a gift. I'll deduct its value from the reward. As for weapons, you're welcome to use my selection. All at the lowest prices in the Zone. But, uh.
you'll have to buy them. What are you looking at? It's not like I've got a charity here
for everyone. Be thankful I don't deduct the price of the shafts from your fee, smart ass.</text>
</string>

<string id="7_katakomby_6">
<text>Where's the entrance to these utilities?</text>
</string>

<string id="7_katakomby_7">
<text>There's a water tower west of the factory. They went in that direction. the entrance must be there somewhere. Why are you still here?</text>
</string>

<string id="7_katakomby_8">
<text>I'm on my way out.</text>
</string>





<string id="7_propusk_0">
<text>I'll steal the box.</text>
</string>
<string id="7_propusk_1">
<text>That's good. We need to steal another crate that the military has here on the Cordon. I recommend you wait till night, most of them are sleeping at night. The box itself should be in the commander's office. Yes, and a huge request, don't make any noise, do everything quietly, peacefully, without noise. I could get in serious trouble. I recommend to act secretly, the soldiers are patrolling, but they are doing it from scratch, because they haven't seen a shift for a long time.</text>
</string>
<string id="7_propusk_2">
<text>Got it.</text>
</string>
<string id="7_propusk_3">
<text>Yes, and look, you can kill the military only as a last resort, I don't want any unnecessary problems with them! Got it?</text>
</string>


<string id="77_propusk_0">
<text>Get your box.</text>
</string>
<string id="77_propusk_1">
<text>Alright! Okay, uh... Uh-huh. A picture is starting to emerge, the military is clearly looking for something in the center... What the fuck do they want?! There's a lot of maps and scientific papers. You might want to show those papers to the Barkeep. Rat should be in his office right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="77_propusk_2">
<text>The Barkeep? Where's that?</text>
</string>
<string id="77_propusk_3">
<text>The Stalker Bar behind the Garbage. Then go there and show him those papers, he'll have a better idea of what's going on. You're a good kid, you do jobs that not everyone can do.</text>
</string>

	<string id="escape_talk_about_escape__00">
		<text>Hi.</text>
	</string>



<string id="escape_talk_about_escape__0">
<text>Tell me about this place.</text>
</string>

<string id="escape_talk_about_escape__10">
<text>It's the road to the Zone. You'll find a merchant in a cellar behind a village near an army roadblock. I don't advise you to go to the checkpoint and get caught by the soldiers, they have orders to shoot without warning... You can't kill soldiers, only as a last resort, for each killed merchant has to pay for it and he will not be happy with this arrangement. There are large packs of blind dogs on the plains, it's dangerous for rookies to go near them. Sometimes mutants come through here.</text>
</string>

<string id="escape_talk_about_escape__1">
<text>Thank you.</text>
</string>

<string id="escape_talk_about_escape__2">
<text>What's further north on the road?</text>
</string>

<string id="escape_talk_about_escape__21">
<text>That's the Garbage. It's a grim place. Some of the trash makes it impossible to get through.</text>
</string>















	<string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_11">
		<text>What do you know about that place?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_12">
		<text>You know, it's not good. I've been feeling it for a long time. Our guys may run the place, but they do some weird stuff, even for a place like this.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_13">
		<text>Uh, what are you talking about?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_14">
		<text>If you're gonna spend the night, it's better to stay at the bar or at our base. The Barkeep would tell stories that would make old men feel uncomfortable.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_15">
		<text>They say it's not very safe out here at night.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_21">
		<text>What? Well, you know, you know, it's an area around here, you know. People come and go. Our territory, you could say, is practically a safe passage to the northern territories. Yeah, well, things happen.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_24">
		<text>Like what?</text>
	</string>


	<string id="esc_bridge_soldiers_start_25">
		<text>Well, I heard that not all the families that lived here evacuated after the accident. There were some fanatics or sectarians or something, you know, out of the world. They've been here since before the first stalkers showed up, they say some of them even had contact with them. I don't know how they lived all this time. Then one day, they disappeared, who knows where. Nobody ever saw them again. I'll tell you something. At night, it's better to be out here in the middle of nowhere. Don't sleep in apartments. A lot of them are boarded up, but some of them are still locked up, and who knows what's in them?</text>
	</string>


	<string id="barman_scary_drunk_article_tx">
		<text>The Barkeep's Story</text>
	</string>



	<string id="barman_scary_drunk_article_text">
		<text>The bar patrons and the Barkeep say it's best to sleep in crowded places at night, because the local apartments can be dangerous.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="esc_stalker_talk_level_0">
		<text>Why don't you tell me about this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_stalker_talk_level_1">
		<text>This is the way into the Zone. I don't advise you to go to the checkpoint and get caught by the soldiers: they have orders to shoot at our brother without warning. On the way to the north there will be a destroyed bridge, but there is also a stationary roadblock there. In the open there are dogs running in packs, it is dangerous for rookies to go there. Sometimes mutants wander in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_stalker_talk_level_2">
		<text>What's further north, beyond the roadblock?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_stalker_talk_level_21">
		<text>It's a dump, that's what it is. It's a dark place. Some of it's impossible to walk through because of the garbage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="astrozombies1">
		<text>There's a house in the village beyond the bridge. They say it's very foul-smelling. There must be something there. Some kind of strong source of radiation. I just got a big version of a highly radioactive capsule. I think you can handle it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="escape_lager_volk_in3fo_2141">
		<text>Waste paper, you say. Well, well, well. Alright, since your memory's gone pretty bad, I'll tell you. The main value here in the zone is not loot, not transport, and not even artifacts. What would you think? That's right, information! 
Seemingly ordinary, unremarkable documents, but they can be so much... look around, boy, what is going on here literally behind every bush. Anyway, if you find anything interesting in this field, don't sell it to anyone.
you bring it straight to me, you understand? I'll pay you. I'll pay you good money. Other traders are interested too, but whatever you find, bring it to me.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="escape_lager_volk_talk_1111111111">
		<text>If there's anything to sinter. You've been blownout. No one knows exactly what it is or where it's coming from, but they say it's coming from the center. A wave of psi radiation that kills everything in its path. Yeah... but good for you, you realized you had to hide if you're still standing here.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="escape_lager_volk_talk_111111112">
		<text>I'll tell you in confidence, after a blowout, artifacts sometimes appear. There's a lot of things going on, especially with the animals, but I guess you'll find out. And about the artifacts, here's another thing. There's a rumor that their properties change, depending on how lucky you are. or they can disappear altogether. It's a weird thing about them. Yeah, well, if anything, I warned you.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="escape_lager_volk_talk_511">
		<text>I'm telling you, it's over now. You. Are you a stalker or something? Look around the village, see if anyone's got a stash. And if not, you can eat rats and crows too... if you manage to shoot them, heh. A lot of people like it. Or you can try bargaining with the boys. But will they still want to bargain with you? That's a separate question. Just be aware that what you find will probably be a little phoned in. There's radiation everywhere. You thought you were gonna get a dose yourself, didn't you? Uh, no, everything around here is practically phoned in. Of course, you might find something that's not irradiated. Still, I suggest you get it from me. I get everything clean. It's usually clean. It's just a matter of luck. Why do you think I've been here so long? I'm the only place you can get good stuff for miles. And it's not the fondue shit. That's why they appreciate it, that's why. Yeah, to see if it's phoned in or not, check your backpack. but carry a gray detector. If it does, you'll get a beep.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="escape_shustryi_start_21">
		<text>Didn't you hear the radiation at the research institute is so strong, you'll fry in a heartbeat? I need a stalker suit. And that's the least of it. Anyway, you find one, we'll talk. I heard Toad has one. And besides the suit, you need a gravitational artifact to carry heavy weights... a useful thing for raids, but it makes you want to eat more often... If you can't find a regular gravitational artifact, you can get two simple ones, that's fine.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="escape_trader_jobs_6111111">
		<text>Wow! You're a good kid. You're a smart stalker, not like some of the others. Hey, uh. I promised you a special present. So here, I'm uploading the information on these artifacts to your minicomputer. You know, so you know what they're good for, or you'll starve to death from the effects of them. And here's one for your health, of course.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="tips_esc_trader_about_anomalies_razradit">
		<text>Toad: You're near the tunnel, aren't you? If you have a discharger, do me a favor - discharge the anomaly inside. One of my couriers from Bar should show up the other day, and he only goes through this tunnel. If you do it, I'll thank you. It's the end of the line.</text>
	</string>


    <string id="monozaz1">
        <text>No one knows for sure, but there's a story about him. I heard there was a stalker in the zone who was under a curse or a fate. His partners were dying and death was following him. As if cursed allegedly by the monolith after some time disappear in the Zone, and no one knows what horror finished them off. They have terrible nightmares, they go crazy. It's like that.</text>
    </string>


    <string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_2511">
        <text>I don't have it.</text>
    </string>


	<string id="esc_and_voyaks_article_tx">
		<text>Trapped soldiers</text>
	</string>


	<string id="esc_and_voyaks_article_text">
		<text>A group of military men are trapped at the end of a railroad tunnel. There's a lot of anomalies around. I don't know what's in store for them. Nevertheless, one of them, apparently the commander, asks me  to run to Toad, who's supposed to help them somehow.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="escape_trader_start_dialog_52111">
		<text>The dead head artifact, how about that, huh? If you don't know what kind of artifact it is and its properties, don't even bring it, because you're a thug, you'll kill people and bring me the heads of my honest customers! Yeah. if you don't have any money. I need this stuff badly, and you, if you've got nowhere else to go, you'll have to figure it out. Or money, of course. Keep in mind, I'll take a percentage for every man I kill.  If you were in a group before you joined the assassins, you'll be a neutral again after redemption, because you'll hardly be taken back after that.</text>
	</string>


    <string id="about_anomalies_razradit_article_tx">
        <text>Discharge the anomaly</text>
    </string>


    <string id="about_anomalies_razradit_article_text">
        <text>Toad asked me to defuse the anomaly in the tunnel. Said he'd pay for it. Well, that's what the discharger's for. </text>
    </string>


	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_0">
		<text>I need some answers to some questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_1">
		<text>Ask away, but I don't know everything. You know, I sit here all day, and life is all out there, in the Zone. I can tell you about the Zone in general, and a little I can tell you about the nearest neighborhoods, where I went myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_100">
		<text>Tell me in general about the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_101">
		<text>Ask me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_2">
		<text>What does the military do in the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_21">
		<text>Guarding, what else! Whether it's the Zone itself or the rest of the world from it, it's unclear. Sometimes whole expeditions come through here, looking for something...  But I'll tell you something. The military don't respect the Zone, so it doesn't like them either. They're always being taken out of the zone in coffins. Well, what can I say? They look down on everyone, like they're gods. Stalker's laws are not honored, they will never come to help, even if you die in front of their eyes. They can shoot you, yes, easily, but they're not punished for it... But I've found a common language with some of them. People need to get vodka and magazines somewhere, don't they? You know what I mean. But don't piss them off for nothing. They'll brush it off and never notice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_3">
		<text>Tell me about the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_31">
		<text>The Zone. It's not just a circle of kilometers in diameter centered on a nuclear power plant. It's something strange. Very strange. You know, I don't think anyone in our world can answer that question. I don't think the Zone is part of it at all. It's a world in its own right, dangerous, strange. and bloody fascinating. And you know why? Because everyone here, if they're lucky, can get rich quick. And the closer you get to the center of the Zone, the faster you can get rich.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_311">
		<text>What's the danger of this particular world?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_3111">
		<text>Ahem. Yes, in general, nothing - but you can die here at every step. And not only from a bullet, although... death from a bullet - it is, in fact, the most pleasant death in the Zone. But anomalies are, you know... that kind of death is, yeah, it's scary. Even mutants avoid them. Speaking of mutants: they are also rare trash, children of the Zone, so it is better not to go here without weapons. In general, no one can tell you about all sorts of dangers better than other stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_312">
		<text>How do you get rich here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_3121">
		<text>Well, my friend, you've been hit pretty hard! Did you forget?!\nArtifacts are the basis of everything. For all sorts of obscure toys from the Zone, many from the Big Land are ready to give a fortune. Artifacts are more valuable than gold, diamonds and pure plutonium. Why? Because no other jewelry in the world has such supernatural abilities and shares them with its owner. Just imagine: when you hang a piece of jewelry on your belt, bullets start to avoid you! What else? Well, you can often find small things even here, right next door. But you only go for the valuable stuff closer to the center.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_313">
		<text>Does anyone know what goes on in the center of the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_3131">
		<text>They talk about all sorts of things. They'll tell you all kinds of stuff later. but I don't believe in any of that otherworldly crap. What I do believe in is that the center of the Zone is full of valuable artifacts. But I've never met anyone who could come back from it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_4">
		<text>Do you know what happened to me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_41">
		<text>Well, brother, since you asked! It's a dark matter, you know...\nThey found you in a death truck. Corpse trucks? From time to time they come from the center of the Zone, loaded with bodies... Nobody really knows where they're going. So one truck crashed, and they found you next to it. And that's the most surprising fact of all. They've found wrecked trucks before, but never a live one. I'm sorry, I can't help you any further. You're gonna have to figure this out on your own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_5">
		<text>Who's Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_51">
		<text>He's a stalker. Rumor has it he's one of the few who went to the center of the Zone and came back. Although there's plenty of legends about hero stalkers around here, so I can't guarantee anything. In any case, personally, I have not done business with him - apparently, he has his own channels for sales... In general, ask the people in the Zone - maybe someone will give you a clue.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_6">
		<text>What kind of stalker is called a ghost?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_61">
		<text>Oh, that's another legendary man.  I haven't heard from him in a while. Probably disappeared somewhere in the depths of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_99">
		<text>What's going on around here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_999">
		<text>Ah! Well, this is the antechamber of the Zone. Army cordon. It's relatively quiet, except for the military sometimes having fun, making a mess. Experienced stalkers are rare here, only rookies linger, and who even stay forever, yeah... There's a rookie camp nestled right next door, on a farm. Look, they know how to pull the trigger, too, so don't get cocky.  What else? Well, there's no good loot to be found here. There's an abandoned factory across the road. To the north, behind the railroad embankment, is the remains of a village, and to the south is a roadblock. By the way, there are mines planted somewhere, so be careful. There was also a bridge in the center, but it fell down. That's about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_9991">
		<text>Tell me more about the blockpost.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_99911">
		<text>There's a few soldiers with orders to shoot without warning, so you'd better stay away from it. If you offend them, they can call in the SWAT team from the outer cordon. They'll make such a mess upstairs that I won't have any clients for a month... I don't know the commander of the soldiers much: he likes to lay low. He's the reason I'm still here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_9992">
		<text>Tell me more about the bridge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_99922">
		<text>It's two steps north, you'll see it right away. I don't know for sure, but I've noticed some of the older stalkers sometimes walk along the railroad tracks. Maybe it's a trail.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_9993">
		<text>Can you tell me more about the factory?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_99933">
		<text>When you cross the road, you'll see it right there. It's a brick building. What they could steal from there was stolen long ago, just a box left. It's a favorite place for gangsters. I don't know if they're there now, but be careful. You ain't got nothing to be robbed from yet. but what do you want with all this trouble?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_9994">
		<text>Tell me about the village.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_99944">
		<text>You're so tedious! Well, the village is just like a village! The previous inhabitants were dead before the Perestroika.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_9995">
		<text>Thank you, that's all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_info_9996">
		<text>There's something else I'd like to know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_level_0">
		<text>Tell me about this place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_level_1">
		<text>Ah! Well, it's the antechamber of the Zone. Army cordon. It's relatively quiet, except for the occasional military raid. Experienced stalkers are rare here, only rookies linger, and some of them stay forever. There's a rookie camp nestled right next door, on a farm. Look, they know how to pull the trigger, too, so don't get cocky. What else? Well, there's no good loot to be found here. There's an abandoned factory across the road. To the north, behind the railroad embankment, is the remains of a farm, and to the south is a roadblock. By the way, there are mines planted by the soldiers, so be careful. There was also a bridge in the center, but it fell down. I think that's about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_level_10">
		<text>Okay, thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_level_2">
		<text>Tell me more about the roadblock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_level_21">
		<text>There's a few soldiers with orders to shoot on sight, so it's best to avoid it. If you offend them, they can call in the SWAT team from the outer cordon. They'll make such a mess upstairs that I won't have any clients for a month... I don't know the commander of the soldiers much: he likes to lay low. He's the reason I'm still here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_level_3">
		<text>Tell me more about the fallen bridge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_level_31">
		<text>It's just two steps north of here, you'll see it right away. There used to be a bridge over the road, and then it fell down during one of the blowouts. The military's got a post there and they don't let anyone in. but if you grease up, they'll let you in. In general, it's better not to shine there, unless you're heavily loaded or wounded.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_level_4">
		<text>Can you tell me more about the factory?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_level_41">
		<text>When you cross the road, you'll see it right there. It's a brick building. What they could steal from there, they stole long ago, only one box left. It's a favorite place for gangsters. I don't know if they're there now, but be careful. You ain't got nothing to be robbed from yet. but what do you want with all this trouble?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_level_5">
		<text>Tell me about the farm.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_talk_level_51">
		<text>You're so tedious! Well, it's just a farm. The pigs were dead there before the Perestroika.</text>
	</string>

</string_table>
