<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>     
<string_table>





	<string id="st_knife_old">
		<text>Bayonet</text>
	</string>

	<string id="tip_radio_on">
		<text>Turn on the radio</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tip_radio_off">
		<text>Turn off the radio</text>
	</string>

	<string id="item_taken_text">
		<text>Item received -</text>
	</string>


	<string id="money_in_text">
		<text>Got the money -</text>
	</string>

	<string id="job_try_give_sms">
		<text>A request from a stalker:</text>
	</string>


	<string id="job_try_give_sms_find">
		<text>find:</text>
	</string>



	<string id="job_try_give_1">
		<text>There's a case... We need to find--</text>
	</string>


	<string id="job_try_give_2">
		<text>Yeah, there's something... We need to find--</text>
	</string>



	<string id="job_try_has_1">
		<text>Did you find it yet? I need to--</text>
	</string>


	<string id="job_try_has_2">
		<text>Did you get it? This thing right here--</text>
	</string>




	<string id="oles">
		<text>Researcher.</text>
	</string>

	
	<string id="find_stancia_last_doc_desc">
		<text>It seems that the last, seventh part of the documents in Pripyat is missing... However, I got a message from Freedom that one of their groups went missing in the Chernobyl area, and they had a red folder with them... maybe that's what you need. We should try to find them in the vicinity of the power plant. According to Freedom, they were traveling in an APC.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="amet_dop_seif_raskaz">
		<text>Yeah, I heard that Rat gave you the keys to the old place... You're telling me to put another safe in there? Well... you can, of course. Only, I think you understand some of the nuances... Well, first of all, the safe itself. I remember there was one in some hut here in Bar... let's say I put it together. Then the lock must be put in order with the door, so that no one stole anything, because here people are clever on this case... And most importantly, so that no one steals the safe, it should be magnetized to something. Like against the wall of the house... ask me how? You know about the Magnet artifact, right? So, few people know, it has a property - if you stick it to the surface, it magnetizes any matter. Anyway,.. I'm in, but I'll take 5,000 for the job and four Magnet artifacts. Do you agree?</text>
	</string>




	<string id="enc_esc_evacuation">
		<text>Professor:\nThe group we were expecting is now in the Cordon area, preparing to evacuate the zone. Your job is to go there, and lead the group along the road through the highway to the exit of the zone. I'm sending their coordinates, you'll get all the instructions on the spot. Hurry up. Over and out.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="enc_snotvornoe">
		<text>A pill to induce drowsiness quickly.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mil_go_to_olmy_expedi_text">
		<text>Informant: Messer, one of the stalker squads has decided to move far into the Zone and explore the territory of the Silent Hills. Among the squad's stalkers, more than half are elite. Equipped they were superbly... can you go see what's wrong with them? Anything you find on them is yours. Just tell me what happened to them. Alright? There were three stalkers in the group - two in exoskeletons, one was in a black science jumpsuit, unless of course he'd changed costumes... I know for a fact he's a sniper. They went missing in the area of the village... When you find them, contact me. Waiting for the signal...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="jackal_podz">
		<text>Messer. Here's the thing, the Jackal's been in touch. Sending out an SOS signal. The message was misshapen in the transmission, he had something about the dark ones. Bullshit... I spotted him underground in the Cordon area, obviously from the underground tunnels. Why don't you go check it out? You'll get to see each other face to face.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="space_start_tri_quest_article_name">
		<text>Professor Markov's order #3</text>
	</string>

	<string id="space_start_tri_quest_article_text">
		<text>Markov gave some kind of artifact... in the Bar area, a zombified stalker has reappeared in one of the apartment buildings. Offers to kill two birds with one stone - get rid of a troublesome stalker, and conduct an experiment... We need to plant this artifact next to him, which should... disintegrate the stalker...</text>
	</string>





	<string id="space_start_two_quest_article_name">
		<text>Professor Markov's order #2</text>
	</string>

	<string id="space_start_two_quest_article_text">
		<text>Markov did something with that artifact from the first order... Now we need to expose it to high temperatures...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="krvzovpobeg_name">
		<text>Major Kravtsov: My brother was forcibly drawn to the killers... He was forced to shoot another stalker... or they would have killed him themselves. There was nothing left for him to do... We need to find him, get him out of the assassins' base, then bring him back to our base. Preferably at night, so no one can see you...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="killerdol_one_sttex">
		<text>Working for the Killers... that's new. Looks like the clan leader wants to cooperate? Then why are the others hostile? Too many questions... Nevertheless, you need to kill the stalker at the MedPribor Research Institute. He's hiding in the underground... The leader gave a tip that the basements of the Research Institute can be accessed through the underground of the Garbage, so as not to receive radiation on the territory of the Research Institute... </text>
	</string>




	<string id="dolina_doki_bkoikr_desc">
		<text>We got a tip from Lone Wolf. He made it clear that they wouldn't just let me into the bar... We need to get some documents from the Dark Valley. This will be my fee for passing into the circle of experienced stalkers... There's some crazy psi noise in the Dark Valley, we need protection. So Wolf gave me a tip on a special helmet you can get from the military, near the creek in the Garbage.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="ratlab_strt_talk_haveart_name">
		<text>Toad's account of the lower levels of the Garbage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ratlab_strt_talk_haveart_text">
		<text>According to Toad, he once saw a group of scientists in the Garbage a long time ago. They walked around, measured something, and went off toward the hangar, apparently into the underground rooms. Then, once under the blowout hit them, and may still be lying there by the railway tunnel in a hollow on the Garbage. Maybe I can find something from them that can open up access to the lower levels. You need an access code... Said if I got in and found anything interesting, to bring it to him, he will pay.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="agr_perepat_tainik_article_name">
		<text>The find in Strelok stash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_perepat_tainik_article_text">
		<text>Looks like we managed to find Strelok's stash, but it looks like there's nothing of value here... Found some book, on a side note which stated that the PDA was stashed behind the main scientific complex of the MedPribor Research Institute in the basement... We should try to find them...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="check_gar_rat_cache">
		<text>Yeah, one more thing... there's a case. In that place, in the hangars, there's a passageway... There, deep underground, on the lower level of the tunnels, the stalkers discovered a large metal gate... Scans have confirmed that there are large underground rooms behind the gates... Come on, go downstairs and see what's going on. Report back to me later. I'm dumping the entry point there into your PDA.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="pda_btn_active_jobs">
		<text>Tasks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_active_news_btn_hint">
		<text>List of current tasks</text>
	</string>


	<string id="pda_complete_news_btn_jobs">
		<text>Journal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_complete_news_btn_hint">
		<text>Journal of notes and messages</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_jornal_back_btn_jobs">
		<text>Back</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_jornal_back_btn_hint">
		<text>Back to section</text>
	</string>


	<string id="pda_btn_news_list_btn">
		<text>Messages</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_news_list_btn_hint">
		<text>News and events in the Zone</text>
	</string>


	<string id="pda_talk_list_btn_btn">
		<text>Dialogues</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_talk_list_btn_hint">
		<text>Player dialog log</text>
	</string>





	<string id="scarydom_ftw">
		<text>What the hell is that?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_bio_to_long">
		<text>see profile</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ui_st_bio">
		<text>biography</text>
	</string>


	<string id="find_yaabneayb_1_article">
		<text>A request from the leader of Clear Sky</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bar_dolg_petrenko_start_21">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="taken_docs_vetri_pogo_prof_article_text">
		<text>Winds of Madness...what it means... Anyway, apparently the road to the center of the Zone goes through Lake Yantar, namely a certain scientist Professor. He's the one who's going to have to help me with this... but I don't know if he'll want to help me. Maybe to get what I need, I'll have to work for the academia first...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="pseudohuman_first_checkup_go_article_text">
		<text>Discovered a strange mutant... It looks like a meter maid, only... more disfigured... Maybe we can find something interesting to do with this mutant. Something tells me this isn't just a simple mindless goon...there's something else...</text>
	</string>


	<string id="rat_katacombs_quest_article_text">
		<text>We need to investigate the underground utilities beneath the Cordon. Before me, a group of stalkers had already disappeared there... You need to find some interesting thing for Toad from there and bring it to the Cordon.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="talk_docent_zamer_vibros_article_text">
		<text>Docent handed out a test sample of a device that would be used to stay under the blowout without shelter... But, in order for him to finish his work, this sample must be laid out in the open in the active phase of emission, when it is already hitting the brains... dangerous business.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="tips_jaba_bigcity">
		<text>This is the road to the Big City... it's closed now, the radiation's too strong. That's where that radio program was from... You don't want to go that way right now.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="bunker_find_journl_fin_task_text">
		<text>The journalist is missing. Followed me north... we need to find him, but first, on the Doctor's tip-off, we need to visit his apartment in Shining Path. Maybe I can find something.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="radar_deac_datel_1_task_text">
		<text>Everything seems ready for the trek north... The Duty Group should be waiting on Radar by now. We have a 9 p.m. to 11 p.m. window available... in which time I need to break into the lab and shut down the Woodpecker. After that, in theory, the road to Pripyat will be open...</text>
	</string>


	<string id="bar_dolg_propusk_taskt_text">
		<text>Next assignment from Toad... You need to find some kind of artifact on the tower that is on the railroad bridge and bring it to him. Gotta remember the detector... damn, the battery is completely near zero...</text>
	</string>




	<string id="strelby_pms_taskt_text">
		<text>Got the gun from Toad... it's a mess, but at least it's something. We have to go down the road, under the underpass. There's a stalker waiting for me there, I think I'll need to take someone down with him... Or something...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="doki_ploty_krisha_article_text">
		<text>Looks like another errand. On the roof of the factory, the Flesh that we've slaughtered has made a lair, where Toad says there are documents. We should find them and bring them to him. Without them, he won't talk to me.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="komandir_kontr_article_text">
		<text>Now that's serious business... We need to rescue the commander of the military patrol and get him out of there. It's located at the factory where the SOS signal is coming from. We need to check gear and first aid kits. And a grenade from Toad would be nice...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="esc_find_glaz_zabiy_task_text">
		<text>After another emission, the Toad's Eye artifact appeared in the Garbage. We need to find it and bring it to Toad. He gave me the coordinates. I wonder why no one wants to go after it.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="esc_talk_dolg_garbage_task_text">
		<text>There's a message from Toad saying a certain Boar knows something about Strelok... It is located in the north of the Garbage, at a roadblock of the Duty faction. We need to talk to him, and then go back to Toad and his eye artifact...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="jababoxone_task_text">
		<text>Damn, this sucks. Woke up in a strange place... that Toad is a very murky man. He wants me to work it off, fine. I need to pick up a crate from the bench in the merchant's bunker, and take it to the roadblock. And from there in turn pick up the other box and bring it to Toad...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="esc_start_find_friend_task_text">
		<text>First serious, real outing. We need to be well prepared... It's probably not a good idea to go alone, either. I need to try and find someone on Cordon who agrees to go to the Research Institute with me. It's worth talking to the locals, see if anyone will agree. Well, if not, I guess you can take your own chances...</text>
	</string>


	<string id="jurnwtf_hell645o_sms">
		<text>Talk to the leader of Duty</text>
	</string>


	<string id="jurnwtf_hel22lo_sms">
		<text>On my way out of Shining Path, I received a message from the leader of the Duty faction. We need to talk to him.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="article_find_gravimolot_text">
		<text>There was a message from the Informant in Bar, it is necessary to find in the basements of the MedPribor Research Institute some gravity hammer created by the Burers and bring it to him.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="article_bunker_2_olr_text">
		<text>Well, I guess the truth is out there. Now I can power down the mythical Black Monolith. You need to go down to the lower levels of the lab under Radar, and get to the control room of the installation. The lower door access code is 5489.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="article_yan_helieq_task_text">
		<text>We need to control the flight of the convoy for the Yantar scientists. The professor issued a rifle, which must then be returned... Also, you can't show up in the village and shine there, you have to do everything quietly if possible.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="article_poymat_plot_gm_text">
		<text>The professor gave the assignment to catch the mutant that everyone calls Flesh... how to do it? The hell he knows... It's probably gonna take a lot of running, because it's a cowardly creature. According to the coordinates, it's in one of the houses in Bright Beam.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="boots_start_gruz_task_text">
		<text>The professor said, a car with a load from the Big Land was driving to the mobile base. The connection was cut right at the entrance to the Exclusion Zone on Cordon... We need to find the scientist and deliver the cargo to the Professor. He didn't say anything about the cargo itself, but since his colleague was traveling by car, perhaps delivering the cargo on foot would be problematic...</text>
	</string>


	<string id="yan_food_dat_task_text">
		<text>The science bunker on Yantar is experiencing food supply problems. It is necessary to bring them food for further cooperation. I think ten canned goods will be enough for them. It's worth talking to Toad, maybe he can sell such a large batch in bulk at once...</text>
	</string>


	<string id="yan_spory_take_task_text">
		<text>The professor needs a measurement of the air with the spores of the parasite. In order to make such a measurement, it is necessary to lay out the device given by him near any corpse infected with this contagion...</text>
	</string>




<string id="custom_treasure_rukzak_desc">
		<text>The backpack from a stalker's kit. You can use it as a stash for loot, but you can't fit much in it. Also, you need to consider the fact that it can be stolen, so you should hide it in a secluded place.</text>
</string>


	<string id="jghkkkjhhh">
		<text>When I was born, the Zone already existed... It's true, the old people said that there was a time when the territory of the settlement was outside the Zone... But I don't remember that... There are legends that somewhere there is some Outer World or huge City... that's where the helicopters come from sometimes and the new stalkers come from... But something happened there a few years ago... Maybe the visiting stalkers know something more specific about this Outer World.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="hfghfghgkkk">
		<text>Strelok... he also came from the outside, they say he was an important figure in the outside world, but nobody really knows anything. There were even rumors that fanatics from the Sin Clan believed that something important depended on him... maybe he was thrice-born, too?</text>
	</string>





	<string id="hgfjmasrte">
		<text>Goplit knew something about him, we're from the same village... he always wanted to be a writer, he said he loved the fantasy genre. There heroes always acted there, and even if they were lonely, still defeated evil in the end... Goplit said something about the Journalist, the latter was looking for something, and Goplit bragged that he had found it... but whether he gave it to the Journalist or not, I don't know.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="gfdgdgdfgdfgdjgh">
		<text>Alright, don't rattle on, we'll get to your base, see what you accidentally grabbed. In the meantime, I should get something to eat, because I've forgotten when I've had anything in my mouth other than knocked out teeth. You didn't grab anything but folders in that archive?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="jurnwtf_hello_sms">
		<text>A journalist?!</text>
	</string>

<string id="kiillde_about_arpop_und">
		<text>Hmmm... I'm a business man. You work for us. you're looking for Strelok, aren't you? I have information about him. But do the job first and then we'll call it even, stalker. You're right about the radiation. But, that fugitive who needs to say hello from us is hiding somewhere in the basements of the research institute... and there's no radiation... I mean, in case you didn't know, the Garbage dungeons are connected to the NII underground, so if you go that way, you won't need the suit in theory. I'll give you the passage info from the underground to the NII...</text>
</string>


<string id="find_find_dezintegrator_article">
		<text>To find an unusual artifact</text>
</string>


<string id="dok_find_dezintegrator_article">
		<text>Some scientist on the roof of Bar asked to find him if possible this artifact, attaching only a photo without any description...</text>
</string>





	<string id="documentacia_zombibrain_doki_opis">
		<text>It's an unremarkable folder. You can tell from the cover that it has been used more than once, but all the sheets inside are laminated and uncharacteristically thick. The content is impressive - it's nothing short of a psi helmet assembly manual. Even at a cursory glance, it can be seen that each sheet is designed with the utmost care so that it can be understood by a knowledgeable professional. From the sketches and attached photos, it can be understood that the device is not particularly difficult to assemble, but, judging from the numerous notes and attached experimental results, requires a certain knowledge of neurobiology and cybernetics for fine-tuning, as well as rare or difficult-to-make parts for efficient operation.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="pda_device_pda_majors_desc">
		<text>PDA found a message for someone named Major:
		R-138, there's a new order. From our friends at bloodcall... into an anthill. It's a big order. There's a rumor that a Frankenstein stalker has been seen in the Zone. The Doctor put it together from other stalkers' body parts. Literally. We can't get to the Doctor in the Swamps - too high psi activity prevents us from reaching his hole, but the stalker himself is still wandering around the Zone somewhere. Find him and bring him to the Perimeter. Alive, if possible. I already gave my eagles the Frankenstein's description. But you have a better chance of finding him. Send the number of the account - I'll pay in advance, if you agree.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="pda_btn_bloknot_hint">
		<text>A notebook with personal notes</text>
	</string>


	<string id="pda_btn_bloknot">
		<text>Notebook</text>
	</string>


	<string id="plen_quest_now_kick_article_name">
		<text>Jackal's note</text>
	</string>



	<string id="plen_quest_now_kick_article_desc">
		<text>... The major's got everyone on it to find him... killers...dark... The Doctor..., his masterful work... put together a few pieces... We can't let him get to the Major... you can't...</text>
	</string>







	<string id="osved_poisk_dokumentov">
		<text>I can help with that... Only the result won't be immediate... you know, you have to make inquiries, who's been where when, and so on... Yeah, one more thing. There are two options you can choose from.\nSo the first... two thousand, and in a little while I'll send you the approximate location of the document you're interested in on the PDA.\nEither the second... I'm the one who's pulling my strings and getting you the document you need. All you have to do is come and get it from me. It will cost more... ten grand total. So, what do you need to find?</text>
	</string>





	<string id="radbun_docs_posthuman_desc">
		<text>Test results of the Posthuman Project.\nIn the document folder, you can find a sheet with the title conclusion. Based on the results, the following conclusions can be drawn: 1) the project is still too far from completion, 2) we should focus on finding a method that combines both the intelligence enhancement of the test material and the effective maximization of external cortex radiation, 3) we should involve the neuroengineering department in the project to consult on the issue of psi overload.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="off_yan1_none">
		<text>It's not working</text>
	</string>


	<string id="lvl_nightmare">
		<text>Unknown</text>
	</string>


	<string id="obmennakod">
		<text>Exchange for a code to the lab</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mertv_lead_ab_door_zakazz">
		<text>The leader of one of the bandit groups in the Dark Valley has agreed to give the password to enter the lab. For this information he asks for a VSK-94 rifle, and five bottles of vodka. Or five jars of jelly... He asked me to say hello to the Informant in Bar...</text>
	</string>


	<string id="ratlab_doki_jaba_desc">
		<text>A large pile of papers with various records...\nIn order to make research work safer and more stable (after several unfortunate incidents), it was decided to administer a third kind of psi-influence to all laboratory workers, from cleaners to scientists. Everyone will be fitted with adaptable psi-blocks that will prevent anyone from disrupting operations, rioting, stealing data, and pogroms or escapes.\nMessage 
...there was a conflict between a group of scientists developing psychotropic weapons and the leaders of Project Cover-up. Scientists did not want to be exposed to the rays of the weapons they themselves were developing. Realizing that psi-impact is a matter of time the scientists began to ponder the situation and came up with a plan to free them from danger.
 </text>
	</string>



	<string id="zone_prosby">
		<text>Stalker requests</text>
	</string>


	<string id="zone_zakazy">
		<text>Orders</text>
	</string>

	<string id="zone_sevenparts">
		<text>Found documents</text>
	</string>

	<string id="tip_use_door">
		<text>Open the door.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="enc_meat_coocked">
		<text>Cooked meat. Completely ready for safe consumption.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="doka_sterok_zametka_desc">
		<text>The development of psychotronic weapons initiated in the USSR led to the creation of the OSOZNANIE project in 2006, the laboratories of which are located on the territory of ZOCHAES.
The idea of the projet is to influence the information shell of the earth, the "noosphere", through which it is possible to influence any individual on the planet. A group of scientists, guided by presumably humane considerations, not excluding, however, the mercenary in essence idea of the gray cardinals of the planet, turn on the generators and begin an experiment that allows, in their opinion, to stop violence, war, crime and so on. This idealistic in essence experiment leads to the breakage of something in the very essence of the universe, as a result of which begins to change nature and its inhabitants so far in the local volume of the Zone. Realizing the fact that something unplanned is happening, but at the same time realizing that it is up to them to eliminate the consequences, the participants of the experiment block the passage to the Center of the zone with psi-fields, and create a mythical Wish Granter, located under the sarcophagus of the Chernobyl NPP, which is actually a "Monolith" psi-installation, causing halluciogenic visions, in the form of the apparent realization of the individual's desires.
 Also, the group has a psi influence on the leaders of the states to prevent massive attacks using the army on the center of the zone, which could lead to the destruction of the generators, which still give a chance to return everything to normal. Plus they force representatives of the authorities to prevent people from entering the Zone in every possible way (military stalkers, cordons, etc.).
Their people who have reached the center of the Zone and fallen under the influence of "Monolith", form either squads of zombie defenders, or wipe their memories and take them far away from the center of the Zone, or send the hardiest to eliminate undesirable people, both in the Zone and outside it. This procedure of total zombification is codenamed S.T.A.L.K.E.R.
Strelok is one of the latter. He realistically learned too much to be left alive, but just as any complex system can fail, so in his case, instead of being eliminated, he was zombified and sent to kill himself. And only the fact that he seems to have an innate ability to easily tolerate this kind of exposure has led to the fact that he is still acting sensibly...
</text>
	</string>



	<string id="psy_shapka_proto">
		<text>Prototype T-ZUD-12</text>
	</string>


	<string id="radbun_karta_pc_desc">
		<text>Transmitter Main Module Control Access Card.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="psy_shapka_proto_desc">
		<text>Experimental prototype T-ZUD-12 (ultra pressure protection). Faulty. Probably has value.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="pribor_antivibros_desc">
		<text>A device for shielding against the effects of emission on the body. Protects against emission damage, has a limited lifespan.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="zameritel_vibrosa_desc">
		<text>A sample of special equipment to survive a blowout. Scientists have discovered that during emission in the Zone there is a strange activity, it is necessary to find out the nature of these phenomena. To measure, the instrument must be laid out in an open area during the intermediate emission phase.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="vorglaz_gig_talk1">
		<text>When the commotion started, I accidentally got into some room, they don't lock a damn thing in there, they must have been sure no one would get in... So there's some sort of archive, I took as many folders as I could fit in my duffel bag. I don't know why, but they're prized in the Zone. The Watchdog wouldn't let us trade information... Maybe he was dealing it himself. And what good are these papers, but you can sell them, and good money, and enough for food, and...</text>
	</string>



	<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-rgo">
		<text>RGO (GRAU index - 7G22) - hand-held anti-personnel defensive percussion-distance grenade. The grenade is designed to engage manpower in defensive combat. The grenade is delivered to the target only by throwing it by the soldier's hand. The grenade fragmentation damage radius is 50 meters, and the potential damage radius is 100 meters. The grenade is similar to the F-1 grenade, but differs from it by the use of a combined percussion and remote fuse. A grenade explodes when it hits a hard surface. The grenade's fuse is all-durable, detonating regardless of the surface inclination or position of the grenade. The fuse is cocked 1.3-1.8 seconds after the safety lever is released (throwing the grenade), which eliminates the possibility of instantaneous explosion in case of accidental encounter with an obstacle at a short distance from the grenade launcher. If the grenade is not detonated by a percussion fuze, the grenade will self-destruct by detonation 3.2-4.2 seconds after the safety lever is released. In this the action of the grenade is completely similar to that of F-1, RG-42, RGD-5 grenades. The battle grenade is colored an olive grayish color. The training simulation grenade is colored black.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="barman_posr_talklong">
		<text>The mediator was generally unsociable, so I don't know about his affairs. He rarely came here, and if he did, he wasn't here for long. He was often seen on Yantar because he was testing something for the scientists there at one time. Came in here today, about an hour before his body was found. Asked about all sorts of things. Asked questions about you, too, by the way.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="barman_posr_talklong2">
		<text>The last person who talked to him was Sanya Borov. Things weren't the warmest between them, you know. I once heard that Mediator ditched Sanya for the loot when they went to the Garbage. They just had another scandal today, and I had to kick them out. So far, all suspicions fall on Sanya, especially since he wanted to get away when he was found at the murder scene.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="barman_posr_talklong3">
		<text>Maybe someone's trying to cover their tracks by using your name... I think Khmyr was hanging around the table where Sanya was standing... Where he is now, I don't know. He left when the trouble started. That's suspicious... I would talk to the Informant about this topic. Hubby was just talking to him.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="barman_posr_talklong4">
		<text>I've been there... Up north. Went through the Incinerator. Three days from the monolithians... Hiding in basements. Then back he went... Again via Burnout... I've been sandpapered twice already... It wasn't without consequences... I'm told there's a clinic. On the Big Land. Where they treat this kind of thing, where they get their brains right... Here I am.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="tutor_radiat_jornl_now_name">
		<text>Leaflet on radiation and exposure</text>
	</string>


	<string id="tutor_radiat_jornl_now_desc">
		<text>Not all items found in the area are safe. Weapons, food, artifacts, objects, everything can be exposed to radioactive contamination.\nA thing like this, even in a backpack, can be very background. So be sure to carry a dosimeter or detector.\nWith its presence you can check if the object is infected. Just look it over in the backpack. If yes, it will beep.\nNow a little bit about radiation sickness.\nIt is possible to get radiation sickness by staying in areas of high contamination or by eating contaminated food. It is expressed as a permanent decline in health and stamina. On top of that, you get a yellowish haze in front of your eyes... The higher the contamination, the higher these negative effects.\nIt can only be fought by taking large quantities of anti-rads, vodka, and some scientists seem to cure this ailment.\nYou can keep an eye on the infection rate by getting checked out by scientists. They may have already made some sort of diagnostic device.\nStalker Toad, 05/21/2007.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="mosk_part_desc">
		<text>A device of unknown purpose.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="esc_dead_kolodetz_article_text">
		<text>Messer, aren't you in the village area right now? There's a hobo from the Garbage was bringing me a package from the bar, but he disappeared somewhere in the neighborhood. Go and see what's in there, and if you find anything, bring it to me right away. We're out.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="dolg_hey_slez_ska">
		<text>What are you doing out there?</text>
	</string>



	<string id="pda_hmir_rostok_dolina">
		<text>Took the Mediator his container... He... Didn't want to give it back nicely. I had to... Do the wrong thing. I've dealt with it, but the container won't open... A lock with a code, man... We should... Back to our meeting place... We should have gotten the code to that thing before we took him down. If I can open it. I'll be cured.</text>
	</string>





	<string id="dpa_vlv_dv_name">
		<text>Pocket personal computer. The owner of the PDA didn't bother deleting recent posts. One of the latest PDA messages from the owner of the Stalker place: ''He's moving North. Last seen at the Garbage. You follow him until he's not
will make it to the center. Don't go to Pripyat, it's a dead end.
subject. If he goes through town, come back -
the military will finish him off themselves.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="nine_pda_rasch_rashifrvn_article_name">
		<text>PDA: Blue 9</text>
	</string>

	<string id="nine_pda_rasch_rashifrvn_article_desc">
		<text>Subject has located passage 1 and 3, protruding into sector 28.\nTeams White, Green to Sector 26 for evacuation.\nGroups Red: in the area of the Dark Valley, in the laboratory sector the exit to the Cordon dungeons.\nGroups Blue: three samples of anomalous formations #24 were found on Cordon. In the area of the factory entrance, water tower, destroyed building in the village.\nTo all groups: The backup weapons stash is located on the Radar property, tag attached to the message. Use only when absolutely necessary.\nContact the major about the facility.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="voenstals">
		<text>Military stalkers</text>
	</string>


	<string id="reload_pda_now_desc">
		<text>Electricity supply data.\nData on the presence of a powerful source of electric power consumption directly behind the Chernobyl NPP.\nThe data has been corrupted.\nBackup code of the lower level of the energy center under Radar territory- Data corrupted </text>
	</string>

	<string id="reload_pda_now_name">
		<text>Journalist's Message</text>
	</string>

	<string id="sl_x18_dream_name">
		<text>Strange dream</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_x18_dream_text">
		<text>I had a strange dream. The hulk of the Chernobyl plant in the semi-darkness. Everything looks peaceful. A lone man appears. I can see him from the back against the power plant. The wind is starting to blow. Suddenly a sea of rats starts scattering away from the power plant in different directions. A man standing with his back to me, shooting rats. Suddenly there's a shout: "Strelok!". The man flinches, freezes for a moment and slowly starts to turn towards me, but...the moment before I would have seen his face, I woke up...what does this dream mean? I don't know...But I think it's something I've seen before.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="tip_use">
		<text>Use</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_pda_dead">
		<text>PDA is low on battery</text>
	</string>


	<string id="tip_tops">
		<text>Stalker rankings</text>
	</string>


	<string id="pribor_paras_spory_name">
		<text>Analyzer</text>
	</string>

	<string id="pribor_paras_spory_desc">
		<text>An air analyzer set up to analyze parasite spores. To activate, you must lay the device out near the source of the spore.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="tips_esc_trader_about_anomalies">
		<text>Watch out! You're near the anomalies. Use bolts to define their boundaries.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="ammo-ammo_psy_s">
		<text>PsyCharge</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-gauss">
		<text>Universal energy module for PSI weapons.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="enc_personal_card_desc">
		<text>Personalized Access Card. Used by scientific groups.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="grenade-grenade_rgd5_anom">
		<text>Gravigranata RGD5</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-grenade_rgd5_anom">
		<text>Gravigranata RGD5. Increased damage radius, strongly throws off the bodies of enemies.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="grenade-grenade_f1_anom">
		<text>Gravigranata F1</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-grenade_f1_anom">
		<text>Gravigranata F1. Increased kill radius, attracts enemies during the explosion, bounces enemies' bodies back hard.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="wpn_knife_anomname">
		<text>Gravity knife</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn_knife_anom">
		<text>Strongly bounces the bodies of enemies, changing the trajectory of the flight.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="enc_personal_card_desc">
		<text>Personalized Access Card. Used by scientific groups.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="grenade-grenade_rgd5_anom">
		<text>Gravigranata RGD5</text>
	</string>




<string id="tip_use_take">
		<text>Take it</text>
</string>


<string id="tip_use_book">
		<text>Book</text>
</string>

<string id="grafime_frpff">
		<text>I remember everything! Give the Winds of Madness cyclicity chart to Messer. He has to go!</text>
</string>


<string id="grafic_ciklichnosti_vetrov_doki_opis_name">
		<text>Documents about "Winds of Madness" with the Professor's notes (Winds of Madness Cycle Chart)</text>
</string>


<string id="grafic_ciklichnosti_vetrov_doki_opis">
		<text>This file appears to have been attempted to be burned. Cover shows signs of sooting, page corners blackened. Those sheets with records of experiments conducted in the Zone were supplemented with the Professor's notes. On the back of some chart, a message to Messer is written in the Professor's handwriting.
\n
"Messer, forgive me. I've devoted my whole life to science. I believed in progress and its good for humanity. I set great goals for myself, but now I see where my actions have led. I didn't want this. I am sorry you have to live in this world, but there is nothing I can do to make up for my mistakes. Go to the North - there you will find the answers to all your questions. Thanks to these papers, I was able to calculate the exact cooling time of the installation that keeps stalkers out of the Center. You can turn it off by sneaking in to the maintenance lab when it's not running at full capacity. The cooling phase begins at 9pm and lasts about two hours. But even at this time, the installation is still active, so you can't get close without psi protection.
\n
I hope I was able to help you in some way. Please don't blame me for what I did. But now I can't rest easy seeing the "marvelous new" world I had a hand in. Go North, Messer. You need to go."
\n
Professor
</text>
</string>


<string id="radbun_thats_okay">
		<text>It's alright, come on in. We're just waiting for you...</text>
</string>

<string id="scene_scientist">
		<text>Research Associate</text>
</string>

<string id="tip_take">
		<text>Take it</text>
</string>

<string id="start_coded_article_name">
		<text>[corrupted data]</text>
</string>

<string id="start_coded_article_desc">
		<text>[Huge amount of information not readily available. It is a mishmash of code that, until then, perhaps someone will be able to decipher...]</text>
</string>

<string id="on_lab_swithc_dok_1">
		<text>Shut down life support system #1</text>
</string>

<string id="on_lab_swithc_dok_2">
		<text>Shut down life support system 2.</text>
</string>

<string id="on_lab_swithc_dok_3">
		<text>Shut down life support system three.</text>
</string>

<string id="on_lab_swithc_dok_4">
		<text>Shut down life support system four.</text>
</string>

<string id="oned_lab_swithc_dok_1">
		<text>Life support system one is offline</text>
</string>

<string id="oned_lab_swithc_dok_2">
		<text>Life support system two is offline</text>
</string>

<string id="oned_lab_swithc_dok_3">
		<text>Life support system three is down</text>
</string>

<string id="oned_lab_swithc_dok_4">
		<text>Life support system four is offline</text>
</string>

<string id="on_lab_swithc_dok_fin">
		<text>Disconnect the power supply to the plant</text>
</string>

<string id="oned_lab_swithc_dok_fin">
		<text>The power to the unit is turned off</text>
</string>

<string id="tip_upsters">
		<text>Go upstairs</text>
</string>

<string id="tip_use_greh_save">
		<text>Open the safe</text>
</string>

<string id="oned_lab_swithc_dol_hall">
		<text>Emergency containment of the complex has been deactivated</text>
</string>

<string id="st_attach_silencer_to_1">
		<text>attach the silencer to the gun</text>
</string>

<string id="st_attach_silencer_to_2">
		<text>attach the silencer to the rifle</text>
</string>

<string id="vetri_bezumia_doki_name">
		<text>Document The Winds of Madness</text>
</string>

<string id="vetri_bezumia_doki_opis">
		<text>
This file appears to have been attempted to be burned. Cover shows signs of sooting, page corners blackened. The folder contains ten sheets of notes on experiments being conducted in the Zone. If Sin's leader locked it in the safe, there was a reason. Also in the folder is a draft of a letter whose recipient is V.M. Chubko.
\n
"Just got back from testing the Kaymanov rig. Not only were the drugs not distributed to everyone, but the biological material is walking around the building unguarded. There's a clear lack of safety in plain sight. Installing it is no good at all. Total cost of equipment and cooling system. I'm already studying their blueprints (don't ask me how I got them, you won't believe me anyway). I'll send them to you with the letter so you can see for yourself. This installation requires a nuclear power plant nearby, so you can forget about any mobility. And if its lockup overheats, the whole rig will get out of control and start messing with everyone's brains indiscriminately. Want to normally secure the Center Lab from foreign elements, use ours.
\n
However, the choice is yours. If you want to have a problematic transmitter at your side, have it, Vladimir Mikhailovich. But I'm not responsible for the consequences. Next time I will send a formal complaint to the Panel for consideration."
\n
Prikhodko P.S.
</text>
</string>

<string id="tip_take_art">
		<text>Get the artifact</text>
</string>

<string id="off_swamp_rubilnik1">
		<text>The swamp installation is disabled</text>
</string>

<string id="off_swamp_rubilnik">
		<text>Disable the installation</text>
</string>


<string id="on_lab_swithc_dol">
		<text>Turn on the emergency lighting of the complex</text>
</string>


<string id="oned_lab_swithc_dol">
		<text>The emergency lighting of the complex is on</text>
</string>


<string id="on_lab_swithc_dol_hall">
		<text>Open the front door to the complex</text>
</string>


<string id="enc_equipment_planshet">
		<text>A tablet with a hand drawn map of the area.</text>
</string>
<string id="planshet_name">
		<text>Manual zone map</text>
</string>
<string id="planshet_short_name">
		<text>Tablet</text>
</string>

	<string id="simple_anomsinfo_article_tx">
		<text>Basic information about anomalies</text>
	</string>

	<string id="simple_anomsinfo_article_text">
		<text>Anomalies are small areas of the Zone in which the physical laws familiar to humans have been seriously altered. Anomalies produce artifacts - various kinds of items with unique properties that stalkers hunt for. Anomalies, along with mutants, are a key feature that distinguishes the Zone from the rest of the surface of planet Earth. Features:\n- spawn artifacts when monsters die in them\n- can be deactivated when spawning an artifact\n- can be deactivated by some equipment\n- deactivated anomalies are reactivated after emission of anomalies.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="simple_artsinfo_article_tx">
		<text>Basic information about artifacts</text>
	</string>

	<string id="simple_artsinfo_article_text">
		<text>Features:\n- to get full known properties you need a description of the sample in PDA\n- may have different price and weight depending on the sample\n- may change properties after a blowout\n- lose their properties when used\n- fully discharged artifact loses its properties</text>
	</string>

	<string id="simple_mutantsinfo_article_tx">
		<text>Basic information about mutants</text>
	</string>

	<string id="simple_mutantsinfo_article_text">
		<text>Features:\n- some individuals are afraid of fire and psi sources\n- some individuals such as rats and crows are edible (they can also be specially cooked on a campfire)\n- some individuals have certain tissue samples that may be of interest to traders and scientists (need mutant information in PDA)</text>
	</string>


<string id="dezint_long_first_1">
		<text>Don't you worry... and don't you dare threaten me here. The Dutyers have an interest in my work, and I'm not afraid of anything. They'll protect me if they have to. So you said you came by to say hello? Hmm. Stalker, huh? I can see from your face that you're clearly an experienced man, you must have seen a lot... When you're out in the zone, bring me one of these if you get a chance. This is so to speak my main object of study here in general. Sent you a photo. I won't hurt you with money, don't worry. This thing is rare, it doesn't come along very often, and I need it. Take care.</text>
</string>

<string id="dezint_long_first_2">
		<text>Would you believe me if I told you what organization I'm from? Ha, I'm not sure. The fact that you got the artifact really speaks volumes... at least for me. I think you and I have a business relationship to continue. Here, as well as the general five hundred as a reward... You ask what the artifact is. You know...it's not easy. Although it does occur in the zone, too. Its true properties I do not yet know, however, it is not a simple bling, no. There's something hidden in it...something beyond our understanding. Yeah, it certainly sounds commonplace here in the zone, but it's a truly unique specimen in terms of its potential... Tell you what, come see me in a day. I will do some experiments with this sample. Afterward, if you come back, I'll pay you twice as much for your next assignment.</text>
</string>

<string id="dezint_long_first_3">
		<text>And the fact that even with partial activation, it was possible to... That's what you're going to find out - you need a practical experiment. Here, take a sample. You need to do a full activation of this sample already. How do you do that? It's very simple. It needs to be exposed to ultra-high temperatures. I don't know the neighborhood much, so I have no idea where to get a heat source higher than a hundred or two degrees around here. You've seen a lot of things, haven't you? In general, throw the sample in some place with elevated ambient temperature and see what happens. Then report back to me what you see. As promised, I'll pay twice as much as last time. Alright, go, I'll wait for the results.</text>
</string>


<string id="enc_zombied_pda_dezintegr">
		<text>...The PDA battery is almost dead... I think this is the last note. It is not known exactly how long I have been here, but I think it is possible to get out... because you can hear the sounds! It's like being behind a wall. There's a lot of people walking around... I've been yelling, but no one seems to have heard me yet. I think I'm gonna make it out. I heard the one from the death truck slipping me something. he's the reason I'm here. It's okay, when I get out of here, I'll tell everyone what he is. And the General,... they thought I don't know. The main thing is to get out before the food supply runs out... It's okay, I'll tell everyone. Strelok said, s...</text>
</string>


<string id="quest_table_main_text">
		<text>Bulletin board</text>
</string>


<string id="car_head_info">
		<text>Driving a car</text>
</string>


<string id="car_info_desc1">
		<text>Start it up - Z. Controls: WASD. Shifting gears - LCtrl,LShift.</text>
</string>



<string id="car_info_desc2">
		<text>Handbrake - Space. Headlights - L. Door - T. Trunk - F.</text>
</string>



<string id="car_info_desc3">
		<text>You need gasoline, battery.</text>
</string>



<string id="jurn_doki_cely_osoznania_desc">
		<text>Psychotropic influence and zombification on a global scale

1. Invisible and imperceptible influence. General behavioral emphases on behavior in large masses of people (cities).

2. Impact on underground political groups

3. Creating a favorable environment for the official introduction of planetary-scale psi effects. Statewide correction of people's psyche, mood and mental state.

4. Correcting the attention of masses of people in order to hide, disguise information about psychotropic research. Causing an artificial loss of interest in parapsychology.

5. There are psi keys on major major major cities that will turn up to 50% of the population into biorobots

6. The first steps (successful tests of large-scale influence at the state level) - mass transition to the old currency (Soviet rubles).</text>
</string>


<string id="jurn_doki_controlory_desc">
		<text>Controllers are ex-humans with introduced surgical and biochemical brain changes. They have the ability to control other living organisms using microlepton brainwaves (simply put, telepathy). Dressed in semi-sporty tight-fitting uniforms, predominantly black in color.

1. Completely mute

2. capture and zombify stalkers with parts of documents

3. Stop any attempts by researchers to penetrate to the center of the Zone

4. Control the mutants of the Zone

5. Set up psi generators to zombify animals and humans.

6. Prefer to operate at night. However, quite capable during the day.

All major takedowns are conducted at night.
Factions
Roadblock
7. They don't touch military stalkers</text>
</string>

<string id="jurn_doki_last_zapiska_desc">
		<text>...Beneath the ground lie the bodies of the unified consciousness their condition is near coma. In the lab is one of the bodies controlled from underground. It carries out their will, controls external processes, and provides their bodies with everything they need. It is representative of the O-Consciousness Project... children were "harvested" by the o-consciousness to prepare a more powerful replacement...</text>
</string>

<string id="journalist_is_you">
		<text>...Journalist?!</text>
</string>

<string id="goavavay">
		<text>You're leaving after all, eh. Even though the old man refused to give you his notes on the cyclical nature of the Winds of Madness. No offense to him, he's been here in the Zone for a hell of a long time. She's like a... What can you compare the Zone to without leaving the Zone? Only with the Zone itself.</text>
</string>


<string id="goavavay2">
		<text>I don't take offense. I've got some paperwork right here. I picked them up at the Sin Clan lair. Maybe you could use them for something. Everything I need to know I already know, and what's missing to complete the picture is not in them anyway, Give it to the professor. I gotta go.</text>
</string>

<string id="prof_labuda_5">
		<text>We all, in one form or another, try to forget anything that involves strong negative emotions, stress,... Otherwise, a person simply won't survive... under our circumstances. And if the stress is great. Or maybe it's the global influences... geofactors... Or. </text>
</string>


<string id="prof_labuda_4">
		<text>What about happiness? Which one of you is happier? By the way, there's a town not far away, and only zombies live there. What about wish fulfillment? Who's desire system and perception of reality are in a more harmonious relationship?</text>
</string>


<string id="prof_labuda_3">
		<text>However, you are quite drowsy, young man. No, by external world I mean the world outside of a person, as opposed to their internal world. Although in some ways it can be compared to the Zone as well. So, what makes you so sure that everything you see and feel is actually happening, that your perception is in accordance with the surrounding reality and not induced by this very surrounding reality? Here's zombies for example - do you think they see the world the same way you do?</text>
</string>


<string id="prof_labuda_2">
		<text>That depends on how you look at the question, young man. Once upon a time I worked in one of the famous institutes dealing with management problems, we had a modest laboratory there... Actually, what do you know about our perception of information from the outside world?</text>
</string>

<string id="prof_labuda_1">
		<text>No, I'm certainly convinced that this is the real artifact... something that doesn't exist. But! In principle, its existence does not contradict my hypothesis about the interaction of complex geofactors, in the sum acquiring completely new properties, which are almost impossible to predict from the properties of the constituent objects of the system...</text>
</string>

<string id="naulagerdocent_1">
		<text>Yes... Once it was a big research camp, volunteers came here, equipment was delivered, but gradually we were forgotten. First, the influx of volunteers stopped - something in the outside world began to fail.</text>
</string>

<string id="naulagerdocent_2">
		<text>What's there to talk about when there's stuff going on here in the Zone... this is where every normal scientist should be. It's certainly a shame that there has been a complete cessation of any supply. Our lab has now moved to an autonomous existence. Young employees gradually began to go to other places, someone joined some clans, someone disappeared in the depths of the Zone, someone died trying to get an artifact. Some have become a sort of a legend in the Zone. Like the Mad Doctor, for example. He was one of the employees of one of the labs here in the Zone, but it was as if he had become part of the Zone. He developed characteristics not found in a normal person. No, he's not a mutant in the literal sense of the word, but there's something so special about him... They say he can reassemble stalkers crippled by the Zone literally from bits and pieces. Or even one of the remains of several. He's also supposedly able to communicate with zombies and even bring them back to normal. However, it is also said that he does this very rarely, as he believes that zombies do not want to return to normal life at all. We also had a guy named, uh. Journalist, I think. - He was obsessed with some sort of international conspiracy idea. All the time he was babbling about globalists, that brought in some kids...</text>
</string>

<string id="naulagerdocent_3">
		<text>They say there are some, but nobody really knows anything. I think there is such an order. They are trying to maintain the status quo. They are also called Angels of the Zone, or adherents of the monolith cult. They guard the center from which, according to rumors, the general management of all life in the Zone is carried out...</text>
</string>

<string id="tip_press_button">
		<text>Press the button</text>
</string>

<string id="greh_leader_key_desc">
		<text>The key to Sin's safe.</text>
</string>

<string id="goplit_pda_dolina_name">
		<text>Goplit's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_goplit_pda_dolina">
		<text>The personal PDA of a stalker nicknamed Goplit. Access is password-protected. Maybe one of the scientists can crack it.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_goplit_pda_dolina_hacked">
		<text>...I didn't have time to do a write-up the day before yesterday. I came across the Journalist in the swamp nearby. I had to carry him back to his nest and help him to his feet. The Zuda I was saving for Toad had to be wasted. It's alright, it's not a pity about the Journalist. He said he was running away from someone, but when asked who exactly was chasing him, he preferred to keep silent. Bid him farewell today - he's scooted off somewhere up north. Where exactly and why - I don't know, but apparently he is going to meet his informants there. Before he left, he asked me if I had visited the archives of the local research institute. He was interested in some papers related to the delivery of equipment to the laboratory on Radar's territory. I'll be in the neighborhood to check it out. In case I find anything, I'll tell the Journalist when I meet him.</text>
</string>

<string id="tip_use_spat_hata">
		<text>Sleep</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_rat_food_coocked">
		<text>Fire-cooked rat. Much more nutritious than raw. Plus, the heat treatment killed all viruses and parasites.</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_crow_food_coocked">
		<text>Fire-cooked crow. Much more nutritious than raw. Plus, the heat treatment killed all viruses and parasites.</text>
</string>

<string id="korobok_spichek_desc">
		<text>A box of matches. You can use it to start a fire. A campfire can be used to keep warm at night or in the rain, cook some food, and scare off hostile monsters.</text>
</string>

<string id="gen_dnev_doki_opis">
		<text>...the Unified Consciousness experiments were a success. The linkage of the five prisoners yielded positive results. "United Consciousness" or 
"O-Consciousness had slightly less power than five times human intelligence. "O-Consciousness" awakened, showing frantic neuron activity and almost five times (compared to the human brain) the speed of information processing. The criminals' previously erased memory was being filled in again...[no data]...the precautions were insufficient. The researchers were not prepared for this kind of eventuality. Contact with one of the group's sedated bodies 
"O-Consciousness," two technicians and a nurse on the maintenance staff came under control. Next, the entire research block where the experiment was being conducted came under control with incredible speed. Instantly reacting, the experiment managers completely isolated the entire unit from the outside world. Deadly gas was pumped through the ventilation shafts. 28 controlled bodies were thrashing around in convulsions while O-Consciousness tried unsuccessfully to find an escape route. It was calculating escape options, scanning the bodies memory. They began to perish, but O-Consciousness had already discovered one-way windows through which a group of scientists were observing the effects of the experiment. With the help of strong telepathic influence, the group was brought under control and the O-Consciousness could hold nothing back anymore. The staff of the underground complex was taken under control, the power of O-Consciousness increased manifold. About 500 people are connected to the O-Consciousness...</text>
</string>

<string id="gen_dnev_doki_name">
		<text>Scientist's Diary</text>
</string>

<string id="golmar_cos_talksf">
		<text>Hmm. I don't really need artifacts, but I do need some parts. Tell you what, you get me a killer suit and a science suit. Plus a p90, and five bottles of vodka. Then I'll give it to you. I'll hold it for you. Or I'll give it to you for ten grand.</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_psy_stabilizator">
		<text>Relieve the effects of various kinds of psi radiation. It surpasses other benzodiazepine and abenzodiazepine tranquilizers by the strength of tranquilizing and anxiolytic (anti-anxiety) action; it also has a pronounced anticonvulsant, myorelaxant (muscle relaxant) and sedative effect.</text>
</string>

<string id="psy_stabilizator_name">
		<text>Psi stabilizers NEURO-A</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_anti_beshenstvo_dog_caps">
		<text>Help cure the effects of a bite from an infected dog.</text>
</string>

<string id="anti_beshenstvo_dog_caps_name">
		<text>Rabies pills</text>
</string>

<string id="onn_rat_avar_rub_on">
		<text>Turn on emergency lighting</text>
</string>

<string id="lvl_rat">
		<text>Rat catacombs</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_exo_acum_ob">
		<text>Servo power cell for the exoskeleton. To work, it is necessary to hang from the belt of the costume.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_outfit_description_outfit_stalker_golmar">
		<text>Made by the stalker Golmar and contains artifact particles. The anti-gravity flaps allow you to hover slightly above the ground. High and distance jumps have been increased. You don't have to worry about falling from 20 meters high. Load capacity +20 kg.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_outfit_name_outfit_stalker_golmar">
		<text>Golmar's costume</text>
</string>

<string id="lvl_mars">
		<text>Data error</text>
</string>

<string id="glazparentblood">
		<text>A false eye made of glass.</text>
</string>

<string id="glaz_fila_checked_article_text">
		<text>Engraved on the glass eye of a stalker nicknamed Phil was the code 667. You might want to remember that.</text>
</string>

<string id="glaz_fila_checked_article_tx">
		<text>The code on Phil's glass eye.</text>
</string>

<string id="golmar_combez_article_text">
		<text>The repairman in Bar offers to exchange the unique stalker suit named Golmar for the following items:\nKiller suit\nScientific suit EX-04\nP90 submachine gun\nFive bottles of vodka.\nOr ten thousand rubles.</text>
</string>

<string id="golmar_combez_article_tx">
		<text>Golmar's suit.</text>
</string>

<string id="mg_zombie_dnevnik_dead_opis">
		<text>Diary of a Dead Stalker. Some of the pages are blurred due to cadaverous decomposition, but some are readable.\n02.04.2012 
	...agreed to an expedition into the city. Maybe even highlight their science suit. In the meantime, I'll go like this, it's not a bad jacket. Oh, yeah, I remember, there's a locked room behind a closet in the ruins. When I'm in town, I should go in there. It's a little hard to move the closet, though.\n03.04.2012 
	Got to Freedom Base. It was just Chrome and a couple of his security guys. He said that the zombies before the blowout in the city are beastly, and it's better to hide somewhere an hour or two before the start. Well, I'll keep that in mind.\n02.04.2012, 23.40
	Found that damn apartment the Professor said. Yeah, looks like one of them used to be here. A couple of units left. Anyway, I've changed the battery, and now I'm going to sleep here. Just as the door on the switch is still working.\n03.04.2012, 03.14.
	Woke up to a knock on the door. Through the gap I spotted three zombies. They're breaking. Hopefully they'll be gone by morning at least.\n03.04.2012, 08.45.
	They don't want to leave. They can smell it. Fucking hell, I'll try to get through.\n03.04.2012, 12.31.
	Yeah, it's been a pretty bad day. One rotten one bit the jacket. The wound is covered in white foam. It sucks.\n03.04.2012, 16.05
	PDA's dead. Huh, I was gonna buy a spare battery from the Barkeep...\n03.04.2012, 20.15
	It's getting dark. Just this red light, and howling zombies. The wound hurts. Covered in sores. Why did I come here?\n04.04.2012, 03.55.
	The door won't budge at all. And they're just standing there, waiting.\n04.04.2012, 5.45.
	passed a couple of stalkers did not see shouted shooting head\n	mapvyoshypych..yvf..fy.
</text>
</string>

<string id="mg_door_closed_rub">
		<text>Door's locked, looks like an electronic lock. A little give but it won't open. Looks like there were zombies in here.</text>
</string>

<string id="pribor_primanka_name">
		<text>Decoy device</text>
</string>

<string id="pribor_primanka_desc">
		<text>A device with which you can lure out the intelligent swamp. To activate, you need to lay out the device in the desired area.</text>
</string>

<string id="psy_shapka_mg_desc">
		<text>Zombie brain simulator, protects the wearer from the strong psi radiation of psionic monsters.</text>
</string>

<string id="psy_shapka_mg">
		<text>Brain simulator</text>
</string>

<string id="horok_ammo_zink_desc">
		<text>A box of ammo to give to Ferret.</text>
</string>

<string id="horok_ammo_zink_name">
		<text>Ferret's ammo</text>
</string>

<string id="horok_rukzak_arts_desc">
		<text>A heavy backpack, presumably filled with artifacts. An orange glow runs through the fabric.</text>
</string>


<string id="horok_rukzak_arts_name">
		<text>Ferret's backpack</text>
</string>

<string id="tip_flykk_door">
		<text>Open the cylinder valve</text>
</string>

<string id="gar_train_doki_name">
		<text>Diary of a Dead Stalker</text>
</string>

<string id="gar_train_doki_opis">
		<text>An old shabby diary found in the cab of a rusty radioactive diesel locomotive, which, by some unknown coincidence, turned out to be very far from the railroad. The decayed remains of what appeared to be the author of the diary were still found in the cabin. Judging from the records, he was trying to hide from the horrors of the Zone inside.\n"... There are still voices swirling around in my cranium. They don't want to come out. Asking to look out the window to see what's left. There's nothing there. Nothing. But I muffle them, because I'd go crazy if I looked out. It's empty. No color and no space. And who will survive when they see the void? No one. There's nothing there. There is only the room within me, and I within which is the room. There's nothing on the other side. Nothing at all. Sometimes I hear something creaking or growling on the other side. It's all a voice, a voice out of me. There's nothing out there. I crawl around the room so that God forbid I see a void. My body aches. The head, too. The geiger counter kept screaming. 
I blowout it into the void so it won't get in the way..."</text>
</string>

<string id="yantar_mozg_doki_name">
		<text>Documentation of the installation at Lake Yantar</text>
</string>

<string id="yantar_mozg_doki_opis">
		<text>Documents found in an underground complex under Lake Yantar. They talk about starting work on an artificially grown biological psi emitter. The very first pages are filled with data on the arrival of biological materials: the dogs of the Pripyatchans, left after evacuation, or the wolves that have multiplied in the Chernobyl forests. However, if some records are to be believed, there were already doubts at that time that they would not be enough for long-term research, so the search for a new source of biomaterials was actively underway. In the appendices is a collective photo of the complex workers next to a life support device of a severed head from a dog. Some of the scientists' faces are censored. In the last pages there is a list of the first semi-annual shift of explorers, as well as a complete list of instructions for them, prescribed by the management.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_pda_pilot_name">
		<text>Pilot's PDA</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_equipment_agro_pda_pilot">
		<text>PDA found near the MedPribor Institute by a military helicopter. Apparently, the handheld personal computer originally belonged to a pilot. The helicopter surveyed Cordon, the Garbage, Dark Valley and the vicinity of the Research Institute before hitting the anomaly and making an emergency landing. Many large sites in the south of the Zone are noted on the PDA. This data has not fallen into the hands of Perimeter Command and is unlikely to ever fall into the hands of Perimeter Command, so we can not be afraid of their further advancement deep into the Zone. You can try to transfer the marks made by the pilot to your PDA yourself - this information will certainly not be superfluous.</text>
</string>

<string id="tip_use_drink">
		<text>Drinking</text>
</string>

<string id="dc_psy_offfffff_article_tx">
		<text>Radiation in the Shining Path</text>
</string>

<string id="dc_psy_offfffff_article_text">
		<text>The leader of the Freedom faction, nicknamed Chrome, asked me to disable a psi device that the scientists had abandoned. According to him, the house where the scientists were located is in the southeast. At the same time, a cluster of super-strong radiation was detected in that area. So we need to prepare for it properly.</text>
</string>

<string id="tip_use_kk_luk">
		<text>Go downstairs</text>
</string>

<string id="tip_use_kk_door1">
		<text>Sign in</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-vintorez_wpn_vintorez_gravi">
		<text>A screwcutter with strong gravitational properties. Experimental design.</text>
</string>

<string id="car_accum_name">
		<text>Car battery</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_car_accum">
		<text>The battery required to start the vehicle's engine.</text>
</string>

<string id="zakazy_scientific">
		<text>Orders from scientific groups</text>
</string>

<string id="jurnalist_ab_monolit_sk">
		<text> There is no Monolith. No and never has been, Strelok. And you're the one who told me that
when we were on the outskirts of Radar. Obviously, the Monolith is just another
a psychotropic facility that was built as the last layer of defense. Defense
ask who and from what? From stalkers, of course. But who organized the defense is already
a mystery. You knew it, but you didn't have time to tell me. What do you think about the rumors
of wish fulfillment, it's very hard to say. Someone may have gotten
to the Sarcophagus and was able to make a wish at the Monolith. But more of these stalkers are alive
No. They're probably getting a blowout caused by a wish they made. I don't know if there's any way--
to get to the bottom of whoever's behind this. After all, that's what we've been trying to do for a long time
for you to find out. As far as I know, you were trying to get to them during that time
outings, but, uh. you've become thrice-born. That's what the stalkers call you, right? Don't
I know what went wrong then. Maybe the Monolith isn't the last line of defense? It can,
there's another one and we didn't know about it? You know, uh. I believe there is another set up.
There, behind the power plant. But where exactly is a mystery. It's also a mystery where the location from where
the installation can be deactivated. In the meantime, I'm gonna try to get in touch with someone I've been
I trust him completely to help me figure this out. You, Strelok, can
to try to get into the Center Zone again. If I hear anything, I'll contact you.</text>
</string>

<string id="jurnalist_ab_chsto_privelo_v_zonu_sk">
		<text>You should know, Strelok, how many times I've told you this... I'm pre-Second
Disaster in a settlement near the CEZ worked. Editorial. She was typing something for someone--
then, uh. I can't remember now what and to whom exactly - the Zone is almost everything
erased my memories of the Big Land. I remember some yellow press where some of the
articles personally sponsored by the mayor. And then it started, the first warning bells.
let's go. Something's happened here with the military coming in such large numbers. It's just like I'm doing right now.
I remember four truckloads of soldiers were brought into our village. A two-story headquarters in two days
they've built, can you believe it? And the mayor's been pale all day. I went to
Checkpoints - there are already barbed wire and mines at the entrances to the city... To all
they refuse to answer questions, they say they're not supposed to answer. Even the Journalists. Yes, it is.
they said. And then... From the neighboring village, the children left. All of them. At night, when my parents were asleep.
There aren't even any babies left. The next morning, there's an uproar, moms are throwing themselves at the military.
thought they'd taken the kids. The military didn't know what was going on. Or maybe it's just the sight
didn't serve. So I went to that village. Already from our newspaper. Gathered the locals
ask around, talk to internal affairs. Neither of them have anything
don't remember. Completely. It's like everyone's memory has been erased. Not all of it, selectively. But about the kids, they're
don't remember anything at all. Some couldn't even remember the name. The cops, of course,
They blamed it on the vodka, because the people in that village drank a lot. But I've been talking to
some acquaintances from there who are teetotalers... No, it wasn't a mass drinking party 
- kidnapping. What did I learn from them, you ask? Nothing useful. I had to wait. And I waited. Children
they're starting to disappear from other townships. Same diagnosis-- no one remembers anything and.
no one saw anything. Some were able to leave for another city out of fear for the child, and others
and stayed in his home village, believing that no one could protect his child better.
That's what everyone thought before the Second Catastrophe. The buses came, people started evacuating.
You can't imagine the panic back then. They thought another reactor
I did. Some of the old-timers have been around since eighty-six. They're the ones who remembered how
The military arrived the day after the accident, and the evacuation was much more
later announced. And in our case, things were even worse: the military had long ago
and they didn't evacuate people until two months later. My neighbor, when I took him to the
last time I saw him, he was calculating something. I asked people I know how he's been dosed
I got it in time. We didn't know what really went on here in those days. And in me, it's just like
then the thought occurred to me that if the kids went anywhere, it was to the Zone. There's no such thing
there's no overlap between the two events. I decided one night, I'd sneak into the Zone.
Just for one day, just to check things out. I was just before the military
the first breakthrough to get there. I watched them all die in anomalies from afar. Part
The APCs have been abandoned. The ones on the road to the center are often found. I went deep into the Zone
and that's it. It's like the memories of the Big Land have been cut off by something. Slowly, so that
I didn't notice. There's something left. Most important: name remembered, nickname, how to eat, drink, with a
weapons to handle. I can still communicate with people, thankfully. And here's the title
of our newspaper I can't remember. I can't remember what we have going on in the capital.
What is it, events in the capital - I can't remember its name... It's possible,
Is the Zone taking away our memories? Selectively, I think. Takes away some, and others
fixes it so you can't get it out of your head. I remember I used to be a journalist
was. I remember the village, my neighbor, the kids. And the same phrase keeps running through my head: find the
children. I can't get any peace. And I'm not gonna rest until I find it. It's the Zone that's holding me back.
</text>
</string>

<string id="jurnalist_what_do_next_sk">
		<text>I can't go to the Big Land anyway, The zone is holding. And I know a lot about the Zone - about
the labs, what's going on closer to Central. There's no turning back.
</text>
</string>

<string id="jurnalist_what_about_childs_sk">
		<text>I know that shortly before the first day, all the children left the settlements near the borders.
of the current Chernobyl Anomaly Zone. Gone to the Zone. They're probably in
the center, on the other side of the Winds of Madness installation. In the South, all the places on the map
but in the north, where there weren't so many people, there may well be.
Something happened back there at the center that lured kids to the Zone. Just the kids, not
adults. And that's what metamorphosed them here and turned them into dwarfs.
- is already a mystery. I'm sure the center of the Zone was not without these labs.
</text>
</string>

<string id="jurnalist_what_about_thirdborned_sk">
		<text>It's hard to say. On the one hand, they're stalker tales that only newbies can get into
Toad has faith. On the other hand, we are in the Zone, where anything is possible. Maybe you really are
you are the Chosen One who can change the world. </text>
</string>

<string id="uchenie_holmy_start_article_text">
		<text>One of the mobile science teams has gone missing in the Silent Hills area. We should try to find them, and if possible find out what happened to them.</text>
</string>

<string id="uchenie_holmy_start_article_tx">
		<text>The missing science team</text>
</string>

<string id="prof_silgrav_start_article_text">
		<text>A professor from the science compex on the lake asks for two strong gravitational artifacts to establish a business conversation.</text>
</string>

<string id="prof_silgrav_start_article_tx">
		<text>The Professor's request</text>
</string>

<string id="find_af_night_star1">
		<text>Magnet Science Group Order #1</text>
</string>

<string id="find_af_night_star2">
		<text>Magnet Science Group Order #2</text>
</string>

<string id="dok_mag_2sht">
		<text>Scientists from the group that researches Magnet Group artifacts require two such artifacts for further study.</text>
</string>




<string id="find_af_night_star3">
		<text>Magnet Science Group Order #3</text>
</string>

<string id="dok_mag_3sht">
		<text>Scientists from the group that is investigating the Magnet Group artifacts need two of these artifacts, plus the Electric Ball artifact, for further research.</text>
</string>



<string id="find_af_night_star4">
		<text>Magnet Science Group Order #4</text>
</string>

<string id="dok_mag_4sht">
		<text>Got some kind of result from a Magnet scientist in the form of an artifact. The task is to throw this artifact into an anomaly like Elektra, and bring the result back for study...</text>
</string>




<string id="find_af_night_star5">
		<text>Magnet Science Group Order #5</text>
</string>

<string id="dok_mag_5sht">
		<text>Another artifact order, but, here I was asked to get something special on top... Ammunition for the Gauss rifle. It looks like a normal cassette, with any number of charges.</text>
</string>


<string id="find_af_night_star6">
		<text>Magnet Science Group Order #6</text>
</string>

<string id="dok_mag_6sht">
		<text>That's a strange order... Should I bring a regular rifle for the scientists? What's this about...</text>
</string>


<string id="find_af_night_star7">
		<text>Magnet Science Group Order #7</text>
</string>

<string id="dok_mag_7sht">
		<text>And these nerds aren't so simple... working for the military. Well, military toys for the stalker cause are always useful... We need to fire a few hundred rounds from a prototype Vintorez with strong magnetic properties, and bring it back to them.</text>
</string>



<string id="jornal_1_desc">
		<text>Documents from MedPribor Research Institute. It says on the cover that this is the main part of the documents, and somewhere is the application part. Inside, in addition to plans of storage rooms with hazardous biological materials and a list of the institute's personnel, one can find instructions from the head of scientific work:
Due to the fact that some of the test subjects from the Department of Bio-breeding and Eugenics (Head of the Department - L. P. Romaniuk) represent a danger to the staff, the meeting decided to organize a storage of bio-waste unsuitable for further work. Pre-dead bio-waste that remains after experiments should be trucked away from the research areas to the disposal site (Rassocha Technique Cemetery). At the disposal site, the waste should be buried under layers of metal junk and rubble in abundance nearby. The railroad hangar is to be converted into a bio-waste storage facility for sorting. There is a high probability that these burials near the water body will cause a marked deterioration of the ecological situation in this region, so the collectors of the railroad shed should be brought to a suitable condition, for water filtration. All subsequent burial and water filtration directives were sent to the railroad facility management...
\n
Pencil marking - The first part of the control code is 65.
</text>
</string>

<string id="jornal_2_desc">
		<text>Documents from the Garbage. The cover has a black gel pen marking Personal to hand. Among the endless directives for troubleshooting the collector system and the list of warehouse personnel, which numbered about a hundred names, there are records of burials and the reception of bio-waste from research areas:
A fresh batch of biological materials from MedPribor Research Institute has been received and is being transferred to our disposal. For the disposal of the waste, military personnel involved in guarding the warehouses north of the Rostok plant (approximately an hour's drive from the above facility) were engaged. Among other things, we had to ask for five more trucks from the storage garages to transport the waste because the previous vehicles were already dirty and not suitable for further use, so they will be disposed of at our landfill. For the new machines, everything has already been agreed, the documents have been signed, and copies of the documentation are in the archive in the main warehouse building. The original documents will be sent to the NRI archives next week.
\n
Pencil marking - The second part of the control code is 76.
</text>
</string>

<string id="jornal_3_desc">
		<text>Documents from MedPribor Research Institute. It says on the cover that this is the application part of the documents, and somewhere is the main part. Almost nothing interesting except that these documents are signed by the technical director of site security after the Second Catastrophe:
After the increase of anomalous activity in the region and loss of communication with a number of northern laboratories (Complex zx-06, Laboratory Center, zx-10), the management of the Research Institute decided to evacuate the personnel and preserve the Institute. Any attempt to escape from the regime territory will be punishable by death. All instructions have already been issued to the site security to deal with trespassers. She should dispose of all bio-materials of the research on site to avoid leakage. Further transportation of bio-waste to the Rassokha burial ground for further burial follows. Check the Institute's archive for compromising data and destroy it before the troops arrive. After all procedures for the conservation of the facility have been carried out, Institute personnel should break through to the Laboratory Center, regardless of the anomalous activity in its region to stabilize the experiment and eliminate its consequences. 
\n
Pencil marking - The third part of the control code is 82.
</text>
</string>


<string id="jornal_4_desc">
		<text>Papers from Silent Hills. Copies. The originals may have been destroyed long ago. Beneath the cover are electroencephalogram readings with notes made in black marker. Next to the results of the graphical record is a trip report to a research facility on one of the islets in Lake Yantar.
	No irregularities were observed during the demonstration of the operation of the ZX-08 biological unit with a unique (to date) sample of artificially grown biomass (sample Y-1M). The research department took every precaution in activating the facility: the attendees were given level one safety spacesuits and medical supplies with ampoules of psi-blocker drugs (in case the demonstration got out of hand). The 1269-bis subjects were exposed to surface psi radiation. Any attempts to impede his control were blocked on a mental level. Fields with multidirectional acceleration vectors (gravity concentrates) were tested on the same subjects. The results of the experiment are recorded on tape. A copy of the tape could not be obtained, so it is currently archived at the research complex. Among other things, recordings of previous experiments and demonstrations are also there.
\n
Pencil marking - The fourth part of the control code is 27.
</text>
</string>


<string id="jornal_5_desc">
		<text>
Papers from Lake Yantar. A thick folder stuffed with scientific documents. Clearly of value to someone who understands the endless stream of dry numbers, graphs and schematics of the transmitter device. Beneath a layer of papers that have partially turned to dust, there is a tape recording of the tests being performed. It's impossible to view it without the necessary equipment. There is also a letter to the head of the Center lab that apparently was never sent to the recipient.\n"Recently demonstrated to our dear guests the workings of an artificially grown biological psi emitter. Everything went well, no comments were received. We are ahead of schedule and have almost overtaken the Kaymanov emitter in power. To do that, truth be told, we had to increase the bio-mass by about a quarter using test biological material, which meant we'd have to go back to Pahlo for everything we needed. Please talk him into another shipment of prisoners from his colony. Subjects for Rainbow are supplied uninterruptedly and on demand, while for our laboratory they have to beg! As if to spite me. I know we're not going to run out of this resource anytime soon, so don't talk about limitations. Speaking of which, was at their demo recently, in the staff room by the main emitters. The trial information is there, so I suggest you familiarize yourself with it sometime too. Caymanoff just recently had a cooling problem with the rig there. Says it's all about nitrogen tanker leaks. For that matter, ask him what's in there. He'll tell you all about it, ha ha."
\n
Head of Laboratory ZX-52, Pavel Stepanovich Prikhodko.\nPencil marking - Fifth part of control code - 18.
</text>
</string>


<string id="jornal_6_desc">
		<text>Radar files. Somebody ripped out the title page, but all the rest is in place. Each page is stamped "classified" and signed "D. M. Kaimanoff". At the very bottom of the folder is an envelope. The addressee is still the same Cayman.
	"Dmitri Mikhailovich, how could it be so, eh? After all, you promised that there would be no more escapes of biological material. We supply them to your lab on short notice, and you lose them. Found one at MedPribor not too long ago. Be thankful they still gave it back to you instead of giving it to Prikhodko or giving it back to Pakhlo. By the way, I heard that Prikhodko keeps threatening to file a complaint against you. For failing to follow safety procedures during an extreme demonstration. They say the drugs were not given to everyone, there are holes in the defense. And this installation of yours is, quote, "no good at all - a total cost of equipment and cooling system". What's suspicious is that your staff performance reports say the exact opposite. I'll stop by after the Center's installation test - I'll look into it personally. And last but not least. I heard a rumor that you're losing your papers again on your trip to Pripyat. For the second time in six months. The first time wasn't enough for you? You'll pick them up personally from the Pripyat school. How and when doesn't interest me."
Vadim Mikhailovich Chubko\nPencil marking - The fifth part of the control code is 05.
</text>
</string>


<string id="jornal_7_desc">
		<text>Documents from Pripyat. They should have been covered in a thick layer of dust the whole time they'd been here, but someone had leafed through them and made notes with a pencil not too long ago. The last entry was a short time ago, "Strelok, I'll be in Freedom group territory. Find me in one of the houses on the outskirts of town. I'll be waiting. Glad you're back. Hurry up. Journalist." This entry was on top of an old notebook whose owner had previously used it as a personal diary:\

"Strange place they chose for the installations. The soil is completely unusable and terribly radioactive. We had to wear spacesuits, which are usually worn by Chernobyl personnel, to avoid grabbing a large dose. Even now, sitting in the break room, I don't want to take the food offered here. It's a good thing no one's gonna bother you here. Vadim Mikhailovich gave a full tour of the Center laboratory. Described the working principle of the plant and its objectives. The sheer scale of it is truly mesmerizing, and my emitter is no match for it. I was particularly struck by its surface generators. We were not allowed to get close to them - the background near them is just off the scale. It's scary to think what the future holds for those who are setting these generators to work now. Or their descendants. Vadim Mikhailovich demonstrated the operation of the plant. For this purpose, ten laboratory employees, including Vadim Mikhailovich himself, had to be involved. From the observation post we watched what was happening. Vadim Mikhailovich kept bragging that he would catch God by the beard. This time he didn't just grab it, he ripped it out by the root."
\n
Pencil marking - The fifth part of the control code is 88.
</text>
</string>

<string id="dolina_prelaba_doki_name">
		<text>Extract from Kiev branch of laboratory No. 15</text>
	</string>


<string id="dolina_prelaba_doki_opis">
		<text>Extract from the minutes of the 42nd meeting of managers of the Kiev branch of the laboratory 15 from 09.09.96\nPresent: 

Director of the Research Laboratories Network - S.K. Frankevich.
Head of Kiev branch of laboratory No. 15 - I.L. Karteevich.
Deputy Head of Kiev Branch of Laboratory No.15 - Ah.G. Lavrikov.

Decided: to recognize the further performance of the Kiev branch of the laboratory  15 incapable. Grounds: lack of funding, partial leakage of information on the laboratory's developments, threat to the existence of other secret facilities, distrust of the staff.

Next Steps:
- Laboratory personnel shall immediately make copies of laboratory reports. Destroy the original classified documents;
- to transfer all available documents to Prof. Chubko K.P;
- all personnel, starting from the head of the Kiev branch and ending with laboratory technicians and cleaners, to undergo procedure B, in order to further preserve the secrecy of developments. Perform the procedure at low power (~100 Jigowatts);
- in the event that any of the personnel resists, action must be taken;
- monitor the mental state of staff for 3 months after the B procedure;
- on the results of procedure B to Prof. Chubko K.P.

Secretary of the meeting

Lavrentiev Ah.L.
</text>
	</string>

<string id="radar_kompleks_doki_name">
		<text>Correspondence</text>
	</string>


<string id="radar_kompleks_doki_opis">
		<text>In person. To the head of the strict regime 1269 bis Pakhlo K.P.\nKirill Petrovich, again I address you with a request. I'm interested in a sheep from your farm. Index: 115. V. D. Krivoshein. Would like to get his dossier soon, and preferably himself. They are willing to give a little more for this frame than for an individual prisoner, but this time already after receiving a copy. Leave transportation to us again - your men are already getting suspicious at the checkpoint.

Prof. Chubko V. M. 


I have no idea where you got the lists of our prisoners, but I have to say in advance that I don't want to know. I can't attach the dossier from the archive - there will be a check the other day, so I'll write here the basic data: Viktor Davidovich Krivoshein, born in 1968. Organizer and chief ideologue of the Grey Brothers religious group. The group was engaged in sectarian activities. Occasional cases of fatal robbery and cannibalism have been seen among the sect members. Here since 1996, life imprisonment. Krivoshein is undergoing psychotherapy sessions, but the prognosis from our psychologists is disappointing. I'll try to forward this frame to you as soon as possible.

Yours sincerely, Warden of Maximum Security Unit 1269 bis, Palo K.P.

P.S. From myself I will add the following: there is practically no data about Krivoshein's past in the dossier. However, I was able to learn from my sources that before the religious organization came into existence, he worked in some institute that dealt with the problems of self-government. Probably, after the collapse of the USSR, the institute was closed, and the biography of the employees was "cleaned up". Well, I don't need to tell you about that.

P.S. 2. The "tops" are still trying to hush up the story of that march of the "brothers" in the capital so that no one would remember it. I assume you remember this event...</text>
	</string>

<string id="mg_monolitovec_doki_name">
		<text>Diary of a Monolithian</text>
	</string>


<string id="mg_monolitovec_doki_opis">
		<text>We are very far away from HIS black blinding radiance. His call is heard, but, in truth, not as much as it is in the North, in HIS domain. We're holed up in some basement. We try to go outside as little as possible. The brothers say that in this city one should never go out into the main square because the arrows of the infidels dot the roofs of the city. Someday the mighty fist of the Monolith will reach here as well, bringing us triumphant victory. In the meantime, all we have to do is bring in reinforcements. The second group should be here soon, which will at least increase our presence in this sector a bit. About five minutes ago, Big Brother had warned me that it would soon be necessary to descend into the city's sewers, from where we could strike at the heretics in the Cooptorg building. But before that, we'll have to deal with the man-eating rats that infest the sewer.</text>
	</string>

<string id="gar_postroika_dnevnik_opis">
		<text>A spring-loaded notebook found on the corpse of a stalker in the Garbage. Only the first third of the notebook was scribbled, the rest of the sheets were left untouched. Judging by the abrupt ending of the entries, death caught up with the stalker as he was making his last journal entry.\nThe ferret is a cattle dog. You can't trust him, I'll tell the Barkeep that when I get to the bar. Said everything was quiet at the Garbage, just kilometers of iron and anomalies. No shit. The brothers are still on their way to get stomped. I had to share my loot. They left me with a bare ass. How am I supposed to go to MedPribor now? I'm gonna kill myself if I don't get the papers. I guess I'll have to go to the bar first to get a gun, and then...</text>
	</string>


<string id="gar_postroika_dnevnik_name">
		<text>Diary of a Dead Stalker</text>
	</string>

<string id="st_power_fists">
		<text>Power knuckles</text>
	</string>


<string id="enc_weapons1_power_fists">
		<text>Power knuckles. The design utilizes elements of a strong gravitational artifact.</text>
	</string>

<string id="scintific_pda_military-pda1">
		<text>Special PDA of a member of the military science team. Basic artifact information is available, as well as encrypted coordinates.</text>
	</string>


<string id="hands_gravity_mane">
		<text>Glove</text>
	</string>


<string id="hands_gravity_desc">
		<text>The Gravity Glove is a new experimental weapon that deals damage using the forces of gravity. Developed by scientists based on the theory of gravitational fields. Can attract and repel objects, acts through walls. The distance limit is 30 meters. The closer the object, the stronger the effect of the glove.\nOpportunities:
\n1.Abruptly pull an object toward you. 
\n2.Hit and push an object</text>
	</string>

<string id="bar_barman_kamaz_doki_name">
		<text>Travel log</text>
	</string>


<string id="bar_barman_kamaz_doki_opis">
		<text>A checkered notebook found in the glove compartment of a truck. Its previous owner ripped out the first pages for some reason, so it is impossible to find out when exactly he started keeping the diary. Judging by the earliest surviving date, he was engaged in transportation of equipment and personnel even before the second disaster. Among the invoices and equipment lists are the coordinates of some laboratories that exchanged information and biological materials among themselves. The last entry was two years ago: 
Military stalkers have been opening fire on every car since the Death Trucks showed up. That sucks. Picked up some stalker at their base, got caught when those freaks noticed him. Lucky - I still can't figure out how I heard it. Introduced himself as Strelok. I thought I'd take him to the scientists' camp, where he'd be back on his feet in no time, but he didn't trust the scientists, as it turned out. He said, "Take me to the doctor."</text>
	</string>

<string id="st_hand_torch">
		<text>Handheld flashlight</text>
	</string>


<string id="enc_weapons1_hand_torch">
		<text>A regular handheld flashlight. Does not require recharging. Can be used as a weapon.</text>
	</string>

<string id="tip_use_bar_doska">
		<text>View available jobs</text>
	</string>



<string id="actor_killer">
		<text>Murderer</text>
	</string>


<string id="af_magnet_drop_q1_desc">
		<text>To complete the experiment, this anomalous formation must be thrown into an Elektra-type anomaly.</text>
	</string>



<string id="af_magnet_drop_q2_desc">
		<text>The result of the effect of the Electra anomaly on the subject of the experiment. We need to give it to him for further research.</text>
	</string>

<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn_knife_old_rotten">
		<text>An old SVT-40 bayonet, rusted and pitted due to age and exposure to the elements - but still deadly.</text>
	</string>


<string id="esc_dead_kolodetz_article_tx">
		<text>Missing courier</text>
	</string>



<string id="radbun_razradnil_nado">
		<text>I think you need a surge protector to get through.</text>
	</string>


<string id="tips_jaba_no_go_lvl12">
		<text>Toad: Don't go there now. This place is dead, the level of PSI activity is off the charts. I warned you, stalker.</text>
	</string>


<string id="cod_on_podz_rostka_tx">
		<text>Remembering the code</text>
	</string>

<string id="cod_on_podz_rostka_text">
		<text>Remembered some code... 3781... Seems to be in some kind of tunnels... Rostok?</text>
	</string>


<string id="feskul">
		<text>What? We don't do that. Where did you get this information? Although, maybe whoever told you that meant the camp on the marshes. There's quite often a helicopter with equipment there. It's not working right now, though, because of the high psi radiation.</text>
	</string>

<string id="doc2dolinaapp_desc">
		<text>According to the directive of the Central Committee of the CPSU, the territories within the unconditional mandatory resettlement zone (hereinafter referred to as the CRZ) within a radius of ten kilometers from the site of the accident, as well as a number of infrastructure facilities and dual-use cities (Jupiter plant, Chernobyl-2, Chernobyl Nuclear Power Plant named after M.V. Lomonosov, Chernobyl Nuclear Power Plant, and the Chernobyl Nuclear Power Plant), were to be resettled within a radius of ten kilometers from the site of the accident. Lenin, Yantar complex) together with all documentation are transferred under the management of the governmental organization MOST (Ministry of Defense and Secret Technologies). The primary goals of the above facilities at the beginning of 1987: to conduct projects "Sky-2", "Cover", development of means of psychotropic defense and attack, genetic research, tests in the field of vortex flows and electromagnetic anomalies in various areas of the world and development of new types of energy. A decision was made to conduct the first test launch of the RD-100 special-purpose unit (aka "Russian Woodpecker", Zagorizontnaya Radar Power plant "Duga") under conditions of increased radiation environment.</text>
	</string>



<string id="doc2dolinaapp_name">
		<text>Document #477</text>
	</string>

<string id="empty_butilka_arg_zam_name">
		<text>Flask</text>
	</string>



<string id="empty_butilka_arg_zam_desc">
		<text>You can get some kind of liquid in here.</text>
	</string>


<string id="ametist_bazag_fin">
		<text>Wow! A local legend, here in my workshop! Oh, well. I'm Amethyst. I'm in the gun and gear repair business. You know it's not so good here, that's why I decided to join the environmentalists. And I've always hated going to landfills and cemeteries... So you need something fixed?</text>
	</string>

<string id="arg_jaba_voda_boloto_opis">
		<text>Water sample from the swamp at the MedPribor Research Institute.</text>
	</string>

<string id="arg_jaba_voda_boloto_name">
		<text>Water from the swamp</text>
	</string>

<string id="arg_trader_about_zamery_article_tx">
		<text>Water sample from the NII swamp</text>
	</string>



<string id="arg_trader_about_zamery_article_text">
		<text>Toad ordered a water sample from the swamp at the MedPribor Research Institute. He said there must be a suitable container in the factory.</text>
	</string>

<string id="digger_detector_article_tx">
		<text>A detector for Digger</text>
	</string>



<string id="digger_detector_article_text">
		<text>Digger needs an anomaly detector. Charged. He said there's one stashed on the roof of the factory somewhere. He said something about some stalker with an eye patch. Sounds like bullshit... though.</text>
	</string>

<string id="af_banka_s_holodcom">
		<text>Stud</text>
	</string>



<string id="enc_af_banka_s_holodcom">
		<text>Concentrate anomaly Studen. When a vessel is broken, a new anomaly is formed.</text>
	</string>

<string id="wtf_kurgan_dolina">
		<text>Messer: Hmm. That's something else.</text>
	</string>



<string id="dolina_barman_house_doki_name">
		<text>Observations on changes in the hierarchy of recessive traits</text>
	</string>



<string id="dolina_barman_house_doki_opis">
		<text>Vadim Mikhailovich, we continue to conduct tests as normal. We are waiting for you at our farm to admire the results of recent tests. We are already testing breeds with introduced "wild" genes. In the attachments to this letter, you can take a look at photos of some of the specimens: you can already clearly see the changes in the musculoskeletal system and the physiology of the sensory system. I also recommend looking at the results of experiments to transplant the pituitary gland of the African "hyena" into our wolves. Amazing, isn't it? By the way, yesterday I. G. Uralov suggested that we should already proceed to transplantation of human pituitary gland, but I had to give up this adventure. I'm sorry, I don't have a qualified Preobrazhensky here yet. Where experienced staff are on a different level of our sixth lab. And the human pituitary gland, Vadim Mikhailovich, is no joke! However, I refused to refuse, but I will not say that this idea will go into a drawer for a long time. In the future, we plan to move on to much more serious experiments.
	It is very unfortunate that the unit you have allocated does not allow for a full range of long term concentrated gravity treatments. It just doesn't have enough power. Get it right: other departments get 20% more energy. Even Makarov's department consumes more, even though he has only three lab technicians on staff and they only do accounting. If you would be so kind, Vadim Mikhailovich, increase the lab's power supply. Tell your people at the plant to get the new fourth reactor up and running within a month. Believe me, it will speed up the work process.
	Head of the Department of Biological Breeding and Eugenics, L. P. Romaniuk
	15.04.1986
</text>
	</string>

<string id="nu_pokushai_hot">
		<text>Eat</text>
	</string>

<string id="name_black_gravi_recipies">
		<text>Black Gravy</text>
	</string>


<string id="black_gravi_recipies_desc">
		<text>The conversion requires: Strong gravitational artifact and Strong Needles.</text>
	</string>

<string id="dc_mono1">
		<text>Listen, we got a case for you. Have you heard of the Monolithians? They're local fanatics. They believe a crystal or monolithic block from space fell on the roof of the power plant. Guys say that no one can come closer than 30 meters to them, or they immediately start shooting...</text>
	</string>


<string id="dc_mono2">
		<text>Anyways... our sharpshooters started spotting them on the road to the Swamps. This is no good, I can feel it. I suspect they've got a staging area somewhere up there by the road to the Swamps. You should go see what's out there. but, you know, we're not really in conflict	, we don't touch each other, but we're still fucking bigots. There's no guarantee they won't attack us tomorrow... See if you can find where they've settled. Snipers passed on that their main activity is usually at night, so I think after midnight there's a chance of catching them...</text>
	</string>

<string id="bar_journalist_dnevnik_name">
		<text>Memo to Strelok.</text>
	</string>


<string id="bar_journalist_dnevnik_opis">
		<text>You saved my hide again. What's the second time? I've lost count, frankly. Okay, now for the main point. I'm never coming back to this house again. Information has surfaced that the military has exits to this city. Which means that now I will definitely not be left alone after our joint "business" in the Valley. Rumor has it that some merchants are doing business with the army, which means it's not safe for me to be in the city. We'll have to leave the shelter and move north. I'd advise you to move somewhere away from the suburbs, too. But knowing you and your appetite for trouble, I realize that my advice will pass your ears.
Those documents we got in the Valley give some insight into the situation around the international research center in the Zone. Until recently, this center did exist, but what has become of it now is unknown. Perhaps it still exists today. We need to find him, Strelok. Unfortunately, I don't have any more information about this center. The eggheads from Yantar couldn't say anything - they blamed it all on signatures on non-disclosure and release of state secrets. 
By the way, if you get a chance, I suggest you drop in on an old acquaintance in the Swamps. He asked me to tell you that he got the medicine you asked for from the scientists. Be careful out there. Stalkers in the bar say that after the extreme emission there psi radiation is prohibitive. Take the other trail.	Take care of yourself, for the Zone's sake.
	Journalist</text>
	</string>

<string id="gar_doc_thousand_dead_desc">
		<text>Personnel: 1,245. 

Of which: 763 are official military personnel; 16 are military stalker guides. 

Support: 45 Armored Personnel Carriers (BTR-70), 8 T-64 tanks, 3 Mi-24 helicopters. 

Main route: equipment graveyard - City - Old Storages - Pripyat - Power plant - F12L area. 

Reserve: equipment cemetery - City - Lake Yantar - G. Free Way - Pripyat - Power plant - F12L area. 

Digression: not provided.

Ambient: There may be previously unknown anomalies closer to the F12L area. Resistance: unknown. The discovery of the remains of the first exploring expedition is likely. 

Objective: to break through to the epicenter of the Zone and destroy the cause of the deadly anomalous fields. Stop the growth and expansion of the Zone's anomalous fields. Locate those involved in the creation of the Zone.

2009.05.13.
</text>
	</string>


<string id="gar_doc_thousand_dead_name">
		<text>Part of the plans and maps of one of the lost detachments of the military expedition</text>
	</string>

<string id="esc_zavod_plot_doki_opis">
		<text>The state commission found no violations during its inspection of the science facilities. The Commission concluded to issue a permit for extension of research works on the territory of the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone not later than 02.06.1998. Currently, the scientific research institute "MedPribor" (see Annex ** for a breakdown of activities) is developing equipment for complex devices used in radiation oncology. From the technical data, it appears that the device will be in high demand for patients with "tumor cordis, casus inoperabilis". The main advantages of the new equipment: increased safety measures for both the patient and the treating physician during the procedure, record speed of one irradiation procedure. In this regard, we ask to withdraw the research documents from the Central Archive and transfer them to the file cabinet of the Research Institute "MedPribor" to optimize the reporting work. </text>
	</string>


<string id="esc_zavod_plot_doki_name">
		<text>The document from the attic</text>
	</string>

<string id="enc_equipment_battery_change_headlamp">
		<text>Battery for a headlamp.</text>
	</string>


<string id="battery_change_headlamp_short_name">
		<text>Battery</text>
	</string>

<string id="gazeta_otrivok_1_name">
		<text>"Echoes of Chernobyl." No. 3 of 2007.</text>
	</string>


<string id="gazeta_otrivok_1_opis">
		<text>... The first reports of missing children from the village, which is close to the perimeter of the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone, were received by the Ivankivka District Department of the Ministry of Internal Affairs only the next morning. Neither the distribution of orientations nor the help of volunteers yielded promising results. It was decided by the rescue team coordinators to triple the search area. 
	"In case the missing children are not found within three weeks, the search will have to be called off," the leader of a group of volunteers in Sector A8 warns us.

\nLaw enforcement officials have suggested that children may have traveled to the CEZ, but cordon commanders say that no persons under the age of majority have been recorded in the vicinity of the thirty-kilometer perimeter. In response to the lead coordinator's request for permission to search for the children on the territory of the CEZ, the perimeter command refused, citing the territory's closed military regime.
	Photos, first and last names can be seen on the last page. The editorial board of the newspaper "Echo of Chernobyl" according to the rescue group is offering a cash reward for any information on the whereabouts of the missing children that will help the search.</text>
	</string>

<string id="ecolog_kogo_tam_door12">
		<text>You've been to the factory before, right? They say it's notorious among stalkers, and that anyone who climbs into the attic will have bad luck. At the Garbage, a guy with an eyepatch even said that a legendary stalker once got betrayed and died there.</text>
	</string>

<string id="ecolog_kogo_tam_door122">
		<text>Yeah, well, yeah. It's up to you in the big picture... but I need a simple anomaly detector. I heard there's one hidden in the attic of the factory. Unless, of course, it's already been stolen. If you get it, I'll give you a new 9x18. It's up to you, kid, to go there or not to go there.</text>
	</string>

<string id="ecolog_kogo_tam_door">
		<text>The door! Close the door. This isn't a passageway.</text>
	</string>


<string id="barman_hey_slez_ska">
		<text>What are you, drunk? Get down from there!</text>
	</string>


<string id="city_fake_dnevnik_name">
		<text>The sarcophagus research document</text>
	</string>

<string id="city_fake_dnevnik_opis">
		<text>To the Head of Kiev Branch of Laboratory No. 15, Karteevich I. L.\
Ivan Lvovich, after conferring with the rest of the group, we have unanimously approved
an offer to give you a sample of the anomalous body, as you requested. The body itself
is dangerously close to the infamous Helena cap, due to the
than it is difficult to study it on site. What we've been able to discover about
the nature of the crystal is described below. We send you a sample container. Labeling
container: "Monolith 2."\n*** \n
Found in the bowels of Unit 4, a body of anomalous nature has no
no analogs with officially (and unofficially) known to modern science alloys.
Psi radiation levels range from ~1200 to ~1500 Jigowatts, which is dangerous
for the life of anyone who comes within ten meters of it. In addition to that,
we discovered a peculiarity in the behavior of the crystal: the creation of organic and
of inorganic substances from literally nothing... </text>
	</string>

<string id="ros_bloodsuk_name">
		<text>Diary of a Bloodsucker's Habits.</text>
	</string>

<string id="ros_bloodsuk_opis">
		<text>In the personal diary of a stalker-hunter found very interesting notes on the habits of mutant bloodsuckers:\


		Entry 1: From the description of the extreme raid into the Silent Hills: Followed Bull's group from afar. The big man and the rookies entered the village. Usually knowledgeable people avoid this place, knowing its inhabitants. Very carefully, trying not to make a sound, the stalkers walked around the crumbling wall of the water tower. They came to a low spot between two hills. There they noticed bodies lying around. They carefully moved closer. In front of them was a gruesome sight: disfigured corpses that belonged to two stalkers. The impression of the bodies was as if not only blood, but all the insides had been drained out of them, leaving only the skin, the outer shell. The stunned stalkers staggered back to cover. Meanwhile, from behind, a tall mutant with huge outgrowths on its muzzle silently jumped down from the five-meter wall. His sickle-shaped arms opened to embrace Bull, who stood closer to him. The thug's back felt someone's presence. He abruptly recoiled and turned around at the same time. Too late - sickle-shaped hands with long fingers and strange suction cups on their palms grabbed his abruptly collapsed body. Fainting, the stalker notices a creepy face, with ugly outgrowths instead of a mouth, approaching his neck. The rookies managed to run away with ghastly screams, leaving their mentor to die. They didn't get far - the frightened stalkers ran right out into the anomaly field...\n

		Entry 2: Bloodsucker. High humidity and darkness create all the conditions necessary to live and hunt. Skin-eating mucus retains its main properties only in a moist environment. Since the bloodsucker has a thermoregulation system at the primitive level of frogs, its metabolism is slow, depending on the air temperature. The best climate for a bloodsucker is high humidity and temperatures above 17-18'C. The bloodhound is a nocturnal animal, the retina of its eye has more cones than the human retina of a human being, allowing it to see in the dark and twilight better than in the daytime. In the dark, his pupils are understandably dilated, so in the light of a flashlight a retina is visible: the so-called red-eye effect.\n
		Record 3: Possible habitat identified:\n
Dungeons:\n1.	Caves
2.	Underground corridors
3.	Basement
Surface:\n1.	Wastelands
2.	Dumps
Premises:\n1.	Factory premises
2.	House premises
3. waste storage facilities
4.	Paddocks
Anomalous zones:\n1.	Radiation hotspots
2. Fog.


		Entry 4: An interesting subject for zoologists are the tentacles on the snout. Presumably these are modified mouth organs - tongue, cheeks and mandible. The bloodsucker's mouth cavity disappeared, splitting into tentacle-like branches. They serve several functions. Basically, it is a sensory organ and part of the oral apparatus. As a sensory organ, the tentacles are analogous to the bifurcated tongue in reptiles. Their surface is heterogeneous and on the inner (mouth) part is dotted with many receptors - this is one of the most sensitive areas in the bloodsucker. On the inner surface are located their mucous glands. The internal structure of the tentacles corresponds to their functional purpose, i.e. it is permeated with blood vessels and nerves. It also has three layers of musculature, allowing the bloodsucker to utilize them as it feeds. When in a relaxed state, the tentacles sway and pick up odors in the air.
</text>
	</string>

<string id="esc_vishka_dnevnik_name">
		<text>Expedition diary</text>
	</string>



<string id="esc_vishka_dnevnik_opis">
		<text>An old yellowed notebook with notes that deal with the first military expeditions to the Zone. Most of the pages are bloodstained or missing altogether. In some places, the handwriting is impossible to make out.\n
	Recording 3. 15.03.2007\n
	... The evacuation of civilians from the village took longer than the perimeter leadership had originally anticipated. We're missing five residents. They're all in their mid-twenties. According to eyewitness accounts, an hour after the ''incident'' the old men took off northward. The major strictly forbade to send the group after them...\n
	Record 5. 16.03.2007\n
       ... We came to a graveyard of radioactive equipment. Lost two boxes along the way. The first one somehow ducked into the curb and all the electronics failed. The second one suddenly stopped in the middle of the road at the entrance to the dump. There are rumors among officers that the enemy is using electromagnetic weapons and disabling our equipment to delay us. The question is: who is the enemy...?\n
	Record 11. 19.03.2007\n
	... The major has gone completely off the rails - he suggests that we fortify ourselves in the city and wait there for reinforcements. Communication with the command is impossible - the radio is dead. Vasiliev had been working on it for two hours already; the major gave him a hard slap for his careless attitude to the radio. The scouts went north to the old warehouses. They say there may be survivors.\n
	Record 17. 21.03.2007\n
	... We finally found Vasiliev. Locked himself inside in one of the houses on the second floor. Had to break down the door to get to him. Hung himself. The scouts still haven't returned - the Major is already going to send more men after them. Vasyan offered to volunteer. Says we need to make a detour and go out to the Perimeter. I agreed.
</text>
	</string>

<string id="af-esc_vishka">
		<text>An unknown artifact</text>
	</string>

<string id="enc_zone_artifact_esc_vishka">
		<text>Unknown anomalous formation. It floats a bit in the air, while being quite heavy.</text>
	</string>

<string id="tips_esc_sos_newbie">
		<text>SOS: Come in! Somebody help me, I'm out here in the woods behind the muck!</text>
	</string>


<string id="yan_sah_spam_0">
		<text>Professor: No reception, stalker. All questions to our assistant in the annex next to the bunker.</text>
	</string>


<string id="hey_goplit2">
		<text>Messer: Hey, you okay?</text>
	</string>


<string id="hey_goplit">
		<text>Messer: Hey, Goplit!</text>
	</string>

<string id="agr_olr_1_pogo_koluchki_article_tx">
		<text>Wounded Goplit</text>
	</string>

<string id="agr_olr_1_pogo_koluchki_article_text">
		<text>Goplit, stalker, cordon rookie in trouble. He seems to be a longtime resident here and may be able to share information. In order to bring him to his senses you need to give him 2 black needle artifacts or 5 regular needle artifacts. I think that will be enough.</text>
	</string>

<string id="onn_bun_etaj2">
		<text>Turn on the second floor lights</text>
	</string>

<string id="onn_bun_etaj1">
		<text>Turn on the first floor lights</text>
	</string>

<string id="radbun_svet_nado">
		<text>Shit. Clearly not worth sticking around for too long... and where are all these scientists?</text>
	</string>


<string id="battery_change_name">
		<text>PDA battery</text>
	</string>


<string id="battery_change_short_name">
		<text>Battery</text>
	</string>

<string id="enc_equipment_battery_change">
		<text>Removable rechargeable battery for PDAs. You can use it to find out the current charge of your portable computer.</text>
	</string>


<string id="yan_oborud_quest_desc">
		<text>A heavy crate of equipment for the scientists' camp at Lake Yantar.</text>
	</string>



<string id="yan_oborud_quest_name">
		<text>Equipment box</text>
	</string>

<string id="fil_saf_papka_name">
		<text>Saffiano folder</text>
	</string>


<string id="fil_saf_papka_opis">
		<text>A saffiano-covered file, the owner was obviously a high-ranking man. Inside data on special equipment deliveries to the XZ-09 laboratory. Probably worth a pretty penny. Reports on the observation of the results of experiments 1) Implementation of the psycho-emotional correction unit in the settlement of employees of the Atomic Power plant was successful. Increases in productivity, efficiency and stamina have been observed among Chernobyl Power plant employees. Psychotherapists have noted a decrease in emotional intensity. It is true that the contingent complains of a sharp decline in general commutative manifestations. The version with the consequences of exposure to ionizing radiation is considered official.
2) Surveillance report on the contingent of long-term residents of the territories with radiation background that does not always coincide with the established norms. Unscheduled gene mutations were seen among the test subjects. Suddenly, previously recessive traits became dominant, which affected production level performance. The observation of new daughter specimens was decided to be handed over to the reserve group. Observation of maternal specimens is ongoing.
</text>
</string>

<string id="tips_monolit_ahtung_military">
		<text>Stalker, if you come near us, we will open fire. Go away.</text>
	</string>



<string id="pomosnik_propizdel_article_tx">
		<text>Silver pendant</text>
	</string>



<string id="pomosnik_propizdel_article_text">
		<text>The scientist at the science complex on Yantar refuses to let me into the Professor's bunker because of some personal problem. His wife disappeared in a lab under the Dark Valley. Clearly he wants the pendant that he said he gave her... Do I go looking for that pendant, or do I send that asshole back there?</text>
	</string>





<string id="garbaga_podzemka_open_tip">
		<text>Start generator (gasoline reserve is required)</text>
	</string>



<string id="bar_hidd_skull">
		<text>formulae ueteres exorsismorum et excommunicationum</text>
	</string>


<string id="skaner_skazal_arty_article_tx">
		<text>Toad's missing courier</text>
	</string>


<string id="skaner_skazal_arty_article_text">
		<text>Toad: Lost contact with one of my couriers near an abandoned village. I don't know where he disappeared to. Do me a favor and find him.</text>
	</string>




<string id="def_art_no_desc">
		<text>An artifact with unknown properties.</text>
	</string>



<string id="why_bacausewolfs">
		<text>Yeah, well, what did you think? We have explosives, I think. We've been planting some land mines here. But I can see you have an interest in the house. Okay, here's the deal. Can you get me an artifact called a disintegrator, preferably a whole one. And one Zuda, I hear it's good for your health. If you bring the good stuff, I'll assign you our bomb squad to do it. Well, if you're tight on artifacts, fine, I'll take 10 grand from you and deal.</text>
	</string>



<string id="skaner_skazal_arty_article_tx">
		<text>Freedom leader.</text>
	</string>


<string id="skaner_skazal_arty_article_text">
		<text>The leader of the Freedom faction asks for a Disintegrator and Zuda artifact or a payment of 10,000 for blowing up the door where the Psi Weapon scientist lived.</text>
	</string>






<string id="empty_butilka_name">
		<text>Empty can</text>
	</string>


<string id="empty_butilka_desc">
		<text>An empty jar of special glass into which the substance of the Studen anomaly can be typed.</text>
	</string>






<string id="vedmak_zaidi_basem_artcl_tx">
		<text>Message from Witcher</text>
	</string>




<string id="vedmak_zaidi_basem_artcl_text">
		<text>On the approach to the bar came a message from Witcher asking for a meeting...</text>
	</string>





<string id="naity_doki_zablika_article_tx">
		<text>The Zyablikov brothers</text>
	</string>



<string id="naity_doki_zablika_article_text">
		<text>A scientist in Bar asked me to find any information about his missing brother, who worked there, at the Rostok factory. Promised a suit for helping me find it.</text>
	</string>







<string id="dolg_road_nin_donk_now">
		<text>Spread the chain! It's about to start! According to intelligence, the lair of the blind dogs was supposed to be in that hollow over there... Stalker! Get over here quick, we need your help!</text>
	</string>




<string id="enc_equipment_antirad_medpribor">
		<text>An experimental sample of an anti-radiation drug designed to protect the human body from alternative types of radiation contamination. The time of action is no more than a few tens of minutes, depending on the expiration date.\nServes as a treatment for radiation sickness.</text>
	</string>



<string id="lvl_level12">
		<text>Level 12</text>
	</string>



<string id="pda_btn_quests_ssss">
		<text>^^^^^Tasks^^^^^</text>
	</string>


<string id="pda_btn_map_ssss">
		<text>^^^^^Map^^^^^</text>
	</string>



<string id="pda_btn_diary_ssss">
		<text>^^^^^Notes^^^^^</text>
	</string>



<string id="pda_btn_contacts_ssss">
		<text>^^^^^Contacts^^^^^</text>
	</string>



<string id="pda_btn_encyclopedia_ssss">
		<text>^Encyclopedia^</text>
	</string>






<string id="af_dummy_dummy_q1_desc">
		<text>It's a strange kind of artifact Pee Wee. It's stuck to the backpack wall. It gives off a faint greenish glow.</text>
	</string>



<string id="Conserva_short">
		<text>Conserve</text>
	</string>



<string id="shiiiiiiit_1">
		<text>Not much, believe me. You know, the device is a rare thing. Not every soldier is eager to share it. So..., works in autonomous mode, the charge is enough for... for quite some time. If you need another one, come on over. Just don't forget the money.</text>
	</string>







<string id="digger_combez_atc_agr_tx">
		<text>Digger's Note.</text>
	</string>



<string id="digger_combez_atc_agr_text">
		<text>Decided to raid the NRI with our local landmark from the truck of death... and why not? He even got me a gravity gun to go with it. It's good stuff. The main thing is not to forget where I left the spare scientist from the last raid, or it's a research institute... okay. I hid it in the cab of the locomotive, I think I'll remember it as soon as I see it... the main thing is that no one stole it when I came...</text>
	</string>







<string id="trader_road_nin_donk_now">
		<text>Toad: I don't recommend going there, it's a scary place. I can't believe how loud it's buzzing. Although sometimes some gangsters came from there, local kids, they hung out here, over the bridge.</text>
	</string>




<string id="svamp_mechenyy_article_tx">
		<text>Another marked one</text>
	</string>


<string id="svamp_mechenyy_article_text">
		<text>Toad said a stalker from the death truck came by looking for me. I need to find him in the swamp, he's obviously in one of the huts. Maybe he remembers something and can clarify things.</text>
	</string>




<string id="pda_dead_off_shit_tx">
		<text>PDA charge</text>
	</string>


<string id="pda_dead_off_shit_text">
		<text>You have to remember to keep your pda charged... especially in raids.</text>
	</string>



<string id="dolg_barter_shit_tx">
		<text>Bartering at the Duty Guy</text>
	</string>


<string id="dolg_barter_shit_text">
		<text>Stalker Duty in the bar offers to exchange ammunition, and other things, such as gasoline for vodka... You can find him at their base at night, or in its vicinity, and negotiate a barter... However, it's unclear how this may yet end...</text>
	</string>




<string id="mg_leader_ab_bolt">
		<text>Don't forget the bolts, buddy...</text>
	</string>


<string id="enc_sigaret">
		<text>A regular Dream brand cigarette. Smoking is bad for you, but temporarily tones you down a bit.</text>
	</string>


<string id="sigaret">
		<text>Cigarette</text>
	</string>


<string id="jaba_arts_go_tx">
		<text>Toad's Order #1</text>
	</string>



<string id="jaba_arts_go_text">
		<text>I need a weak gravity...and a medium, I mean regular one too. Probably seen these before. You bring it in, I'll take it back at a higher price. And if you get both of them, I'll make you an extra one from me.</text>
	</string>





<string id="enc_equipment_detector_siniy">
		<text>A detector for measuring anomalous activity. To make measurements it is necessary to take the device in your hands and activate it near the source of anomalous energy.</text>
	</string>


<string id="detector_siniy_name">
		<text>Detector</text>
	</string>



<string id="water">
		<text>Water</text>
	</string>


<string id="enc_equipment_food_water">
		<text>Drinking water, helps quench thirst. Produced clearly out of the zone.</text>
	</string>



<string id="dont_open_deads_here">
		<text>It says "bodies here</text>
	</string>


<string id="hidd_code_1">
		<text>...54...</text>
	</string>


<string id="hidd_code_2">
		<text>.1...8...</text>
	</string>


<string id="hidd_code_3">
		<text>2......</text>
	</string>


<string id="hidd_code_4">
		<text>......3</text>
	</string>


<string id="hidd_code_5">
		<text>..54...</text>
	</string>


<string id="hidd_code_6">
		<text>....83.</text>
	</string>



<string id="monobar1">
		<text>I'm going to tell you a story I tell everyone. It's the legend of the Monolith, quite
that may have caused the Zone. In 2006, the Zone exploded, there were
measures were taken and the population in the district was evacuated, the Zone was cordoned off by army units. No one's
knew what was going on, panic all around, the Zone was growing, the field labs were powerless. Heap
people died inside. Everyone is afraid of radiation that could cover half of Europe.</text>
	</string>


<string id="monobar2">
		<text>A few years went by, the first desperate guys like you showed up. They called themselves
stalkers. They penetrated the army cordons, believing that there was something in the Zone, and it was
something that can bring them wealth, fulfill their desires. Slowly we started
dragging strange things out of there, artifacts that were instantly chased.
Scientists went crazy over these things. For one such sample they paid mad money, no
the way it is now. And so, the first stories and legends emerged about what was in the
inside the Zone, near a dilapidated nuclear power plant. One of the veterans retold the story,
heard from one of the local old-timer stalkers, a story about the Monolith, supposedly a
the wish-granting one. What hysteria ensued, stalkers huddled together in groups and
to the center of the Zone, each wanting something from the Monolith. The gloomy ones appeared
details of the first stalker to reach Monolith. Back when the Zone first
came along, a lot of people were trapped, cut off from the outside world.</text>
	</string>


<string id="monobar3">
		<text>Most perished, but there were rare lucky ones who not only survived, but also
trying to do something about it. One of the survivors ended up near the power plant, inside
he saw a strange glow. He had no choice, the way back was cut off, and he was
got closer. A picture was revealed to him-the pierced roof of the sarcophagus, illuminated by the
from the inside. He climbed the wall and the insides of the Sarcophagus were revealed before him. There,
amid piles of metal debris and charred concrete pancakes, rested a huge
a black block of geometric shape. That was the Monolith. Stalker woke up to a strange
and realized he'd climbed into a Sarcophagus that stinks to high heaven. The horror
restrained him, and the call of the Monolith monotonously pierced through the fear. The monolith called out to him, and at the
the stalker's hair stood on end. Strange, creepy things were exploding in his head
pictures of the alien. We don't know what's in
of this story, true or false.</text>
	</string>



<string id="monobar4">
		<text>The point is, he made a wish and it came true,
and the Zone increased dramatically by five kilometers. It seems that for every execution
the Zone's desire to eat our Earth. But that doesn't stop the stalkers. They're
continue to tear inward, carrying their deepest desires to the Monolith...</text>
	</string>






<string id="jaba_ab_mon_tx">
		<text>Toad's story about the monolith</text>
	</string>


<string id="jaba_ab_mon_text">
		<text>There's a lot of rumors about this thing, the Monolith thing. And rumors of all kinds.
Some stalker told me that the Monolith is a sort of... What did he say? The basis of all human aspirations and desires, is it? Something unique to which
man strives... Quin-tez-sen-tsi-yah, fuck... He said a lot of clever things back then -
I can't remember everything. I wasn't really listening - I wished he'd just shut up and get out
get the hell out of the basement. He was right about something. Everyone aspires to the Monolith. Rumor has it that
is something of extraterrestrial origin. I heard he landed near the Sarcophagus,
or the roof blew through the roof and into reactor four, yeah. That's why a lot of people
they think he's the reason the Zone came into existence.</text>
	</string>



<string id="babosy_platit">
		<text>Cost of payoff:</text>
	</string>


<string id="gar_zov_mon_text">
		<text>It was all of a sudden... the partner died right before my eyes in a split second... he literally burned from the inside out... what was that? And that call-- something was calling me-- I'll have to tell Toad about it when I get to his bunker.</text>
	</string>



<string id="gar_zov_mon_tx">
		<text>A strange call</text>
	</string>



<string id="doki_agro_dyatel_opis">
		<text>A small pile of papers with some drawings and calculations. -the impact zone of the plant in the city area is approximately several tens of kilometers, depending on the power supplied... - The mobile versions of units 2 and 3 are currently inactive, unit 3 is still in the scientist camp as far as I know.  </text>
	</string>




<string id="doki_agro_dyatel_name">
		<text>R-Dyatel project documentation</text>
	</string>





<string id="milradio_article_tx">
		<text>Strange radio program.</text>
	</string>


<string id="milradio_article_text">
		<text>Heard a broadcast on an ancient radio. Probably from
the Big Land, which is sometimes mentioned by other stalkers. I don't know if they were telling the truth on the air or lying;
if it was an old tape or a live feed, but I can't
believe what I'm hearing.
...no real basis for a serious worries.
...temporary measures...
... decisive actions...
...drastic changes...
...it's certainly too early to talk about accomplishments
biological minimum...
It feels like that the Big Land
is as messed up as the Zone... if not worse. You have to wonder if God exists.
Earth, really? I've probably been there. In my
past. What if I wasn't? Maybe there's no
Big Land? Then where do stalkers come from, and where is this broadcast coming from?</text>
	</string>


<string id="bar_generator_tip">
		<text>Refuel the generator (a can of gasoline is required).</text>
	</string>


<string id="tips_jaba_ahtung_yantar">
		<text>Toad: Stalker! You're near the Yantar crossing now. Don't go in there now unless you want your brains to turn into mush.</text>
	</string>


<string id="tips_barman_ahtung_military">
		<text>Stalker! You're near the Silent Hills crossing now. Don't go in there now unless you want your brains to turn into mush. Keep this in mind.</text>
	</string>



<string id="tips_barman_ahtung_yantar">
		<text>Stalker! You're near the Yantar crossing now. Don't go in there now unless you want your brains to turn into mush.</text>
	</string>


<string id="angelfuck4">
		<text>We're scientists, we're interested in everything that happens here. So, as I said, the mutant is quite rare in these parts, but recently a group of freedom fighters that is in the dead city of Shining Path noticed one such individual wandering in the vicinity of the destroyed apartment buildings. And it is this one that is of particular interest to us. It's been spotted-- but that's beside the point. You see, our group is small in number, and we need to collect material, so you must capture this mutant for us. We need live tissue samples, so we can't kill the monster. Say lock it up somewhere in one of the apartments in town, or any other suitable place. Alright, go ahead, stalker.</text>
	</string>



<string id="neizvest32nyy_bandits">
		<text>That's it, and now I need a drink. Come over later.</text>
	</string>

<string id="neizvestnyy_bandits">
		<text>An unknown bandit</text>
	</string>



<string id="neizvestnyy_stalker">
		<text>Unknown stalker</text>
	</string>


<string id="neizvestnyy_novichok">
		<text>Unknown rookie</text>
	</string>



<string id="neizvestnyy_voyaka">
		<text>Unknown military man</text>
	</string>




<string id="device_pda_last_day">
		<text>PDA stalker group Last Day. Last entry -...the world is heading for the end of the world... the Zone's territory will soon expand many times over. Several countries will find themselves in the Zone, whose populations will not have time to evacuate... data error...we track down zombified stalkers, study psi radiation, develop theories about psychotropic weapons and how they work. It is necessary to send agents, as the target is extremely difficult to reach, even though they can penetrate outside the zone.</text>
	</string>



<string id="bolezn_behenstvo_art_tx">
		<text>Diseases: Rabies</text>
	</string>

<string id="bolezn_behenstvo_art_text">
		<text>Caught rabies from a dog bite. You're lucky you had a chance to heal. You have to be careful with dogs from now on, it turns out these things are not as harmless as you might think at first glance. I bet most of them are infected with this virus... and the virus is insidious. The symptoms occur spontaneously and not immediately.</text>
	</string>




<string id="mg_zaidivdom_hello">
		<text>Stalker, get in the house. I need help.</text>
	</string>





<string id="jellomg_1">
		<text>Don't shoot. I won't hurt you unless you want me to.</text>
	</string>



<string id="jellomg_2">
		<text>You're not human. How can you talk?</text>
	</string>



<string id="jellomg_3">
		<text>There was when what... talk... it's no problem... stalker, you wouldn't happen to have anything to eat, would you?</text>
	</string>



<string id="jellomg_4">
		<text>Anti-rad</text>
	</string>





<string id="Antirad_sh">
		<text>Anti-rad</text>
	</string>


<string id="Medkit_short">
		<text>Health-13</text>
	</string>


<string id="Medkit_army_sh">
		<text>Health-16</text>
	</string>


<string id="Medkit_scientific_sh">
		<text>Health-18</text>
	</string>


<string id="stalker_outfit_name_m671">
		<text>Damaged suit</text>
	</string>


<string id="stalker_outfit_description_m671">
		<text>A stalker's jumpsuit completely worn out and turned to dust.</text>
	</string>


<string id="st_outfit_spawn_poltera_article_tx">
		<text>A suit for a partner</text>
	</string>


<string id="st_outfit_spawn_poltera_article_text">
		<text>Found a man to go to the NRI together. We need to get a costume for him though, otherwise he won't go. Toad said he had one, but in return he asked to deal with a certain mutant in the village beyond the bridge. Well, what else is left?</text>
	</string>



<string id="esc_spawn_poltera_masinistadart_tx">
		<text>A train wreck</text>
	</string>


<string id="esc_spawn_poltera_masinistadart_text">
		<text>Toad promises a new scientific suit suitable for trips to research institutes and especially radiation-contaminated zones. We need to check out a railroad embankment with a fallen train lying next to it.</text>
	</string>


<string id="bocjonok_start_article_tx">
		<text>The radioactive house behind the bridge</text>
	</string>

<string id="bocjonok_start_article_text">
		<text>I got my hazmat suit, Toad noticed it right away. Asked me to get something just as phoned in from the house that's as phoned in as a reactor. The suit is supposed to protect against radiation, but you need to check the condition first. If there is a lot of wear, you should not climb inside it.</text>
	</string>



<string id="dead_case_go_osved_article_tx">
		<text>It's a strange case</text>
	</string>



<string id="dead_case_go_osved_article_text">
		<text>Found a strange case on the tower... there are dead bodies nearby, practically bones already. Probably some kind of scientific expedition or something. Toad showed interest, but I decided to keep him...for now. Said to talk to a certain Informant at the bar.</text>
	</string>



<string id="Diary_tog">
		<text>Stalker requests and notes</text>
	</string>


<string id="glaz_atric_tx">
		<text>Insert eye</text>
	</string>

<string id="glaz_atric_text">
		<text>I met a stalker named Phil at the Garbage. Asked me to get him his false eye. He says that it's with a stalker at the Duty checkpoint on the northern part of the dump.</text>
	</string>


<string id="find_aka_novic">
		<text>Kalashnikov for the beginner</text>
	</string>


<string id="find_aka_novic_text">
		<text>The strange rookie at the rock asks to take his AK74 by force from the bandits. That's a nice weapon. Maybe I should keep it, send it out, or-- or--</text>
	</string>




<string id="psy_blocerator_desc">
		<text>A psi-damage shielding device for the Dark Valley. Doesn't save you from exposure to strong radiation. Used by military stalkers as well as veteran stalkers.</text>
	</string>

<string id="psy_blocerator">
		<text>Psi-blocker</text>
	</string>

<string id="item_razradnik_name">
		<text>Discharger</text>
	</string>


<string id="esc_dead_bochonok_name">
		<text>Barrel</text>
	</string>


<string id="esc_dead_bochonok_desc">
		<text>The barrel from the radioactive house. The sign on the side says hazardous materials.</text>
	</string>


<string id="item_razradnik_desc">
		<text>Anomaly Discharger. Temporarily neutralizes anomalous activity and radiation within a radius of about 10 meters from the activation site. To activate, you must activate the device near the anomaly.</text>
	</string>



    <string id="wpn-pistol_future">
		<text>Paralyzer</text>
	</string>


    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pistol_future">
		<text>A paralyzer pistol developed presumably in the northern part of the exclusion zone.\nAffects humans and mutants, causing a sense of panic in the enemy.</text>
	</string>


<string id="uouoifd4">
		<text>I don't know. They wanted to shut down the radiation on the lower levels to get access to some documents. I don't know the details of it. Look, in the main hall, there's-- there should be an emergency release switch for the front door. This is our chance.</text>
	</string>


<string id="uouoifd3">
		<text>Closed? Holy shit. We were brought up on a standard nighttime alert. A few minutes to pack, then into the chopper. We got here last night. We had a couple of people with us in, you know, orange jumpsuits... they were with the equipment, but they're probably rotting around here somewhere. I don't know what it was. It came out of nowhere. We thought it was one of the surviving scientists, but this thing attacked the lieutenant... chewed off half his face. Damn it, get me out of here!</text>
	</string>

<string id="uouoifd2">
		<text>Alright, alright, you just tell me how. As soon as I walked in here, the door automatically closed. What was your squad's mission and why were they all killed?</text>
	</string>


<string id="uouoifd">
		<text>Stalker! Ah. Whew. I thought I was gonna stay here forever. Our squad was on a mission here-- all dead. I'm the one who ran away, hid, piled my crates here, fought back for the first...hell how long have I been here...a day or two. Get me the hell out of here, please. I can't do it alone.</text>
	</string>


    <string id="tips_arg_nov_marevo2">
		<text>Unknown stalker: Damn, that anomaly. Help me get out of here, please.</text>
	</string>


    <string id="tips_arg_nov_marevo">
		<text>Unknown stalker: Hey, you're a stalker! By the Tunnel! I'm inside here, please help me!</text>
	</string>


   <string id="tips_arg_trader_about_zamery">
		<text>Messer, you're in the swamp area, aren't you? Got a little errand for you... The scientists at the science camp on Yantar ordered me to get water samples from there. If you're around, do them a favor. There's probably some vials in the complexes, so you can fill them up. Yeah, don't go to Yantar now, there's so much radiation, you'll burn your brains out. Anyway, get some samples, and then when you're near my bunker, drop them off. That's it.</text>
	</string>


    <string id="device_pda_slizen_reg_desc">
		<text>PDA of a stalker of the Black Slime faction. Merchants can offer a good price for it.</text>
	</string>


    <string id="device_pda_slizen_desc">
		<text>PDA of the leader of the Black Slimes. The access code record for the underground complex is access code 4578.</text>
	</string>


    <string id="tip_use_lestniza">
		<text>get out</text>
	</string>


    <string id="st_attach_gl_to_2">
		<text>attach grenade launcher</text>
	</string>


   <string id="st_attach_scope_to_2">
		<text>attach scope</text>
	</string>

      <string id="kb_car_open_door">
		<text>---</text>
	</string>


       <string id="st_actor_netspawn">
		<text>CLIENT: Synchronising</text>
	</string>


       <string id="st_move_to_slot6">
		<text>Put on a suit</text>
	</string>


        <string id="st_move_to_slot5">
		<text>Slot five.</text>
	</string>


        <string id="st_move_to_slot4">
		<text>In slot four.</text>
	</string>


        <string id="st_move_to_slot3">
		<text>In the third slot</text>
	</string>


       <string id="st_move_to_slot2">
		<text>In the second slot</text>
	</string>


       <string id="st_move_to_slot1">
		<text>In the first slot.</text>
	</string>



       <string id="ui_st_money_regional">
		<text>$</text>
	</string>



       <string id="tip_use_light_hata">
		<text>Lighting control</text>
	</string>


       <string id="tip_use_verstak">
		<text>Use a workbench</text>
	</string>

       <string id="rpk_empty_now">
		<text>No ammunition</text>
	</string>


       <string id="barmen_wtf_valinah">
		<text>There will be no talking now... Come back in the morning.</text>
	</string>


       <string id="barmen_wtf_uyoneed">
		<text>Hey, stalker, what do you need?</text>
	</string>


       <string id="jaba_trader_bio">
		<text>Stalkers returning from the Zone sell the artifacts they find to an old stalker-trader, he has many connections to the outside world. The customers of artifacts are diverse - scientists, military, representatives of corporations. Customers order Toad to collect certain artifacts, and he in turn gives tasks to stalkers. You can also buy weapons and a variety of equipment from the merchant. Lives in the cellar of an abandoned cabin. He's a bossy fat guy with bulging eyes. Has a very nasty and mean character. Dressed in a tank top and pants, the stump of his left arm is wrapped in black leather. He has difficulty walking because of his broken legs. There are rumors of rookie stalkers that were killed by him, whom he let go on a deliberately deadly mission. But he's the only merchant in the area, you have to go to him. Doesn't put stalkers in anything and is frankly rude to them. Keeps a shotgun on him just in case, mood is as bad as ever.</text>
	</string>



       <string id="pizdui_na_krisu">
		<text>Alright, head to the bunker site.</text>
	</string>



        <string id="diplomat_code_viska_name_desc">
		<text>An old shabby briefcase with a code lock. Closed. Looks like we can't open it with improvised means. There's something inside.</text>
	</string>


        <string id="diplomat_code_viska_name">
		<text>Closed briefcase</text>
	</string>



	<string id="loced_from_other_side_olr">
		<text>Closed on the other side</text>
	</string>



	<string id="OLR_3_start_here_1111111">
		<text>!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!! FRA 30 !!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!</text>
	</string>



	<string id="car_task_moskv_tx">
		<text>Bought Moskvich</text>
	</string>


	<string id="car_task_lada_tx">
		<text>The Lada I bought</text>
	</string>


	<string id="car_task_zapor_tx">
		<text>Bought a Zaporozhets</text>
	</string>




	<string id="from_dc_to_swamp">
		<text>To the Swamps</text>
	</string>




	<string id="zaebalsukableat">
		<text>Hello! We've got a little problem with an expedition that went missing in the Silent Hills. The signal with them was lost in the area around the base. Could you check that place out?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="vhem_delo_ska">
		<text>Hello, what's the problem?</text>
	</string>



	<string id="def_trade_1_1">
		<text>You want to trade?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="def_trade_1_2">
		<text>Yes.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="def_trade_1_3">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="def_save_me_1_1">
		<text>I need help!</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="def_save_me_1_2">
		<text>Yes.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="def_save_me_1_3">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="def_out_you_1_1">
		<text>Get out of here!</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="def_out_you_1_2">
		<text>Yeah, okay.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="def_out_you_1_3">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="def_by_1_1">
		<text>So long!</text>
	</string>
	



        <string id="zone_artifact_dezin_desc">
		<text>Transmutation requires the artifact Strong Needles and Double Void.</text>
	</string>


        <string id="name_zone_artifact_dezin">
		<text>Disintegrator</text>
	</string>


        <string id="zone_artifact_af_electra_moonlight_glassbeads_spring_desc">
		<text>Transmutation requires: artifact Knot and Stinging cotton candy.</text>
	</string>



        <string id="name_zone_artifact_af_electra_moonlight">
		<text>Electric ball</text>
	</string>



        <string id="zone_artifact_af_dummy_glassbeads_spring_desc">
		<text>The artifact Radioactive Bolt and Rusty Hair are required for transmutation.</text>
	</string>



        <string id="name_zone_artifact_af_dummy_glassbeads">
		<text>Dead head</text>
	</string>



        <string id="zone_artifact_af_dummy_spring_desc">
		<text>Transmutation requires the Toad's Eye artifact and the Transparent Orb.</text>
	</string>


        <string id="name_zone_artifact_af_dummy_spring">
		<text>Washcloth</text>
	</string>



        <string id="name_zone_artifact_af_soul">
		<text>Black drops</text>
	</string>



        <string id="zone_artifact_af_soul_desc">
		<text>Transmutation requires: artifact Bagel and Zuda.</text>
	</string>



        <string id="recip_0">
		<text>I have an artifact transmuter, I'm interested in recipes for it.</text>
	</string>



        <string id="recip_1">
		<text>Okay, I can sell you the descriptions for the transmutation. The price of the question - 1000 rubles. You'll have the description in your PDA.</text>
	</string>



        <string id="Recepies_olr">
		<text>Transmutation Recipes</text>
	</string>


        <string id="name_rec_ribk">
		<text>A strong gravitational artifact</text>
	</string>


        <string id="recept_ribka">
		<text>Transmutation requires: artifact Weak Gravity and Gravity.</text>
	</string>



        <string id="atifact_merger_desc">
		<text>Experimental artifact crossbreeder. The development of scientists from Lake Yantar, allows you to transform anomalous formations in the presence of certain fusion recipes.</text>
	</string>



        <string id="kanistra_benz_desc">
		<text>A canister of gasoline for refueling cars. The volume is 15 liters.</text>
	</string>

        <string id="kanistra_benz_name">
		<text>Gasoline reserve</text>
	</string>


        <string id="mil_uchenis_za_nami">
		<text>Scientists hostage: Someone's here! Are we behind us? Hey! Stalker! You're from the Professor?!</text>
	</string>




        <string id="doki_dla_ch_opis">
		<text>Clear Sky Leader's Note: The Zone surged and splashed in all directions, increasing the size of the affected land at breakneck speed, and the cities caught in the waves of the Emission were dying out, while the territory of the Zone kept growing, expanding in all directions. Across the Earth, people look in horror at the blackened sky, and footage from orbit shows a monstrous black blot that is expanding to swallow up the earth. When things quieted down, more than 100 square kilometers became a scary zone. The ground, vegetation, and buildings were covered in black dust. Tons of radioactive dust rose into the air, which was blown by hurricane-force winds over vast areas, contaminating clean bodies of water and fertile land...</text>
	</string>

        <string id="doki_dla_ch_name">
		<text>Unknown document</text>
	</string>



        <string id="femalehidden">
		<text>Zx34-ioAndr</text>
	</string>


        <string id="qulon_name_desc">
		<text>Silver pendant. The Elder gave it to me as a reward for my help.</text>
	</string>



        <string id="qulon_name">
		<text>Silver pendant</text>
	</string>


        <string id="dnevnik_strelka_name">
		<text>Strelok's diary</text>
	</string>


        <string id="dnevnik_strelka_opis">
		<text>Diary of a legendary stalker nicknamed Strelok. Judging by the appearance of the diary and the entries, the owner of the diary has been keeping it for a very long time. There are records of attempts to break through to the center of the Zone, some diagrams, maps, notes.
Footage of a hike to the center of the Zone:
Recording #1. 
So the road is scouted, the plan is made, the supplies are gathered, the barrels are cleaned to a shine. Thanks to the Doctor for helping with medicine and provisions, which we've been short on lately. Hopefully all of this isn't in vain and we find a clue as to what's going on there. It is said that man has it in him that everything that is unknown to him makes him both curious and afraid at the same time. But I feel something else, a third something, like. the call.\nThe main thing is not to forget the main code - 667. That's the most important thing...</text>
	</string>





        <string id="jabin_holodilnik_desc">
		<text>A container of medical supplies for the Doctor. Pretty heavy.</text>
	</string>




        <string id="jabin_holodilnik_name">
		<text>A container for the Doctor</text>
	</string>




        <string id="na_bolotah_toze_izluchenie">
		<text>This is the Professor from Lake Yantar speaking. In case you haven't heard, the edge of the swamp is under the influence of strong psi radiation. Our workers were doing tests here and what happened to them we do not know. The door of the house where the switch is located is coded as we know, the code is in the possession of another swamp mobile group that left the area due to the Phantasm's psi-influence. Maybe they'll come back and you can find out the code...</text>
	</string>




        <string id="rostok_hm_kodovaya_dver">
		<text>Code door... Code...</text>
	</string>






        <string id="rostok_znakomoe_mesto">
		<text>The place seems familiar...</text>
	</string>


        <string id="st_boloto_sos_greh_lider">
		<text>Message: Sin Leader: hmm, there he is... You didn't get far. Finish him, stalker. He's already dead!</text>
	</string>


        <string id="st_boloto_sos">
		<text>SOS: Somebody help! I'm in the house, in the swamp...</text>
	</string>




        <string id="zenado_0">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>

        <string id="zenado_1">
		<text>What do you want?! Get outta here!</text>
	</string>




        <string id="olr_zablikov_doki_name">
		<text>Order #3467</text>
	</string>


        <string id="olr_zablikov_doki_opis">
		<text>Heads of administration of Rostok plant, Nikolaev Oh.D.
Order
I.I. Zyablikov, an employee of the product delivery department, was transferred from the product delivery department to the research laboratory No.6 due to production needs.
Date: 10.02.2005
Signed: Nikolaev Oh.D.
</text>
	</string>



        <string id="looks_like_arhiv_rostok">
		<text>Looks like the plant's human resources department. Or some kind of archive...</text>
	</string>


        <string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-zara">
		<text>Serves as a psychophysical influence, through distracting and overwhelming light and sound effects. Used in hostage rescue and crowd control operations.</text>
	</string>


        <string id="grenade-zara">
		<text>Zarya-2</text>
	</string>



        <string id="grav_shot_wpn_desc_ammo_posi">
		<text>Bolt box</text>
	</string>



        <string id="grav_shot_wpn_desc_ammo">
		<text>A regular set of 5x25mm bolts. Might come in handy in the household.</text>
	</string>




        <string id="grav_shot_wpn_desc">
		<text>Gravity Shotgun</text>
	</string>



        <string id="grav_shot_wpn">
		<text>An anomalous weapon that harnesses the energy of gravitational artifacts. Can be charged with a wide variety of metal junk not exceeding certain dimensions.</text>
	</string>




        <string id="enc_equipment_devic_device_pda_jan_one">
		<text>Secret
To the head of the Psi-Barrier project. Prof. Chubko V.M. From the head of the laboratory K.T.S. Prikhodko P.S.
"ZX-16 unit test report on prohibitive modes."
The tests were conducted under conditions of forced underestimation by a factor of 2 of the emergency shutdown barrier due to thermal overheating. The ZX-16 unit was activated in its normal psi-field mode, Perimeter Defense. The tests performed showed the appearance of uncontrollable peak-like bursts of psi radiation and induced fields after 5-6 minutes of continuous operation. The strength of the psi-field reached values 50-60 percent higher than the design parameters of the installation. In absolute values, the values are 170-190 psiA. The obtained values are not explained by Kasyanov's theory of induced psi-fields, since the result of psi-field lowering at the moment of transmitter overheating was assumed. Part of the staff believes that the increase in the temperature of the transmitter due to overheating leads to an increase in the parameters of neural activity of the biomass of the pseudo-brain "Ya-1M" and the brain becomes a kind of a repeater of psi radiation, not only a source of psi waves pumping the transmitter. But this claim requires a serious experimental test, for which the team lacks the resources. Others claim that after the experiments they go crazy and don't think much at all. This is indeed a problem - some of the staff will have to be parted with soon. Biomaterials exposed to psi-fields during the experiment unfortunately became unusable due to irreversible changes in the activity of the brain and central nervous system. CT scan and encephalogram data are attached in a separate report. In spite of unexpected and unpredictable results of the experiment on the ZX-16 installation, in general they are very interesting, because they give the right to assert that the use of psi emitter together with pseudo-brain "Ya-1M" can give in the end a more reliable result of the "Psi-barrier" system than similar results of our competitors from the laboratory.
12.12.2007 Prikhodko P.S.
P.S. To continue the research we need a new batch of biomaterials, in the amount of: 10 animal specimens and 10 human specimens from 1296- bis. Please also send additional guards, as it is becoming problematic to hold the prisoners after the psi effect. After the last experiment, some of them managed to escape. During the pursuit, the guards managed to eliminate some of them. The rest were driven into a high radiation area and the pursuit was terminated.

To the head of the laboratory Prikhodko P.S.
Pavel Stepanovich, in my opinion, after the experiments not only some of the employees, but also you personally are not in order with your head. Fucking experimenter!!! Who gave permission to run the brain-emitter complex under uncalculated conditions!!!? Didn't your grandfather work at Chernobyl Unit 4 in 1986? But if in 86 the staff fell under the impulse of the "Russian Woodpecker" (there is at least some explanation for stupid experiments there), I can find no explanation for your behavior! The manual says in black and white "it is strictly forbidden to increase the psi power above 120 psiA." Did you forget about this? Damn it! As a result, you lost control of the biomaterial and moreover let it escape. Do you realize how hard it is for me to get prisoners for my experiments? Do you realize the danger if ANYONE gets wind of our experiments? I hope you understand. So please, in the future, don't do anything like this without notifying me personally. I understand a young scientist's desire to outrun his competitors, but keep your head up. Speaking of competitors. The lab at their facility yesterday got the psi emitters running steadily with only TWO cooling shutdowns per day. 8-30 to 9-45 in the morning and 20-12 to 21-00 in the evening. Therefore, the comparison with your mode (5 min. work -3 min. rest) is clearly not in favor of the installation of your laboratory. The Psi Barrier should work reliably and without any holes in time. However, I don't want to upset you, I also think that the complex "pseudo-brain - psi emitter" is more progressive, intelligent, and the future is behind it. But. A protective barrier is needed now, so at first it is most likely to use the fully man-made version of your colleagues. Yeah, it works like a sledgehammer - bang and no brains. But, as they say, "without noise and dust", cheap and surly. (just kidding).
Please pass on my congratulations to the lab staff on a Happy New Year and Merry Christmas.
Prof. Chubko V.M. 20.12.2007
P.S. I will make arrangements for the supply of biomaterials shortly.</text>
	</string>





     <string id="enc_equipment_devic_device_pda_jan_two">
		<text>Laboratory Order.
In connection with the catastrophic processes that began on April 12 of this year in the center of the Exclusion Zone around the Chernobyl NPP, I order: 1.	Laboratory staff to copy lab reports and assemble 4 sets of documents. Destroy the original classified documents. 2.	Security to dispose of all biomaterials. 3.	Perform preservation of the laboratory. 4.	Prepare to load the experimental program "Shroud of Darkness" into the pseudo-brain "Ya-1M", as well as the activation of all external tracking sensors. 5.	Activate wind turbines and backup power sources. Switch the laboratory to an energy-saving mode. 6.	Make your way to the main lab in the Z17-45 area in groups of 3. Each group carries 1 set of documents. One guard is assigned to each group. Everybody wear protective gear. 7.	Good luck, everyone.
Laboratory Manager
Candidate of Technical Sciences Prikhodko P.S.</text>
	</string>



        <string id="enc_equipment_devic_device_pda_jan_tri">
		<text>Posthumous note
I, Prikhodko Pavel Stepanovich, head of the laboratory, born in 1976, being in my right mind, voluntarily pass away today April 26, 2008. Now I just want to explain the reasons why. I hope someone finds this note and passes it on to my loved ones and colleagues to whom I remained loyal to the end. Two weeks ago, I signed a mothballing order for our lab. After the events of April 12, the laboratory could no longer operate normally. Communication with the center was lost. Having reproduced the lab results materials I sent four groups of my staff to the main lab. Some of them will make it, I believe. And the invaluable results of our work will not go to waste. And will benefit our GREAT cause. Next. Left alone, I loaded into our brainchild - pseudo-brain "Ya1-M" developed by us program "Shroud of Darkness", which was supposed to make our psi-defense complex ZX-16 to inspire any thinking creature within 200 meters, the absolute invisibility of our laboratory, as well as on a subconscious level to inspire unwillingness of anyone to approach it... Anyway, I'll be brief. I don't know why. But it wasn't the program that worked. When I tried to leave the psi-protected room with the "brain" I received a crushing psi order to defend the facility and kill all uninvited guests. When I woke up, I found myself back in the psi shelter. I don't remember how I got back. Over the past 2 weeks that I've spent in this room - I've asked myself thousands of times, how could a program we just started developing work? The answer scares me. Perhaps the most fantastic hypothesis of my colleagues about the possibility of self-learning in Ya-1M worked. If so, that monster is probably grinning slyly at me right now. I tried to smash his hull, but to no avail. My PM can't do anything about that armored glass. And all the machine guns were taken away by our guards. The only way to shut down the complex now is from the backup control panel. I trapped myself. We ran out of water and provisions a week ago. If I leave the room - the psi radiation will destroy me as a person, and my remaining short days will be spent living the life of plants. I don't want to do that. So I kept the last bullet in my gun.
Good luck to all...don't mention it. Paul.
April 26, 2008. 13-40</text>
	</string>










        <string id="enc_equipment_pribor_zamery_zameryany">
		<text>An anomalous field map device.</text>
	</string>


        <string id="pribor_zamery">
		<text>Measuring device</text>
	</string>



        <string id="enc_equipment_pribor_zamery">
		<text>A device that measures anomalous activity. To measure, you must approach the anomalous area, hold the device in your hands, and activate the device.</text>
	</string>




        <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ghsa">
		<text>The GSh-18 is a Russian pistol developed in the late 1990s at the Tula Instrument Design Bureau. It was named after the first letters of the surnames of the designers under whose supervision it was designed (Vasily Gryazev and Arkady Shipunov) and the number "18", meaning the capacity of the magazine.\nAmmunition:\nbasic 9x19mm Parabellum,\nenhanced 9x19mm PBP.</text>
	</string>


        <string id="dead_crow_food">
		<text>Dead crow</text>
	</string>

        <string id="enc_crow_food">
		<text>Crow carcass. Quite edible, but quite highly radioactive. You can cook it over a campfire.</text>
	</string>


        <string id="deads">
		<text>Dead people</text>
	</string>


        <string id="laba_opis">
		<text>The files from the abandoned lab. They mention the experiments being conducted in the complex. Particularly over the Burers. There are monthly reports of scientific department work, lists of all researchers, project budgets, and instructions for standard procedures. There is also talk of transferring the results of experiments to another complex. According to the coordinates, it's located somewhere on Yantar.</text>
	</string>


        <string id="osveschenie_doma">
		<text>Digital lighting control. Control codes: 1 - on, 2 - off.</text>
	</string>


        <string id="tip_pnut_door">
		<text>Blocked. You can try to knock it out.</text>
	</string>


        <string id="det_art_super">
		<text>SUPER artifact detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="det_art_super_info">
		<text>SUPER Series Artifact Detector. This detector is the latest development of local scientists. Thanks to nanotechnology, the sensitivity of the detector has been increased to 1.5 kilometers. The presence of artifacts is indicated by markers on the terrain map. In addition to their locations, the detector recognizes artifact types, making it the best of all the detector series.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="det_art_pro">
		<text>Artifact Detector PRO</text>
	</string>
	<string id="det_art_pro_info">
		<text>PRO Series Artifact Detector. This is an improved version of the INDY artifact detector, having been upgraded by local scientists. Added a terrain map with marker output on its surface. The range has been increased to 70 meters. Due to its reasonable price and improved performance, its use is considered to be the most preferred.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="det_art_indy">
		<text>INDY artifact detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="det_art_indy_info">
		<text>INDY Series Artifact Detector. This is the first artifact detector developed by local artisans. The device is ineffective because its range does not exceed 40 meters, and the presence of an artifact is recognized only by an audible signal. But in its time, more than one and a half thousand artifacts have been found with this device.</text>
	</string>




	<string id="st_dead_comm">
		<text>Faction:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_death_loc">
		<text>Location:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_death_msg">
		<text>Name:</text>
	</string>


<string id="lelnl_spam_sms">
	<text>Hey, kid! Come here, I have something to do!</text>
</string>




<string id="enc_device_torch_bad">
	<text>Non-working flashlight. I think the batteries are dead.</text>
</string>

<string id="device_torch_bad">
	<text>Non-working flashlight</text>
</string>



<string id="off_ust">
	<text>Disconnect power to the PSI unit.</text>
</string>

<string id="off_cheno">
	<text>Power to the PSI unit is turned off.</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-pda2_ucheny">
	<text>The data has been corrupted. Last entry: Damn, I think my leg is broken, ah... Apparently it's holed up in the basement, creating a psi blockade... There's no way down! Unless we can get to the psionic control panel and try to lock it down. Shit... The door code is 8620. Good thing the Professor told me, just in case!</text>
</string>


<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-pda1_ucheny">
	<text>The basic data is encrypted, but there is information about the lab. A group of scientists from Lake Yantar moved out to search for equipment. Personal note: as we know the staff left the lab disorganized and chaotic, a lot of very interesting and useful research equipment, ranging from simple dosimeters and dynamometers to experimental weapons and equipment remained there. We'll probably find technical documentation, reports, maybe personal diaries of specialists. All of this should give at least a little insight into what was going on there. Who knows, maybe the information found there will help us bring about another scientific and technological revolution? You should look for documents on the first and second levels of the complex, and equipment in the storage rooms. Note from the Professor: Be extremely vigilant and cautious as test specimens number 1 and 2, as well as the Alpha psionic specimen have disappeared. Maybe they're still in the lab.</text>
</string>



<string id="art_box_special">
	<text>Artifact container (R2)</text>
</string>
<string id="art_box_special_s">
	<text>Artifact container (R2)</text>
</string>
 <string id="art_box_1special">
	<text>Capsule (R1)</text>
</string>
<string id="art_box_1special_s">
	<text>Capsule (R1)</text>
</string>
 <string id="art_box_8special">
	<text>Artifact container (R3)</text>
</string>
<string id="art_box_8special_s">
	<text>Artifact container (R3)</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arc_art_box_basic">
	<text>A medium-sized scientific artifact container. Designed for hand carrying medium hazard artifacts. Despite the small size, quite provides the necessary protection from the average anomalous and radioactive radiation. It is made of special heavy-duty plastic, coated on top with a layer of the latest metal alloy obtained in a laboratory at Lake Yantar. Highly sought after by professional artifact miners.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arc_art_box_8basic">
	<text>A scientific container for artifacts. Designed to carry radioactive artifacts by hand. Despite the small size, quite provides the necessary protection against weak radioactive radiation. It is made of special heavy-duty plastic, coated on top with a layer of the latest metal alloy obtained in a laboratory at Lake Yantar. Highly sought after by professional artifact miners.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arc_art_1box_basic">
	<text>A special scientific container for artifacts. Designed for hand carrying particularly dangerous or highly radioactive artifacts. Despite the small size, quite provides the necessary protection against anomalous and radioactive radiation. It is made of special heavy-duty plastic, coated on top with a layer of the latest metal alloy obtained in a laboratory at Lake Yantar. The manufacturing process is kept secret, but it is known that hard radiation of any intensity is almost completely shielded by the walls of the container. Highly sought after by professional artifact miners.</text>
</string>
 <string id="enc_arc_art_box_basic_1">
	<text>A special scientific container for artifacts. This container contains one artifact.</text>
</string>
 <string id="enc_arc_art_box_basic_2">
	<text>A special scientific container for artifacts. This container contains two artifacts.</text>
</string>
 <string id="enc_arc_art_box_basic_3">
	<text>A special scientific container for artifacts. This container contains three artifacts.</text>
</string>
 <string id="enc_arc_art_box_basic_4">
	<text>A special scientific container for artifacts. This container contains four artifacts.</text>
</string>
 <string id="enc_arc_art_box_basic_5">
	<text>A special scientific container for artifacts. This container contains five artifacts.</text>
</string>
 <string id="enc_arc_art_box_basic_6">
	<text>A special scientific container for artifacts. This container contains six artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arc_art_box_basic_7">
	<text>A special scientific container for artifacts. This container contains seven artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arc_art_box_basic_8">
	<text>A special scientific container for artifacts. This container contains eight artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arc_art_box_basic_9">
	<text>A special scientific container for artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arc_art_box_basic_10">
	<text>A special scientific container for artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arc_art_box_basic_11">
	<text>A special scientific container for artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arc_art_box_basic_12">
	<text>A special scientific container for artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arc_art_box_basic_13">
	<text>A special scientific container for artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arc_art_box_basic_14">
	<text>A special scientific container for artifacts.</text>
</string>





	<string id="dolg_base_marker">
		<text>Base Duty</text>
	</string>  


<string id="enc_dead_rat">
		<text>Dead rat. Can be consumed. You can cook it over a campfire.</text>
	</string>

<string id="dead_rat">
		<text>Rat</text>
	</string>

<string id="dead_rat_s">
		<text>Rat</text>
	</string>

<string id="tre_ruck_s">
		<text>Backpack</text>
	</string>

<string id="tre_ruck">
		<text>Backpack</text>
	</string>


<string id="enc_tre_ruck">
		<text>The backpack from the stalker suit. You can make your own stash in a secluded place.</text>
	</string>

<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-rpk74">
		<text>The Kalashnikov 5.45-mm handgun (RPK-74, GRAU Index - 6P18) is a handgun designed to replace the 7.62 mm RPK machine gun in the army as part of the small arms system for the 5.45 mm low-pulse cartridge. Adopted into service in 1974 together with the AK74 assault rifle.</text>
	</string>


<string id="container_spam_sms">
		<text>Get outta here, stalker!</text>
	</string>


<string id="wpn-striker">
		<text>Protecta</text>
	</string>

<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-striker">
		<text>Protecta is a 12-gauge (about 18.5 mm) smoothbore combat shotgun built on a revolver design (formerly known as Striker). It is used in big game hunting. Compact and convenient.\nAmmunition:\n12x70 buckshot,\n12x76 javelin,\n12x76 dart.</text>
	</string>

<string id="dolg_spam_sms_garbage">
		<text>Stalker, this is Duty's outpost! If you're going to go to the Bar area, you can go through.</text>
	</string>



<string id="enc_equipment_4r34devic_device-pda1">
		<text>Oh, you stalker! You know, the journalist was kind too, helping me. So about him. One time I was at his place, he told me a story. Anyway, behind the power plant there are some installations that caused that big Emission that hit me back then. And that he's scouting the local neighborhood for documents. Said he wanted to find out what happened in the Zone.</text>
	</string>

<string id="enc_eq234uipment_devic_device-pda1">
		<text>That's it, you don't know anything else?</text>
	</string>

<string id="enc_equipment_devic_de444vice-pda1">
		<text>No, that's all I remember about him... Thank you for your help, I think you'll find what you're looking for...</text>
	</string>


<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-pda1">
		<text>Personal computer for data storage.</text>
	</string>


<string id="mg_zobmie_hello">
		<text>Hey, stalker, come here! I'm in the house on the hill.</text>
	</string>


<string id="dolg_spam_sms">
		<text>Stalker, you are in the territory of the Duty faction. Don't you dare shoot here!</text>
	</string>

<string id="jaba_hello_sms">
		<text>Messer, I'm up in the hills. Come into my bunker. Toad.</text>
	</string>

<string id="warfare">
		<text>We're thinking of doing a raid on Silent Hills. Those darkies are obviously up to something, so we need to do a little recon. The village to the west of the Hills is suitable for camouflage. The problem is, there's a controller freak in there. It must be destroyed.</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl16_generators_level_changer">
		<text>To the lab</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl14_stancia_level_changer_0001">
		<text>To Generators</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl14_stancia_level_changer_0001">
		<text>To Generators</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl14_stancia_level_changer_0000">
		<text>To the Sarcophagus</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl14_stancia_level_changer">
		<text>To Pripyat</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl13_prip_level_changer_0000">
		<text>To Chernobyl</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl13_prip_level_changer">
		<text>To Radar</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl11_deadcity_level_changer_0000">
		<text>To the Swamps</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl11_deadcity_level_changer">
		<text>To Lake Yantar</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl11_deadcity_level_changer_0001">
		<text>To the Silent Hills</text>
	</string>


<string id="lvl10_radar_level_changer">
		<text>To the Silent Hills</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl10_radar_level_changer_0000">
		<text>To the lab</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl10_radar_level_changer_0001">
		<text>To Pripyat</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl9_military_level_changer">
		<text>To Radar</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl9_military_level_changer_0000">
		<text>To the Shining Path</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl10_military_level_changer">
		<text>To the Stalker Bar</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl8_swamp_level_changer">
		<text>To Lake Yantar</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl8_swamp_level_changer_0000">
		<text>To the Shining Path</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl7_yantar_level_changer_0002">
		<text>To the Shining Path</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl7_yantar_level_changer">
		<text>To the Stalker Bar</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl7_yantar_level_changer_0000">
		<text>To MedPribor Research Institute</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl7_yantar_level_changer_0001">
		<text>To the Swamps</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl5_bar_level_changer_0001">
		<text>To the Silent Hills</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl5_bar_level_changer_0002">
		<text>To the Rostok plant</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl5_bar_level_changer">
		<text>To the Rostok plant</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl5_bar_level_changer_0000">
		<text>To Lake Yantar</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl6_rostok_level_changer">
		<text>To the Stalker Bar</text>
	</string>




<string id="level_prefix_level_changer">
		<text>To the Garbage</text>
	</string>

<string id="level_prefix_level_changer_glue">
		<text>To Chernobyl</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl4_darkdolina_level_changer">
		<text>To the lab</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl4_darkdolina_level_changer_0001">
		<text>To the Garbage</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl4_darkdolina_level_changer_0000">
		<text>To the Garbage</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl3_agroprom_level_changer_0001">
		<text>To Yantar</text>
	</string>


<string id="lvl3_agroprom_level_changer">
		<text>To the Garbage</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl3_agroprom_level_changer_0000">
		<text>To the Garbage</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl2_garbage_level_changer_0001">
		<text>To the Dark Valley</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl2_garbage_level_changer_0004">
		<text>To the Dark Valley</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl2_garbage_level_changer_0003">
		<text>To the Stalker Bar</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl2_garbage_level_changer_0000">
		<text>To MedPribor Research Institute</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl2_garbage_level_changer_0002">
		<text>To MedPribor Research Institute</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl2_garbage_level_changer">
		<text>To the Cordon</text>
	</string>

<string id="lvl1_escape_level_changer">
		<text>To the Garbage</text>
	</string>

<string id="esc_kv_atr_1">
		<text>We need to pick up Toad's box.</text>
	</string>

<string id="neutral">
		<text>Stalker</text>
	</string>


	<string id="caes_barman">
		<text>Stalker, it's Toad. I can't believe you're there at the power plant. If you do decide to sneak inside to the Monolith, listen... The entrance to the reactor is behind the plant, on the north side. Double gates. I hope you know what you're doing...</text>
	</string>


	<string id="chaes_barman">
		<text>Stalker, it's Toad. I can't believe you're there at the power plant. If you do decide to sneak inside to the Monolith, listen up. The entrance is behind the power plant, on the north side. Double gates. I hope you know what you're doing!</text>
	</string>



	<string id="barman_kogo_tam">
		<text>Who the hell is out there?</text>
	</string>


       <string id="final_olr_0">
		<text>Hello, Messer!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_olr_1">
		<text>What? Who are you?</text>
 
	</string>
	<string id="final_olr_2">
		<text>Quiet, quiet, it's all behind us now...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_olr_3">
		<text>What?!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="sliznyaki">
		<text>Black Slugs</text>
	</string>

	<string id="lastday">
		<text>Last Day</text>
	</string>

	<string id="iskateli">
		<text>Scientific Group</text>
	</string>


	<string id="sin">
		<text>Sin</text>
	</string>

	<string id="hui_pizda">
		<text>You mean the scientist from Yantar? Yeah, he lived here. He went missing under unclear circumstances, recently. Our guys wanted to check out the apartment, but the door was jammed. One of our guys tried a few times on the wires from the neighbor's house, but he kept falling off. Doesn't want to anymore... And it looks like the window's boarded up. I think we're gonna have to break the door down. Or blow things up.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="aaj_golova">
		<text>Hey, stalker!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gen_find_exit_lab_d_name">
		<text>Find the entrance to the Lab.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gen_find_exit_lab_d_text">
		<text>Somewhere in the Generators' territory is the main laboratory. We need to find the entrance to this lab.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="off_dyatel1">
		<text>Shut down the Woodpecker-1 unit.</text> 
	</string>

        <string id="off_dyatel_otkl">
		<text>The Woodpecker-1 unit is offline.</text> 
	</string>


        <string id="off_yan">
		<text>Disable the installation.</text>  
	</string>

        <string id="off_yan1">
		<text>The installation is disabled.</text> 
	</string>


        <string id="yan_sah_spam">
		<text>Messer! Indications are that you are very close to the installation!</text> 
	</string>




        <string id="sin_hello_sms">
		<text>Unknown Stalker: This area is closed to solo stalkers. But if you're here on business, come to our base.</text> 
	</string>



	<string id="actor">
		<text>Loners</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_dolg">
		<text>Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_freedom">
		<text>Freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arena_enemy">
		<text>Opponent</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bad">
		<text>badly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit">
		<text>Bandit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bio">
		<text>Biographies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg">
		<text>Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog">
		<text>Ecologist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stranger">
		<text>Unknown</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enemy">
		<text>enemy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="excellent">
		<text>perfectly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_name_m1">
		<text>Exoskeleton PNB-4UZ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="experienced">
		<text>experienced</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Found_PDA">
		<text>Electronic media</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom">
		<text>Freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="friendly">
		<text>friend</text>
	</string>
	<string id="good">
		<text>well</text>
	</string>
	<string id="indifferent">
		<text>neutral</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer">
		<text>Killer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl1_escape">
		<text>Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl2_garbage">
		<text>Garbage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl3_agroprom">
		<text>MedPribor Research Institute</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl4_darkdolina">
		<text>Dark Valley</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl5_bar">
		<text>Stalker Bar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl6_rostok">
		<text>Rostok Plant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl9_military">
		<text>Silent Hills</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl7_yantar">
		<text>Lake Yantar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl11_deadcity">
		<text>Shining Path</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl10_radar">
		<text>Radar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl12_radar_bunker">
		<text>Lab 9</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl13_prip">
		<text>Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl14_stancia">
		<text>CHERNOBYL NPP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl8_swamp">
		<text>Swamps</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl16_generators">
		<text>Generators</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl17_warlab">
		<text>Military laboratory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="master">
		<text>master</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military">
		<text>Military</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith">
		<text>Monolith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="neutral">
		<text>neutral</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadbody">
		<text>corpse</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novice">
		<text>rookie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_no_active_task">
		<text>No active task</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_time_till_surge">
		<text>Emission Timer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker">
		<text>Loners</text>
	</string>
	<string id="terrible">
		<text>terribly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader">
		<text>Merchant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_community">
		<text>group</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_price">
		<text>Price</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_rank">
		<text>rank</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_relation">
		<text>attitude</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_reputation">
		<text>reputation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="very_bad">
		<text>very badly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="very_good">
		<text>very good</text>
	</string>
	<string id="veteran">
		<text>veteran</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zombied">
		<text>zombies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Btn_Cancel">
		<text>Cancel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Btn_No">
		<text>No</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Btn_OK">
		<text>OK</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Btn_Yes">
		<text>Yes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="global_map">
		<text>Map of the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_autosave">
		<text>Autosave...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_game_over">
		<text>Game over.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_item_used">
		<text>Used</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_not_enough_money">
		<text>Not enough money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_not_enough_money_npc">
		<text>The NTC doesn't have enough money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_opponent_items">
		<text>Backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_search_treasure">
		<text>Search($$ACTION_USE$$).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="inventory_item_use">
		<text>Pick up an item ($$ACTION_USE$$)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_mm_check_updates">
		<text>Updates</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_mm_alternative">
		<text>Alternative</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_health">
		<text>Health</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_radiation">
		<text>Radiation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_satiety">
		<text>Hunger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_power">
		<text>Energy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_bleeding">
		<text>Bleeding</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detail_list_for_foo">
		<text>Detailed list of statistics</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_knife">
		<text>Knife</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mp_disabled_voting">
		<text>Voting is not available on this server.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mp_no_current_voting">
		<text>There are no active votes right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mp_ready">
		<text>ready</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl4u_darklab">
		<text>No data</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl12_radar_bunker">
		<text>Radar bunker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lvl15_sarcofag">
		<text>Sarcophagus</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anomaly_zone">
		<text>Anomalous area</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radioactive_zone">
		<text>Radioactive zone</text>
	</string>
        <string id="sky">
		<text>Clear Sky</text>
	</string>

<string id="Antirad">
		<text>Anti-radiation drugs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Arm-heavy">
		<text>Heavy stalker gear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Arm-light">
		<text>Light stalker gear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Arm-medium">
		<text>Average stalker gear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandage">
		<text>Bandage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Binocul">
		<text>Binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bread">
		<text>Bread</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killers_documents_desc">
		<text>A polyethylene file of documents.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Conserva">
		<text>Conserve</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Detect1">
		<text>Anomaly detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Devic">
		<text>Instruments and devices</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device-PDA">
		<text>PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device-torch">
		<text>Flashlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-heavy">
		<text>A hazmat suit. Weight - 18 kg. Features: protects the body from Blizzard, Stinging Fluff, most anomalousities and mechanical damage. The chest and back are protected by integrated biometallic plates. Equipped with a sealed metal-plastic helmet and two oxygen tanks. Warning: with prolonged use it becomes unusable - damaged and torn.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-light">
		<text>A hazmat suit. Weight - 8 kg. Features: protects the body from the effects of weak anomalies and mechanical damage. Equipped with an oxygen mask. Warning: with prolonged use it becomes unusable - damaged and torn.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-medium">
		<text>A hazmat suit. Weight - 12 kg. Features: protects the body from Stun, Stinging Fluff, many anomalousities and mechanical damage. Equipped with a pressurized helmet and oxygen tank. Warning: with prolonged use it becomes unusable - damaged and torn.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_sci2">
		<text>Orange colored protective spacesuit with a sealed helmet. Weight - 11 kg. Features: protects the body from fire, acids, gases, exposure to a variety of anomalies, Stinging Fluff and mechanical damage. Equipped with two oxygen tanks. Warning: with prolonged use it becomes unusable - damaged and torn.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_binocul1">
		<text>Army portable binoculars.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect1">
		<text>The device, which detects anomalous fields and disturbances, emits clicks and turns on a red light when a positive reaction occurs.\n- does not detect all anomalies\n- works unstably, there are failures\n- if you have this device, you can scan items in your backpack for radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect2">
		<text>Anomaly Detector (DA-2).\nA device that detects the presence of anomalous fields and disturbances. It beeps when detected. To operate, you must activate by placing the device on your belt.\nNumber of zones to be defined - 3.\nDetection radius 10 m.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect3">
		<text>Universal anomaly detector (UDA-14a).\nA device that detects the presence of anomalous fields and disturbances, as well as centers of radioactive contamination. When detected, it beeps and marks the anomaly on the screen. To operate, you must activate by placing the device on your belt.\nThe number of zones to be defined is 4.\nDetection radius 15 m.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-PDA1">
		<text>A pocket personal computer is an indispensable device in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch1">
		<text>A flashlight with a fairly powerful bulb. Quite useful in low-light conditions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch1_m1">
		<text>A flashlight with a fairly powerful bulb. Thanks to the improved transformer, the battery charging time is reduced.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_energydrink">
		<text>Medical capsules. A dosage form of medication to treat minor wounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_bread1">
		<text>A regular soft wheat loaf. Apparently brought into the zone from the Big Land.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_conserva1">
		<text>Canned meat. Probably from a stalker-run army food depot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_kolbasa1">
		<text>Regular sausage. The composition is unknown, but it seems to be edible.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_vodka1">
		<text>Vodka. It is good to drink and noticeably reduces the effects of radiation, but should not be abused.\nLoss of coordination.\nSlightly relieves the effects of radiation sickness.\nQuenches thirst</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_antirad1">
		<text>Anti-radiation drugs reduce the effects of radiation on the body.\nThere are minor side effects with use.\nPossible loss of coordination.\nA little treatment for radiation sickness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_bandage1">
		<text>Dressing material. Helps stop the bleeding.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit1">
		<text>Universal Medical Kit. Allows you to treat injuries of varying degrees of complexity (wounds, burns, poisoning, etc.).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit2">
		<text>A specialized medical kit for dealing with physical injuries and bleeding. It includes components to speed up blood clotting, painkillers, antibiotics and immune stimulants - Anti-rad 1pc, Medical Capsule 1pc, Bandage 1pc.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit3">
		<text>A medical kit designed specifically for working in the Zone. The composition of the kit is selected both to combat wounds and to eliminate radionuclides from the body. Prevents the development of radiation sickness and also reduces the dose of accumulated radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="energy_drink_name">
		<text>Medical capsules</text>
	</string>
	<string id="energy_drink_short_name">
		<text>Medical capsules</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Equipment">
		<text>Equipment and food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Food">
		<text>Foodstuffs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Kolbasa">
		<text>Sausage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Medi">
		<text>Medicines</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Medkit">
		<text>Medical kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Medkit_army">
		<text>Medical kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Medkit_scientific">
		<text>Medical kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Sci2">
		<text>Scientific EXP-4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Vodka">
		<text>Vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector">
		<text>Anomaly detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector2">
		<text>Anomaly Detector (DA-2)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector3">
		<text>Universal anomaly detector (UDA-14a)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector_descr">
		<text>Designed to detect anomalous zones, as well as centers of radioactive contamination.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_gd5">
		<text>Smoke grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="guitar">
		<text>Guitar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_item_guitar">
		<text>A regular six-string guitar. Stalkers like to belt out a tune while sitting around a campfire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="harmonica">
		<text>harmonica</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_item_harmonica">
		<text>A regular harmonica. The simplest musical instrument in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Dimanit">
		<text>Dynamite</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_all_item_explosion">
		<text>Explosive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hand_radio">
		<text>Walkie-talkie</text>
	</string>


	<string id="enc_weapons1_hand_torch_super">
		<text>Handheld flashlight with increased brightness and illumination range.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-gauss_sgs">
		<text>A super-precision weapon that the designers in the Zone put together. Artifact energy is used for firing. Despite the enormous power of the shot, the recoil of the Gauss gun is very low. The first version of the Gauss gun in the zone.\nAmmunition - energy containers with ready-to-use killstreaks in the magazine for the gauss-gsg5 rifle.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo_plasma">
		<text>Energy containers with ready-made killstreaks in the magazine for the gauss-gsg5 rifle.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-tiss">
		<text>The OC-12 Tiss is a Russian assault rifle developed by the Tula Central Design Bureau of Sporting and Hunting Weapons (TsKIB SOO) based on the AKS74U. The key difference is the use of special subsonic 9x39mm cartridges (SP-5 and SP-6), which entailed changes in the barrel, blowback device, dimensions of the bolt mirror and magazine. The sight and muzzle brake-compensator have also been modified.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-bm16short">
		<text>Weapons of unknown origin. Looks like a regular double-barrelled shotgun.\nAmmunition:\n12x70 shot,\n12x76 javelin,\n12x76 dart.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-sv17">
		<text>An experimental weapon of unknown origin.\nCan be loaded with 2-millimeter gauss ammunition.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="wpn_vsk94_desc">
		<text>The VSK-94 (Voyskoy Sniper Complex) is a Russian sniper rifle based on the small-sized 9A-91 assault rifle developed by the Tula Instrument Design Bureau in 1994 for silent and flameless sniper fire.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-_anom7h14">
		<text>Gravipatron</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-anom">
		<text>A 7.62x54 caliber gravipatron, with elements of the artifact gravi.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="binocular-name">
		<text>Binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-bizon">
		<text>Bison</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-bizon">
		<text>The PP-19 Bison submachine gun was designed in the early 1990s at the Izhevsk Machine Building Plant to arm the Ministry of Internal Affairs with a modern small-size automatic small arms weapon to replace the AKS-74U.\n- 9x18mm, 9x18mm BMP\n- effective range 100m\n- magazine capacity 64 cartridges </text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-m_134">
		<text>M-134</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-m_134">
		<text>Six-barrel machine gun with electrically driven barrel rotation. As a hand weapon, it can only be used with a hydraulic exoskeleton. Inside the Zone, it is extremely rare due to the inconvenience of using it in the field. The army uses to defend the perimeter against swarms of mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_groza_old_desc">
		<text>The complex consists of a 9x39mm assault rifle and a 40mm underbarrel grenade launcher. The automatic system operates by expulsion of powder gases from the barrel channel, locking the barrel by turning the bolt. The rifle is based on bullpup layout, and one of the most significant disadvantages of this layout has been solved - displacement of the center of mass of the weapon and location of the extractor close to Strelok's face, which leads to the fact that the weapon intended for use by right-handed shooters cannot be used by left-handed shooters, because hot fired cartridges fly into their faces. The first drawback was eliminated by the underbarrel grenade launcher, and a special channel was made for the shell casings, through which the casings were carried forward and discharged outside on the right side near the pistol grip. Later, a similar cartridge case pattern was used in the Belgian FN F2000 rifle. The closed receiver also protects the receiver from dirt, which has a positive effect on reliability.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-groza_short">
		<text>Thunderstorm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oka74protoo_podstvol">
		<text>The AG-40 is a grenade launcher used by the PA md. 86. Originally firing a proprietary 40mm round, all AG-40's in the Zone have been rechambered to accept the 40mm VOG-25 round by either Zone gunsmiths or contract gunsmiths working for the Ukrainian military; all of them are converted for the sake of simplifying logistics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oka74protoo">
		<text>The PA md. 86 is the current service rifle of the Romanian Army. Large amounts of them have made their way into Zone, circulated by arms dealers buying them in bulk and selling them to the Ukrainian Army or independent stalkers. Some prefer the PA md. 86 over the AK-74 due to its improved ergonomics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-akm74">
		<text>Kalashnikov assault rifle of 5.45 mm caliber, developed in 1970 by designer M.T. Kalashnikov and adopted by the USSR Armed Forces in 1974. It is a further development of the AKM. The development of the AK-74 is related to the transition to the new low-pulse 5.45 mm cartridge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-igla">
		<text>MANPADS Igla</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-igla_desc">
		<text>The third-generation MANPADS Igla successfully operates in conditions of natural (background) and artificial interference (false thermal targets), to this day remaining one of the best complexes in its class.\n\nUsage:\nTurn on the power supply.\nWithin 5 seconds, the missile is placed on alert - the homing head cools to operating temperature and the target tracking coordinator gyroscope unwinds.\nAim the launcher at the target. When a target appears in the field of view of the GSN, the thermal radiation flux hits the coordinator. If the flow rate is greater than the coordinator's minimum sensitivity, an audible alarm sounds. The target is captured and the launch lock is released.\nWhen a beep is heard, the missile is launched. The power supply remains operational for about 40 seconds after being turned on. If no launch has been made within this time, the missile is unsuitable for further use. Target acquisition is impossible when the angle between the target and the Sun is less than 20 degrees.\n\nAmmunition:\nGuided Missile Needle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-igla">
		<text>UR Needle in the launch tube</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-igla_s">
		<text>SD Needle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-igla_desc">
		<text>Guided missile Igla in the launch tube. The missile is equipped with a dual-channel infra-red sounder, which provides high noise immunity of the missile against natural and artificial thermal interference. The fuze ensures detonation of the warhead both on direct hit and when flying in close proximity to the target. To increase effectiveness, the residual propellant of the missile is detonated along with the warhead. </text>
	</string>

    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74u_anom">
        <text> Rumor has it this barrel was found in a pile of rust in the Garbage. The same place where the gravity anomaly was for three months. I'm surprised the barrel itself isn't rusted through. On the contrary - how many shots have been fired out of it already, and the wear is still not noticeable.\nFeatures: Strongly inferior to the regular Kalashnikov in accuracy and damage, but lighter and more agile.\nThe AKS-74U is similar in size and weight to submachine guns, but due to the cartridge and mechanisms used, it is still considered to be a shortened assault rifle. The advantages of the AKS-74U include high mobility in cramped conditions, the possibility of concealed carry, and a fairly high penetration capacity of the cartridge. Disadvantages - short sighting range, low stopping power of the bullet, tendency to overheat during firing. The magazine capacity is 30 rounds. The base ammunition is 5.45x39 FMJ, 5.45x39 AP armor-piercing round.</text>
    </string>    

    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-gauss_m">
        <text>A sample Gauss rifle with an enlarged magazine.</text>
    </string>

    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-knife_m1">
        <text>The personal knife of a stalker nicknamed Crowbar. The handle is rubbed, however the knife fits perfectly in the hand.</text>
    </string> 

    <string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch1_m2">
        <text>Halogen flashlight. Experimental sample, malfunctions may occur.</text>
    </string> 

    <string id="weapon_addon_scope_m">
        <text>PSO-1 Strelok telescopic sight.</text>
    </string> 

    <string id="weapon_addon_scope_susat_m">
        <text>Diamond scope.</text>
    </string>     

    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-svu_m1">
        <text>Features: by modifying the bolt it was possible to increase the speed of the IED, unfortunately the accuracy suffered.\nThe Dragunov rifle is a more modern version of the Dragunov bullpup rifle, which is very convenient for traveling in the Zone, and is a compact version of the powerful automatic sniper rifle. It's hard to get. Unless you take it from a military stalker in combat. The magazine capacity is 10 rounds. The basic ammunition is 7.62X54 7h1 , the armor-piercing ammunition is 7.62X54 ar, the sniper ammunition with improved characteristics is 7.62X54 7h14.</text>
    </string> 

    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-g36_m">
        <text>Features: The barrel is sprayed with powder derived from a graviartefact.\nThe G36 assault rifle is a first-class example of modern German weaponry - it is lightweight, reliable and easy to handle. The magazine capacity is 30 rounds. The base ammunition is 5.56X45 SS109 , 5.56X45 AR armor-piercing round. The ammunition for the underbarrel is M209 grenades. A veteran's or master's weapon.</text>
    </string>   

    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-vintorez_m1_new">
        <text>A unique piece with improved optics.\nFeatures: Gift inscribed screwcutter. In addition to the lettering, adjustments have been made to improve the accuracy of the gun.\nSniper-Specialty Rifle. Designed for silent and flameless sniper shooting. The rifle has an integrated silencer. A very "respected" gun in the Zone. From 400 meters, it pierces any body armor that a real person can wear without assistance. At the same time, it can be done almost silently. The weapon of the seasoned stalker and veteran. The magazine capacity is 20 rounds. The base ammunition is 9x39 PAB-9, 9x39 AP armor-piercing round, and 9x39 SP5 sniper round.</text>
    </string> 

    <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-beretta_m1">
        <text>Good reliability.\nFeatures: a modified version of the popular pistol. Created in the scientists' bunker specifically for expedition self-defense.\nThe Beretta is in service with the U.S. Armed Forces, many other paramilitary and law enforcement organizations, and police forces, both in the U.S. and in other countries. 9mm caliber. The magazine capacity is 15 rounds. Base ammunition is 9x19 FMJ, performance-enhanced ammunition is 9x19 PBP.</text>
    </string>  

	<string id="Ammo">
		<text>Ammunition</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
		<text>11.43x23 FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_s">
		<text>11.43x23 FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
		<text>11.43x23 hydro</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_s">
		<text>11.43x23 hydro</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-buck">
		<text>12x70 buck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-buck_s">
		<text>12x70 buck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-dart">
		<text>12x76 dart</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-dart_s">
		<text>12x76 dart/S</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan">
		<text>12x76 slug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_s">
		<text>12x76 slug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap">
		<text>5.45x39 AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_s">
		<text>5.45 APS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
		<text>5,45x39 FJM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_s">
		<text>5.45x39</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap">
		<text>5.56x45mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_s">
		<text>5.56x45 AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
		<text>5.56x45mm SS109</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_s">
		<text>5.56x45 SS.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1">
		<text>7.62x54 mm 7H1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1_s">
		<text>7.62x54 7h1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
		<text>7.62x54R 7N14</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_s">
		<text>7.62x54R 7N14</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap">
		<text>7.62x54 mm BP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_s">
		<text>7.62x54 BP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj">
		<text>9x18 mm.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_s">
		<text>9x18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm">
		<text>9x18 mm PMM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_s">
		<text>9x18 PMM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pbp">
		<text>9x18 mm PBP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pbp_s">
		<text>9x18 PBP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj">
		<text>9x19 mm.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_s">
		<text>9x19 Par.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp">
		<text>9x19mm PBP cartridges</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_s">
		<text>9x19 PBP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-ap">
		<text>9x39mm SP-6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-ap_s">
		<text>9x39 SP-6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9">
		<text>9x39mm PAB-9</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_s">
		<text>9x39 PAB9</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-sp5">
		<text>9x39mm SP-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-sp5_s">
		<text>9x39 SP-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-gauss">
		<text>Gauss cartridges</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-gauss_s">
		<text>Gauss</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-m209">
		<text>M203</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-m209_s">
		<text>M203</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-og-7b">
		<text>OG-7B</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-og-7b_s">
		<text>OG-7B</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25">
		<text>VOG-25</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25_s">
		<text>VOG-25</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25p">
		<text>VOG-25P</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25p_s">
		<text>VOG-25P</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
		<text>The base cartridge for Colt M1911, Sig-Sauer P220, USP Compact, and Desert Eagle pistols. Simple core, jacketed bullet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
		<text>It's called HydroShock. An enhanced performance cartridge for the Colt M1911, Sig-Sauer P220, USP Compact, and Desert Eagle pistols. An expansive bullet with good stopping power.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-12x70-buck">
		<text>A regular 12-gauge cartridge loaded with 6mm shot. At close ranges, it has tremendous killing power. Designed for shotguns TOZ-34, BM-16, Mossberg 88, SPAS-12, Protecta, Striker. Most effective at ranges up to 30 meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-12x76-dart">
		<text>Pointed bullet that stabilizes in flight, which has a positive effect on accuracy. For shotguns TOZ-34, BM-16, Mossberg 88, SPAS-12, Protecta, Striker. Increased range and armor-piercing power - effective at ranges up to 150 meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-12x76-zhekan">
		<text>A cartridge with a heavy breech-loading bullet. Usually used for hunting large animals, but suitable for other purposes as well. Its heavy bullet does not pierce, but actually pierces through body armor. Designed for shotguns TOZ-34, BM-16, Mossberg 88, SPAS-12, Protecta, Striker. Effective at ranges up to 100 meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.45x39-ap">
		<text>Armor-piercing cartridge for AKS-74, AKS-74U assault rifles. Improved armor-piercing ability of the bullet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
		<text>Standard cartridge for AKS-74, AKS-74U assault rifles. Simple core, jacketed bullet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.56x45-ap">
		<text>Armor-piercing bullet cartridge for L85, LR-300, Sig-550, G36, FN-2000 assault rifles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
		<text>Standard NATO cartridge, commonly known by the Belgian SS109 index. Used in L85, LR-300, Sig-550, G36, FN-2000 assault rifles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-7h1">
		<text>A low-cost modification of the sniper cartridge for SVD, SVU-AS and PKM sniper rifles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
		<text>Sniper cartridge for SVD, SVU-AS sniper rifles and PKM machine gun. It has improved accuracy and range characteristics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-ap">
		<text>Armor-piercing bullet. For SVD, SVU-AS sniper rifles and PKM machine gun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x18-fmj">
		<text>Basic cartridge for PM, PB, Fort-12, APS pistols. Simple core, jacketed bullet. Weak armor-piercing effect.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x18-pmm">
		<text>Cartridge with improved ballistic characteristics for PM, PB, Fort-12, APS pistols. Due to the higher muzzle velocity of the bullet, it is much more effective than a conventional cartridge. More pronounced armor-piercing effect.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x18-pbp">
		<text>A cartridge with improved characteristics for PM, PB, Fort-12, APS pistols. Powerful cartridge with expansive bullet and armor-piercing core.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x19-fmj">
		<text>Basic cartridge for HPSA, Walther P-99, Beretta92FS, GSh-18 pistols. A jacketed bullet. Weak armor-piercing effect.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x19-pbp">
		<text>Improved performance cartridge for HPSA, Walther P-99, Beretta92FS, GSh-18 pistols. Powerful cartridge with expansive bullet and armor-piercing core.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x39-ap">
		<text>Armor-piercing cartridge for Groza, Val and special Vintorez sniper rifle. It has subsonic flight speed, but due to the special bullet design it penetrates most body armor at ranges up to 400 meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x39-pab9">
		<text>Cartridge for Groza, Val and special Vintorez sniper rifle. A later and cheaper to manufacture modification of the armor-piercing cartridge. It has subsonic flight speed, but due to the special bullet design it penetrates most body armor at ranges up to 300 meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x39-sp5">
		<text>Sniper cartridge for Groza, Val and special Vintorez sniper rifles. It has subsonic flight speed, but due to the heavy bullet of special design it penetrates most body armor at ranges up to 400 meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-gauss">
		<text>Energy receptacles with ready-made killstreaks in the magazine for the Gauss rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-m209">
		<text>Grenade for M203 underbarrel grenade launcher. Used in LR-300, G36, Sig-550, L85 assault rifles and for integrated grenade launcher in FN-2000.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-og-7b">
		<text>Fuzed fragmentation grenade for RPG-7B. Equally effective against both manpower and lightly armored vehicles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-vog-25">
		<text>Standard grenade for GP-25 Kostyor underbarrel grenade launcher, Groza integrated underbarrel grenade launcher and RG-6 revolver grenade launcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-vog-25p">
		<text>Grenade for GP-25 Kostyor underbarrel grenade launcher, Groza integrated underbarrel grenade launcher and RG-6 revolver grenade launcher. Before detonation, the grenade jumps up to a height of about a meter, which increases its impact effect.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-f1">
		<text>A hand-held defensive grenade with a large fragmentation radius. Throwing is recommended only from shelter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-gd05">
		<text>Hand-held smoke grenade. Designed for the installation of a smoke cover. Time of action is 10 seconds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-rgd5">
		<text>Offensive hand grenade. The fragmentation damage radius is small.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-abakan">
		<text>AKM variant with metal buttstock folding down under the forend. The stock mounting system has been changed compared to the AKS. The buttstock is raised to bring the point of rest closer to the firing line. The modification is designed specifically for paratroopers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-abakan_m1">
		<text>An assault rifle equipped with a modified telescopic sight for sniper fire. The body-mounted optics have a higher magnification than standard sights.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-abakan_m2">
		<text>This assault rifle is equipped with an integrated underbarrel grenade launcher, making this model an even more versatile weapon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-grenade-launcher">
		<text>Under-barrel grenade launcher for assault rifles used in Warsaw Pact countries.\nAmmunition - VOG-25\ngrenade and VOG-25P grenade.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-grenade-launcher-m203">
		<text>Underbarrel grenade launcher for NATO rifles.\nAmmunition - M203 grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-scope">
		<text>Widely used Soviet-made telescopic sight. The standard dovetail mount of the Warsaw Pact countries is used for mounting on the weapon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-scope-susat">
		<text>Optical 4x scope manufactured in NATO countries. Mounted on a standard NATO mount - the so-called Picatinny bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-silencer">
		<text>An effective silencer, assembled in the Zone by some skilled craftsmen. It comes with a set of adapters for any caliber weapon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74">
		<text>A 1974 model folding assault rifle chambered for 5.45x39mm cartridge. It is a simple and reliable weapon, although the cheapness of production has somewhat affected the usability and accuracy of combat. In the Zone, it is the primary weapon of military stalkers and many loners.\nAmmunition:\nconventional 5.45x39mm,\narmor-piercing 5.45x39mm BP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74_m1">
		<text>Modified bolt mechanism increases the rate of fire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74u">
		<text>By its dimensions and weight the AKS-74U is close to submachine guns, but the principle of operation of the mechanism of this weapon and the cartridge used in it make it a representative of the submachine gun class. Advantages include small size, which is extremely useful in urban combat, and a fairly high penetrating power of the cartridge. The main disadvantages are short sighting range and tendency to overheat quickly when firing in bursts.\nAmmunition:\nconventional 5.45x39mm,\narmor-piercing 5.45x39mm BP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-beretta">
		<text>It is in service with the U.S. military and police forces, as well as many paramilitary and law enforcement units around the world. Equally popular with the criminal world due to its powerful cartridge and large magazine capacity.\nAmmunition:\nbasic 9x19mm Parabellum,\nenhanced 9x19mm PBP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-bm16">
		<text>This shotgun is one of the most common weapons for beginners.\nAmmunition:\n12x70 buckshot,\n12x76 javelin,\n12x76 dart.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-colt1911">
		<text>Classic automatic Colt, which has passed with honor all the armed conflicts of the XX century and confidently entered the new century. The low magazine capacity is compensated to a certain extent by the use of a powerful cartridge.\nAmmunition:\nregular 11.43x23 FMJ,\nenhanced 11.43x23 "HydroShock".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-desert-eagle">
		<text>A real gun for real heroes. Big, heavy, and extremely killable. Because of the price and size is not particularly popular in the Zone, after all, not every day you hunt an elephant.\nAmmunition:\nregular .45 ACP,\nenhanced .45 ACP HydroShock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-fn2000">
		<text>FN2000 with computerized fire control module sight and 40mm grenade launcher.\nAmmunition:\nconventional 5.56x45mm SS109,\narmor-piercing 5.56x45mm AR.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-fort">
		<text>The Fort 12 pistol is a police pistol to replace the morally and physically obsolete PM (Makarov) pistols of the Soviet era. It has better accuracy than the PM, larger magazine capacity and more comfortable grip.\nAmmunition:\nbasic 9x18mm,\nenhanced 9x18mm PMM.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-g36">
		<text>German-made assault rifle, which is a first-class example of a modern weapon - lightweight, reliable and ergonomic.\nAmmunition:\nconventional 5.56x45mm SS109,\narmor-piercing 5.56x45mm AR.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-gauss">
		<text>A super-precision weapon that the designers in the Zone put together. Operates almost silently, as it uses artifact energy rather than gunpowder gases to fire. Despite the enormous power of the shot, the recoil of the Gauss gun is very low. It is superior to any classic small arms weapon in accuracy and killing power.\nAmmunition is 2-millimeter gauss ammunition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-groza">
		<text>Automatic grenade launcher is a very successful variant of the assault rifle in the Zone conditions: compact, reliable, and at the same time versatile and powerful. Thunderstorm is much favored by military stalkers.\nAmmunition:\nregular 9x39mm PAB-9,\narmor-piercing 9x39mm SP-6,\nsniper 9x39mm SP-5,\nfor underbarrel grenades VOG-25 and VOG-25P.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-hpsa">
		<text>Produced by the Belgian company FN Erstal. The Browning HP (High Power) family of pistols is designed for police and military use. They are in service in more than 100 countries around the world. 
The Browning High Power is deservedly considered one of the finest pistols of the twentieth century.\nAmmunition:\nbasic 9x19mm Parabellum,\nenhanced 9x19mm PBP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-knife">
		<text>A hunting knife. An indispensable weapon if you need to take someone out quietly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-l85">
		<text>After this rifle was replaced by the British Army with the German G36, it surfaced in large numbers on the black market and then in the Zone. The main advantages of the L85 are the standard 4x scope and the high accuracy of the first shot. When firing in bursts, the accuracy of the rifle drops drastically, and the reliability of the main mechanisms of the rifle is not high enough.\nAmmunition:\nconventional 5.56x45mm SS109,\narmor-piercing 5.56x45mm AR.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-lr300">
		<text>The latest development of the American company Z-M Weapons, whose owner Allan Zitta is well known in gun circles for his many years of experience in technical development of .Colt-based combat and sporting pistols.  1911. The LR-300 is nothing short of a new stage in the development of the AR-15. LR-300 stands for Lightweight Rifle Effective Fire Rifle up to 300 meters. Compared to the AR-15, the AR-15 utilizes a shorter gas system, significantly modified gas exhaust system and completely reconstructed upper part of the bolt carrier.\nAmmunition:\nconventional 5.56x45mm SS109,\narmor-piercing 5.56x45mm AR.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-mp5">
		<text>One of the best in the submachine gun class of weapons. During the last decades of the XX century, it was adopted by special units of the army and police in many countries of the world. With the beginning of its gradual replacement by more modern models began to appear often on the black market, from where it massively got into the Zone.\nAmmunition:\nbasic 9x19mm Parabellum,\nenhanced 9x19mm PBP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-HK53">
		<text>HK 53 - HK33KA3 variant with shortened barrel to 211mm, extended four-slot flame arrester and forend similar to HK MP5. It is not possible to install underbarrel grenade launcher and bayonet knife. Produced since 1975 and used by special forces.\nAmmunition:\nconventional 5.56x45mm SS109,\narmor-piercing 5.56x45mm AR.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pb">
		<text>A pistol with an integrated silencer, once used by the Soviet Special Forces. Morally obsolete, but in capable hands still quite effective.\nAmmunition:\nbasic 9x18mm,\nenhanced 9x18mm PMM.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pm">
		<text>Designed and manufactured by Izhevsk Machine Engineering Plant in Russia for police and military armament since 1951, this Soviet legacy is the most common pistol in the Zone and is one of the best compact self-defense handguns available. It is small, highly reliable, easy to use and maintain in working order. It also suffers from several drawbacks, including its short range, low firing accuracy and poor stopping power, while also losing out to modern pistols in its class in terms of weight and magazine size.\nAmmunition:\nbasic 9x18mm,\nenhanced 9x18mm PMM.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-rg-6">
		<text>Revolver-type grenade launcher. Sometimes just indispensable, in particular when clearing large areas of mutants, attacking guarded stationary objects, in combat with particularly tenacious creatures.\nAmmunition - VOG-25 grenade,\nand VOG-25P grenade.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-rpg7">
		<text>A grenade launcher from the 1960s, left in huge quantities in army warehouses, from where it got into the Zone. A rare weapon for stalkers: its impressive size and heavy weight make it not too popular, although for some tasks it is indispensable.\nAmmunition - OG-7B.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-sig220">
		<text>A model developed back in 1975, but still popular all over the world. The magazine is not big enough, but the mechanism is as reliable as a Swiss watch; the second advantage is the use of a powerful Colt cartridge.\nAmmunition:\nregular 11.43x23 FMJ,\nenhanced 11.43x23 HydroShock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-sig550">
		<text>One of the relatively new Swiss assault rifles chambered for the 5.56x45mm SS109 cartridge. The accuracy, soft recoil and high reliability of this weapon quickly gained it the widest popularity.\nAmmunition:\nconventional 5.56x45mm SS109,\narmor-piercing 5.56x45mm AR.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-spas12">
		<text>The SPAS-12 shotgun was developed in the late 1970s as a versatile combat weapon for police and Army assault units. These weapons are characterized by high reliability and flexibility of use; on the other hand, they are rather massive, complicated and expensive. Perhaps, there is no better gun for close combat in the Zone.\nAmmunition:\n12x70 buckshot,\n12x76 javelin,\n12x76 dart.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-svd">
		<text>Sniper rifle. It has been widely used in all combat operations conducted by the Soviet and Russian armies since the 1960s. Has proven to be an extremely reliable and easy to handle weapon. In the Zone, it is especially favored by experienced stalkers of the "Duty" faction.\nAmmunition:\nconventional 7.62x54 mm 7H1,\narmor-piercing 7.62x54 mm BP,\nsniper 7.62x54 mm 7H14.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-svu">
		<text>A more modern version of the rifle, designed in a compact bullpup pattern. Very good for long distance travel in the Zone.\nAmmunition:\nconventional 7.62x54 mm 7H1,\narmor-piercing 7.62x54 mm BP,\nsniper 7.62x54 mm 7H14.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-toz34">
		<text>TOZ-34 is a two-barrel light-type hunting rifle with low barrels designed for commercial and recreational hunting. Produced piece by piece since 1964 at the Tula Arms Factory.\nAmmunition:\n12x70 buckshot,\n12x76 javelin,\n12x76 dart.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-usp">
		<text>Solid trunk. German quality and reliability. A compact melee weapon. Particularly popular with veterans of the Zone. A variant for the 0.45ACP caliber. The magazine capacity is 8 rounds.\nAmmunition:\nregular 11.43x23 FMJ,\nenhanced 11.43x23 HydroShock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-val">
		<text>It is based on the Vintorez silenced sniper rifle, from which it differs by its folding buttstock, the ability to fire in bursts, and a larger magazine. Originally intended for use by special forces in attack situations requiring silent and flameless firing.\nAmmunition:\nconventional 9x39mm PAB-9,\narmor-piercing 9x39mm SP-6,\nsniper 9x39mm SP-5.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-vintorez">
		<text>The VSS Vintorez (Special Vintorez Sniper Rifle) was developed on the basis of the AS Val by designers P. Serdyukov and V. Krasnikov at the Central Research Institute of Precision Machine Building and adopted for service in 1987. The Vintorez is designed for silent and flameless sniper shooting.\nAmmunition:\nconventional 9x39mm PAB-9,\narmor-piercing 9x39mm SP-6,\nsniper 9x39mm SP-5.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-walther">
		<text>Excellent German-made pistol with high reliability, large magazine capacity and good accuracy, especially in this version - for 9mm Parabellum cartridge.\nAmmunition:\nbasic 9x19mm Parabellum,\nenhanced 9x19mm PBP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-wincheaster1300">
		<text>American-made pump action shotgun, designed for use in the most adverse conditions and characterized by high reliability. All parts are provided with an anti-corrosion coating.\nAmmunition:\n12x70 buckshot,\n12x76 javelin,\n12x76 dart.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pri_lom_ak74">
		<text>A stalker nicknamed Crowbar used to work as a mechanic in a locksmith factory. He made small changes in the design of his AK-74M, which increased the weapon's rate of fire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-vintorez_coll">
		<text>Sniper rifle, special, modernized. Designed for silent and flameless sniper shooting and features an integrated silencer. The firing mechanism was modified to reduce wear and tear during firing. The magazine was also enlarged to 20 rounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grenade-f1">
		<text>F1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grenade-gd05">
		<text>GD-05</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grenade-rgd5">
		<text>RGD-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Weapons1">
		<text>Weapons</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wp_desert_eagle">
		<text>Desert Eagle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_hpsa">
		<text>FN HPSA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_usp">
		<text>USP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-abakan">
		<text>AKMS-MF1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-abakan_m1">
		<text>AKMS Sniper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-abakan_m2">
		<text>AKMS - Assault</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon-grenade-launcher">
		<text>GP-25 Bonfire</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon-grenade-launcher-m203">
		<text>M203</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon-scope">
		<text>PSO-1 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon-scope-susat">
		<text>SUSAT scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon-silencer">
		<text>Silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-ak74">
		<text>AKS-74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-ak74_m1">
		<text>AKS-74 Rapid-fire</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-ak74u">
		<text>AKS-74U</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-ak74u_m1">
		<text>AKS-74U Spetsnaz</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-beretta">
		<text>Beretta</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-bm16">
		<text>BM-16</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-colt_m1">
		<text>Colt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-colt1911">
		<text>Colt M1911</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-eagle_m1">
		<text>Eagle-m1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-fn2000">
		<text>FN-2000</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-fort">
		<text>Fort12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-fort_m">
		<text>Fort-12M</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-g36">
		<text>HK G36</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-gauss">
		<text>Gauss</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-groza">
		<text>OK-14 Groza</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-groza_m1">
		<text>Thunderstorm 5.45</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-l85">
		<text>L85A2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-l85_m1">
		<text>L85A2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-l85_m2">
		<text>L85A2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-lr300">
		<text>LR300</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-lr300_m1">
		<text>LR-300</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-mp5">
		<text>MP5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-mp5_m1">
		<text>MP5 9x18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-mp5_m2">
		<text>MP5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-pb">
		<text>PB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-pm">
		<text>PMM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-rg-6">
		<text>RG-6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-rg6_m1">
		<text>RG-6 M203</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-rpg7">
		<text>RPG-7B</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-sig_m1">
		<text>Sig-550 Assault</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-sig_m2">
		<text>Sig-550 Sniper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-sig220">
		<text>P220</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-sig550">
		<text>Sig-550</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-spas12">
		<text>SPAS12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-spas12_m1">
		<text>SPAS12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-svd">
		<text>SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-svd_m1">
		<text>SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-svu">
		<text>SVU</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-toz34">
		<text>TOZ-34</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-val">
		<text>AS VAL</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-val_m1">
		<text>Shaft</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-vintorez">
		<text>VSS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-walther">
		<text>P-99</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-walther_m1">
		<text>Walther 9x18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-wincheaster1300">
		<text>Mossberg 88</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-vintorez_coll">
		<text>Improved Rifles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_bm16_full">
		<text>BM-16</text>
	</string>
    <string id="enc_weapons_wpn_bm16_full">
		<text>Unshortened version of the BM-16 shotgun. It is distinguished from the Obrez by its greater nastiness and accuracy. Suitable for hunting boars and larger animals. Often seen in rookies and on sale at merchants.\nAmmunition:\n12x70 buckshot,\n12x76 javelin,\n12x76 dart.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="wpn-p90_name">
		<text>FN P90</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-p90">
		<text>Belgian submachine gun developed in the 1980s by FN Herstal. Despite its unusual appearance, it is quite effective. In the Zone, the FN P90 was fairly quickly redesigned for a special 5.56x45mm cartridge with more penetrating power than other pistol cartridges. The gun is easy to use and has extremely low recoil.\nAmmunition:\nconventional 5.56x45mm SS109,\narmor-piercing 5.56x45mm AR.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="wpn-pkm_name">
		<text>PKM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pkm">
		<text>Such weapons are usually equipped with heavily armed squads of military stalkers. It is extremely rare in the Zone, due to its large size and weight, which sometimes requires wearing an exoskeleton to shoot from hand.\nAmmunition:\narmor-piercing 7.62x54 mm BP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-aps">
		<text>APS</text>
	</string>
        <string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-aps">
		<text>APS is an automatic pistol developed in the late 1940s and early 1950s and adopted by the Soviet Armed Forces in 1951, at the same time as the Makarov pistol. APS is intended for arming officers taking direct part in combat operations, as well as for soldiers and sergeants of some special units.\n- 9x18mm, 9x18mm BMP\n- effective range 100m\n- magazine capacity 20 rounds\</text>
        </string>





	<string id="enc_zone_art_lampa">
		<text>Description: A super-powered psi wave emitter of unknown type. It looks like an ordinary lamp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_lampa">
		<text>Death-lamp</text>
	</string>


	<string id="enc_zone_af_art_kub">
		<text>Description: Has interesting and unpredictable properties. For example, it increases resistance to breakouts. Rumor has it that if you fall asleep with this artifact being zombified, the disease can recede and the artifact itself will disappear...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-af_art_kub">
		<text>The invisible cube</text>
	</string>


	<string id="enc_zone_art_lenss">
		<text>Description: a valuable and rare artifact. The object of sale, studied properties has no properties, except one - increases the body's resistance to high temperatures.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_lenss">
		<text>Lens</text>
	</string>



	<string id="enc_zone_art_ruchk">
		<text>Description: an anomalous object of unknown origin. Something that looked like a thick pen, dark in color with a grayish pattern on the surface. Radiates warmth - you can feel it even through the gloves of your protective coveralls. Increases the weight carried by 3 kg.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_ruchk">
		<text>Handle</text>
	</string>




	<string id="enc_zone_art_spiral">
		<text>Description: an anomalous object of unknown origin, resembling a spiral. When worn on the belt, it causes a feeling of drowsiness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_spiral">
		<text>Spirals</text>
	</string>





	<string id="enc_zone_art_steklo">
		<text>Description: transparent objects valuable from an aesthetic point of view.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_steklo">
		<text>Glass-like objects</text>
	</string>




	<string id="enc_zone_art_sterj">
		<text>    Description: The only artifact of its kind. The straight metal rod is 43 cm long. On one of the sides you can see the numbers "2465" clearly printed.
    Properties: Capable of quenching any type of energy without changing shape or showing any primary signs (heating or cooling). Non-radioactive, no hazardous effects have been identified.
    Application: Object of scientific research.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_sterj">
		<text>Rod 2465</text>
	</string>










	<string id="enc_head_cherep">
		<text>A human skull, but made of a strange material. It's moving a bit, there are some fastenings in the eye sockets.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="enc_zone_art_chernaya_busina">
		<text>Description: Artifact with the negative properties of the host's influence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_chernaya_busina">
		<text>Black bead</text>
	</string>




	<string id="enc_zone_art_lichinka">
		<text>Description: a shrunken larva of an unknown insect inside a glass oval. Has a strange property of saturating its host.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_lichinka">
		<text>Larva</text>
	</string>





	<string id="enc_zone_art_3_step_anom_svetim">
		<text>An artifact of third-degree anomalous luminosity. Properties are unknown except one - increases resistance to radiation. It is well known that artifacts of the anomalous luminosity class can react anomalously with other artifacts of that class.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_3_step_anom_svetim">
		<text>An artifact of the third degree of anomalous luminosity</text>
	</string>





	<string id="enc_zone_art460">
		<text>Artifact #460. An object with a negative degree of anomalous luminosity. Properties unknown. It is well known that artifacts of the anomalous luminosity class can react anomalously with other artifacts of that class.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art460">
		<text>Artifact #460</text>
	</string>





	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_black_kristal">
		<text>An artifact of unknown origin. A poorly studied specimen. It has the property of increasing the muscle tone of the wearer, so you can move around longer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-black_kristal">
		<text>Black crystal</text>
	</string>



	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_kolco">
		<text>An artifact of unknown origin. It has the property of increasing the muscle tone of the wearer, so you can move around longer. Prone to degeneration with prolonged use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-af_kolco">
		<text>Ring</text>
	</string>



	<string id="enc_zone_af_studen">
		<text>A viscous substance. Ultra-hazardous colonies of mutated bacteria.\nSpecificity: very dangerous anomalous formation, store only in a secure container such as an R1 capsule.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-af_studen">
		<text>Stud</text>
	</string>


	<string id="enc_af_gold_fish_black">
		<text>The result of artifact modification. Has boosted properties of parental artifacts, including negative ones.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-af_gold_fish_black">
		<text>Black Gravy</text>
	</string>




	<string id="af_studen_m1_desc">
		<text>The result of genetic modification of artifact jelly. Protects against exposure to parasitic spores, eliminates the possibility of contracting the disease.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="af-ameba-mica">
		<text>Mercury ball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-ameba-slime">
		<text>Radioactive bolt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-ameba-slug">
		<text>Radioactive debris</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-blood">
		<text>Toad's eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-cristall">
		<text>Double pacifier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-cristall-flower">
		<text>Glass bagel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-drops">
		<text>Zuda</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-battery">
		<text>Disintegrator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-dummy">
		<text>Pacifier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-glassbeads">
		<text>Dead head</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-pellicle">
		<text>Plasma</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-spring">
		<text>Washcloth</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-electra-flash">
		<text>Burning Wat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-electra-moonlight">
		<text>Electric ball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-electra-sparkler">
		<text>Node</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-fireball">
		<text>Transparent balloon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-fuzz-kolobok">
		<text>Strong needles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-gold-fish">
		<text>A strong gravitational artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-gravi">
		<text>gravitational artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-medusa">
		<text>Bagel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-mincer-meat">
		<text>Rusty hair</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-night-star">
		<text>Magnet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-rusty-kristall">
		<text>Black thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-rusty-sea-urchin">
		<text>Needles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-rusty-thorn">
		<text>Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-soul">
		<text>Black drops</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-vyvert">
		<text>A weak gravitational artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Agroprom">
		<text>MedPribor Research Institute</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Ameba">
		<text>Cholodets</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Anomalies">
		<text>Anomalies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Artifacts">
		<text>Artifacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bald">
		<text>Mosquito Patch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bar">
		<text>Bar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Darkdolina">
		<text>Dark Valley</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Electra">
		<text>Electra</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Hvat">
		<text>Grabber</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Birthmark">
		<text>A birthmark</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Witchring">
		<text>Witch rings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Emp">
		<text>Electromagnetic pulse (EMP)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Acidfog">
		<text>Acid cloud</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Lift">
		<text>Elevator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Roundabout">
		<text>Carousel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-winchester_m1">
		<text>Chaser Modification. A small fragment of Gravi artifact was embedded in the under-barrel ammunition receptacle, oriented in such a way as to increase the bullet's flight velocity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_acidfog">
		<text>This formation is so named because of the characteristic damage when it enters the area of action. Visually, however, it looks like a bright purple shimmer in the air.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_roundabout">
		<text>The name is due to the effect of lifting any living thing into the air and then spinning it up to tremendous speed. The nature of the "Carousel" has not yet been fully explored. Detected by a light dust vortex and scattered body fragments around. It is very important not to miss the moment of the beginning of pulling into the anomalous vortex and not to get into the zone of maximum strong effect in the center - only then there is a chance to get away with minimal injuries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_ameba">
		<text>A formation of a nature not entirely clear. On contact with the body, causes injuries similar to the effects of strong acid.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_emp">
		<text>A localized concentrate of electromagnetic energy. When quiet, it appears as a dull blue-blue flicker. At the moment of actuation, it creates a disturbance of the electromagnetic field affecting any material object in the area of its action. The damaging effect of an electromagnetic pulse (EMP) is caused by induced voltages and currents in various conductors. The effect of EMI is manifested primarily in relation to electrical and radio-electronic equipment. Does not pose a threat to living things, but can severely damage all electrical appliances. EMP is most often the cause of military helicopter crashes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_witchring">
		<text>One of the Zone's most inexplicable phenomena. It is not known whether this formation causes damage on contact. There is also no information regarding the artifacts produced. It's not just scientists who are trying to study the anomaly, the black market is also showing great interest. Rumor has it that the substance could give stalkers back the ability to have healthy children.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_birthmark">
		<text>Aggressive Organics. The original source appears to have been moss. The formation does not have a permanent shape, when approached, it digs into the victim with outgrowths, causing severe damage to exposed skin areas. Scientists have not yet determined what artifacts form this anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_hvat">
		<text>The progenitor of this mutaflora species is not yet known to scientists. Mostly grows in densely overgrown grassy areas, so it is hard to detect. Remarkably, it is impossible to detect this anomaly with detectors. To hit small objects, such as bolts or stones anomaly is also indifferent. Only works on organic life forms. If the subject enters the target area, it instantly collapses, preventing escape. Forms "Thorn" artifacts of various kinds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_bald">
		<text>One of the Zone's most common anomalies. It represents a region of multiply increased gravity - "graviconcentrate". The type of damage is a gravity strike. Causes severe damage to internal organs, destruction of skeletal bones, and tissue tears. Depending on concentration, tears apart a trapped living creature or inflicts severe damage such as deep cuts all over the body. Forms gravitational artifacts of various types of effects. An anomalous gravitational field in a quiescent state is easily visible by a characteristic sparkle-like glow. There is a rumor among stalkers that anomalies of this type began to be fixed outside the zone. This is of no-nonsense concern to the scientific world, although there has been no confirmation of these rumors so far.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_electra">
		<text>An anomalous formation about 10 meters in diameter, accumulating static electricity. A disturbed anomaly explodes with dozens of mini lightning bolts, and electrocution is almost always fatal for any living creature. A characteristic feature of the electra is the bluish mist visible above it during the day. At night, it is easily detected by any kind of detectors or by throwing metal objects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_fuzz">
		<text>anomalously altered vegetation. At the rapid approach of a living creature, it emits a cloud of particles, which in case of contact with open or poorly protected skin will seriously injure the latter. It does not respond to slow moving objects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_gravi">
		<text>The anomaly is presumably gravitational in nature. At the moment of activation with a terrible force pulls into itself everything that is within a radius of 10-15 meters. If hit in the center of the funnel there is no chance of survival: the body of both animal and human will be compressed into a dense lump, and then torn at the moment of the so-called discharge. During the entire period of its existence - on average about a week - the anomaly does not change its location; it can be visually detected during the day by the characteristic air movement above it, swirling foliage, fragments of dismembered corpses and a characteristic dark spot on the ground in the center. Extremely dangerous at night, as it is only detected by detectors or by throwing metal objects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_lift">
		<text>A harmless gravitational anomaly that allows you to forget about the laws of gravity for a while. In a local volume with a diameter of a few meters, the Earth's gravity is greatly reduced. Forms the artifact "Film".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_meat">
		<text>The name is due to the effect of lifting any living thing into the air and then spinning it up to tremendous speed. The nature of the roundabout has not yet been fully investigated. Detected by a light dust vortex and scattered body fragments around. It is very important not to miss the moment of the beginning of pulling into the anomalous vortex and not to get into the zone of maximum strong effect in the center - only then there is a chance to get away with minimal injuries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_radioactive">
		<text>An area of elevated levels - more than 50 mcR/h - of radiation. Prolonged exposure to such places should be avoided.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_time">
		<text>An anomaly, which can rightly be called a small miracle: in a volume with a diameter of several meters, the flow of time is repeatedly slowed down. There appears to be no negative health effects, but it is not easy to get out of it. Interestingly, at the center of the time machine is usually an artifact called Mama's Beads, upon removal of which the anomaly ceases to exist.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_zharka">
		<text>In an inactive state it looks like a cloud of hot air, but when any object or living creature comes into range it forms a compact area heated to a temperature of about 1500K. Can only be detected at night by powerful detectors or by throwing metal objects. Forms three types of artifacts: "Drops," "Fireball," and "Crystal."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-mica">
		<text>Consists of liquid metal of anomalous origin. It is formed after emission, in contact with the body it lasts for a short time, after which it evaporates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-slime">
		<text>Cheap artifacts in the form of metal scraps and construction debris. It has no useful properties. Only of interest to researchers for radiation measurements.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-slug">
		<text>Cheap artifacts in the form of metal scraps and construction debris. It has no useful properties. Only of interest to researchers for radiation measurements.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-blood">
		<text>A unique artifact. The result of the interplay between Black Spiked and Meatgrinder. Rarely appears in clusters of anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-cristall">
		<text>Appears in clusters of anomalies. Protect against unconsciousness, restore strength, shield against psi effects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-cristall-flower">
		<text>A "springboard" anomaly is born. Such an artifact can be found in few parts of the zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-drops">
		<text>Formed by the "Roast" anomaly at high temperatures. Externally, it looks like a blackened drop-shaped formation with a glossy surface, covered with cracks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-battery">
		<text>A super artifact of an electro-magnetic nature. A directed field of disintegration. When activated, it emits a powerful force field that instantly transforms any objects into "jelly". The origin of this thing is shrouded in a veil of scientific mystery. It is clear that it includes dielectric elements, but under what physical conditions it is formed - science does not know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-dummy">
		<text>An artifact from a weak energy anomaly with no practical use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-glassbeads">
		<text>A level two super artifact. Appear in clusters of anomalies. Has the ability to scare away monsters while attracting the controller. When panicking monsters, it loses its anomalous energy and can vaporize. anomalous energy level: very high. Cost: very high.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-pellicle">
		<text>An artifact of transmutational origin. Has a high price tag. A viscous substance resembling a sticky mass, yet very strong. It tends to spread into crevices. Rumor has it that when this artifact is worn on the belt, it sinks into damaged areas of the suit and then solidifies there, thus patching holes and damage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-spring">
		<text>A superartefact with unstable gravity. A throwing object, after hitting the floor or an obstacle is fired at a living body. Once hit, is fired at the next living body until it falls or hits an inanimate object. After which it can be lifted.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-flash">
		<text>Large flying fluff, leaves severe burns when it hits the body. It accumulates in lowlands, pits and hollows. When there is a wind or explosion, it rises into the air. A rash of "burning fluff" growths.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-moonlight">
		<text>An outgrown case of Elektra anomaly activity. Apparently, such a wonderful rounded shape can be obtained by subjecting the anomaly to thermal stress. An expensive artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-sparkler">
		<text>The origin of this type of artifact as well as the name is shrouded in mystery. Valued amongst the explorers of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fireball">
		<text>An artifact of thermal origin. A transparent shimmering sphere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fuzz-kolobok">
		<text>When you hold this enigma of the Zone in your hands, you can feel your skin roughening and becoming less sensitive. It's still easy to puncture it with a bullet, but it's much harder to cut it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-gold-fish">
		<text>Spawned by the Vortex anomaly. Elemental artifact with a directional magnetic and gravitational anomaly. Allows you to carry an additional 6 lbs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-gravi">
		<text>Elemental artifact with a directional magnetic and gravitational anomaly. Has a variety with more pronounced anomalous properties - "strong gravitational artifact". Allows you to carry an extra 4 kilograms of weight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-medusa">
		<text>An elemental artifact of a gravitational nature. It has the shape of a torus, which explains its name. At least two varieties of this artifact are known, the common and the "glass bagel".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-mincer-meat">
		<text>An elemental artifact of organic nature. A bundle of stiff lichen fibers of a dirty rusty color. It has no useful properties. Object of Sale.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-night-star">
		<text>Various metal junk, which had been lying in gravitational anomalies for a long time, acquired the ability to create a directed magnetic field of high intensity. This specimen is a fragment of a gearbox toothed shaft. Magnet - A strong gravitational artifact with a strong one-sided gravitational anomaly, used to create gravity weapons and anti-gravity devices. Possesses surreal effects. Appears next to a maternal anomaly. It is not dangerous, so it can be picked up and does not necessarily need to be stored in a container. The artifact moves in every possible way: it dances and jumps up to half a meter, floats unsteadily above the ground and shakes; it can hang on the wall or ceiling, which confirms its gravitational origin. From 15-20 meters, the sound detector reacts to the artifact with a special sound. Has 1 level of anomalous energy. Allows you to carry an extra 5 pounds of weight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-kristall">
		<text>Crystallizes in the Stinging Fluff anomaly. Occurs infrequently and is quite effective, which has earned it a stable price on the artifact market.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-sea-urchin">
		<text>Reminiscent of 10-centimeter needles. Appear in their mother anomaly, stuck in the ground and swaying slightly. Will not fall if mounted on a point; will also stay on a point if pounded into a wall or ceiling at any angle. They are not dangerous, so they can be picked up and do not necessarily need to be stored in a container. From 3-7 meters, the detector reacts to the artifact with a special sound. Temporarily shielded from psi effects, blind dogs "lose track".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-thorn">
		<text>The result of the interaction between the Stinging Fluff anomaly and the body of an inattentive stalker. The spiked artifact prickles the wearer's body no matter how it is attached. Pretty common and cheap.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-soul">
		<text>Very rarely found near Carousel anomalies. Only a few people manage to find such an artifact, and few people have even seen it. It has a nice shape and an equally nice price.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-vyvert">
		<text>It is located near anomalies of the "Funnel" type. On contact with the body, it spreads directional radiation that increases endurance. Such an artifact is not difficult to find, so the money for it is not much. Allows you to carry an extra 2 kilograms of weight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_agroprom">
		<text>Strange terrain. If you go deeper into it, you'll come to a heavily contaminated plain. The shallow lake located there is filled to the brim with wreckage of machinery. You can also visit the old institute and the factory, but lately the military has been there too often.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_bar">
		<text>The Duty group has cleared a place on the outskirts of this wild territory for their base and allows stalkers to rest here. A kind of oasis. There is a department store building that houses a stalker bar: stalkers from all over the Zone gather there. The bar is run by a local merchant, so not only can you socialize here, but you can sell-buy almost anything. To the north of the bar is the military base, to the south is the Garbage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_darkdolina">
		<text>It's always gloomy and foggy here, and it rains often. You can get some nice artifacts in the Dark Valley, or you can quickly say goodbye to your life. There are many old stalkers here - they came here for valuable artifacts; there are also bandits. We could look for an entrance to an underground laboratory somewhere around here, but no one has ever returned from there, and no one really knows what's hiding there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_escape">
		<text>A kind of pre-bathroom of the Zone, the first place where rookies get, settling in little by little. In the cellar behind the village near the army checkpoint there is a merchant - it is useful to talk to him. It is not reasonable to go to the checkpoint and get caught by the soldiers: they have orders to shoot without warning; on the other hand, some of them are ready to instantly become friendly for money, especially if there are no superiors around. Killing soldiers is highly discouraged, except in the case of a direct threat to life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_garbage">
		<text>A huge technical cemetery: mountains of radioactive junk were brought here after the first accident. There are remnants of old buildings, mutants are encountered. There are a lot of rookies here, just like at the perimeter itself - and there are gangsters hanging around, always looking for a bigger piece of the action without much hassle. You can find some artifacts, but it's better not to stay long - there are more interesting places. If you go east, you'll come to the Wild Territory; to the west is the passage to the Research Institute; to the north is the road to Stalker Bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_military-loc">
		<text>An abandoned army base, an old village and a small lake. On the army base settled group Sin, religious fanatics who believe in the divine essence of the Zone, in the final redemption of mankind. According to the Barkeep about two weeks ago all the PDAs of the stalkers of this group went offline, since then nothing has been heard from them. All stalkers who approached their base disappeared. Either this group no longer exists, and something has settled there and is destroying everyone who comes near, or they've completely lost their minds and the Sinners are attacking everyone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_pripiat">
		<text>Mutant City. Home of controllers, bloodsuckers, and zombie armies. Packs of various mutants are born here. It's impossible to eliminate everyone, the only thing left is stealthy movements</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_radar">
		<text>Everyone exposed to the antenna is zombified. The resulting zombies wander towards the antenna, where they die over time from starvation, radiation, or aggression from other zombies. The approaches are strewn with dead bodies, and zombified mutants and stalkers roam the neighborhood, occasionally fighting each other.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_rostok">
		<text>It was a rather large factory, of which now only ruins remain. A lot of stalkers found their end in them: all sorts of unclean things have spread there, as if they converge there from all over the Zone. Rumor has it, though, that there is something very important at this plant, so there are always plenty of people willing to try their luck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_stancia">
		<text>A former nuclear power plant that everyone has heard of at least once. This is the heart of the Zone. If legends are to be believed, somewhere out there is some thing that can fulfill any wish - it's called the Monolith.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_yantar">
		<text>The lake has several islands of piled industrial debris and dilapidated buildings. Stone hulks stick out of the poisonous water. The lake is dead, nothing can live in it, getting into the lake causes severe acid burns. Rubber boots can be used to walk in shallow depths. There are several large islands of trash and building hulks in the center of the lake. They are accessed by several trails through shallow water. The largest one has a descent into an unflooded basement.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-2006">
		<text>There have been anonymous reports of strange phenomena being noticed in the inner ten-kilometer zone. 

A notoriety is growing around Pripyat - strange animals have appeared on the nighttime streets of the forgotten city. The first missing persons reports are coming in. 

After a bus carrying foreign tourists went missing in Pripyat, the zone was closed to visitors. Several lengthy investigations were inconclusive. There is no doubt - the bus has vaporized in the city, but further investigation yields nothing. 

Locals brought the dead body of a strange animal covered with red hair to the checkpoint. The mutated creature had a humanoid build, small stature, and large black eyes. The mutant has been taken. A few days later, the newspapers in the capital refuted the numerous rumors that the found corpse belonged to an escaped monkey of one of the maintenance chiefs.
</text>
	</string>



	<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-2008">
		<text>Chernobyl Scientific Research Institute of Parapsychology (NIIP). It is the central research building of the former Union. The various departments are scattered throughout the former USSR. From where research material was regularly sourced. The main goals are the study and development of human paranormal abilities. The priority is to work out a new concept of relations between a person and the state. Creation of a new society based on the common consciousness of the laboring masses. A new level of collectivism - a full-blown collective intelligence that encompasses all areas of human endeavor and includes all citizens of allied countries.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-2010">
		<text>In the footsteps of desperate lone stalkers for large-scale study of the Zone again take scientific expeditions. However, inside the perimeter guarded by the army, there are already many unaccounted for individuals - right down to poachers and bandits. In the bulk of stalkers travel through the Zone in search of a variety of anomalous formations - the so-called artifacts, for which often earn good money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-raid">
		<text>Rumors emerged among the local population that Chernobyl was a battery of secret government laboratories. The explosion was due to overloading during the experiment.  </text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-compas">
		<text>Spiral</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-compas">
		<text>A bizarre artifact shaped like a spiral.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Escape">
		<text>Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fuzz">
		<text>Stinging fluff</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Garbage">
		<text>Garbage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Gravi">
		<text>Funnel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Lift">
		<text>Elevator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Locations">
		<text>Locations</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Meat">
		<text>Carousel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Military-loc">
		<text>Silent Hills</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Pripiat">
		<text>Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Radar">
		<text>Radar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Radioactive">
		<text>Radioactivity hotspot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Rostok">
		<text>Rostok Plant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Stancia">
		<text>CHERNOBYL NPP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Story-2006">
		<text>2001-2005. Exclusion Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Story-2008">
		<text>2005</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Story-2010">
		<text>2010</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Story-raid">
		<text>Breaking into the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Time_machine">
		<text>Time machine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Yantar">
		<text>Yantar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Zharka">
		<text>Roasting</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Zone">
		<text>Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Zone-story">
		<text>History of the Zone</text>
	</string>

<string id="cant_walk">
		<text>You're too exhausted!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cant_walk_weight">
		<text>You're too overwhelmed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Global Map">
		<text>Global map</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gun_jammed">
		<text>The gun jammed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cant_sleep_near_enemies">
		<text>You can't sleep when your enemies are around</text>
	</string>
	<string id="inventory_box_use">
		<text>Search ($$ACTION_USE$$).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Local Map">
		<text>Local map</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_game_saved">
		<text>game saved</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tip_car_locked">
		<text>No keys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tip_car_use">
		<text>Enter ($$ACTION_USE$$)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tip_door_close">
		<text>Press ($$ACTION_USE$$) to close the door.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tip_door_decode">
		<text>Press ($$ACTION_USE$$) to decode the door.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tip_door_locked">
		<text>The door is closed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tip_door_open">
		<text>Press ($$ACTION_USE$$) to open the door.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tip_gate_close">
		<text>Press ($$ACTION_USE$$) to close the gate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tip_gate_locked">
		<text>The gate's locked.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tip_gate_open">
		<text>Press ($$ACTION_USE$$) to open the gate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tip_monolith">
		<text>MAKE A WISH ($$ACTION_USE$$)</text>
	</string>



	<string id="dpa_pda_ecol_dolina">
		<text>Most of the information is encrypted. Just the latest message from the Professor: The lab has an exit to the lower levels of the cordon, but the entrance to it is reportedly closed from the inside. If possible, verify this information after you take the measurements.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="enc_blue_pda_nine">
		<text>PDA of a military stalker with the call sign Blue 9. Blocked. Maybe someone can decipher it.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="rat_black_box_name">
		<text>Black box</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rat_black_box_desc">
		<text>A container with unknown contents.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="ros_korpus_pass_desc">
		<text>Note in the margin: Personally in hand.\nOn your order, a shipment of gas masks and work clothes has been transferred to the lower levels of the workshops. A total of 140 pieces, plus boxes of specialty weights for your job. We have one access from the plant to your area, and I know the access code to the anteroom. Code 2565, I'll remind you. Further passage is not available to us. We're not going to ask too many questions, but still, Mr. Petrov. Why do you have wagons coming to you? They come from the city, pass under the lake, and come to you. Get it right, we don't stick our nose where it doesn't belong, but I don't want to risk my position... I hope to meet you in person where we can discuss things more specifically.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_korpus_pass_name">
		<text>Note from the production manager</text>
	</string>



	<string id="enc_detector_zomscan">
		<text>Experimental prototype for PSI radiation scanning. To work, you need to point the device at the object, and activate it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="detector_zomscan_name">
		<text>Scanner</text>
	</string>




	<string id="jurn_plen_mesage_name">
		<text>Journalist's note</text>
	</string>


	<string id="jurn_plen_mesage_desc">
		<text>Shit... I had to get so screwed up. the winds of madness must surely be around here somewhere...\ndidn't need to go straight to the base of those nutcases...\njust to get out...\nneeds to catch the time...\nnotice the chance...</text>
	</string>







	<string id="daem_proto_psy_shap_desc">
		<text>A prototype device radiating from psi radiation. The operation is unstable, failures may occur.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="doc_4way_link_name">
		<text>Documentation: Brain Link</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_4way_link_desc">
		<text>...The 4 in charge lie in a state of induced coma, and if I'm not mistaken, they control everything that happens in the zone...\nNote: Strelok knew the code to enter the lab... maybe it's still in the stash on Roztec...</text>
	</string>


	<string id="tip_use_yanprib_hata">
		<text>Activate the device</text>
	</string>


	<string id="outfit_antirad_name_m">
		<text>Anti-radiation suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="outfit_antirad_description_m">
		<text>A modification of a scientific suit with active radiation protection. Removes radiation from the owner's body when in good technical condition.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="psystab_helmet_name">
		<text>Psi stabilizer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psystab_helmet_desc">
		<text>A device that allows you to shield certain types of psi attacks from a	 controller. Protects against the fatal effects of phantom formations.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="st_psivizor_detector">
		<text>Psy-watch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_psivizor_detector">
		<text>A device that registers in the PDA the presence of mutants with psi activity.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="jurn_psi_defence_name">
		<text>Psi Stabilizer Documentation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jurn_psi_defence_desc">
		<text>A thick folder in which, surprisingly, all the sheets stayed in place intact. The title page bears the title, "documentation for a defense device for protection in high psi background" and the state seal." On the following pages, in neat and even handwriting, there are notes in simple pencil, the author of which insistently advised to reduce the power consumption of the main unit, which, according to him, will affect the increased mobility of the protection device. Taped to the last page are two envelopes with letters to the head of the ZX-16 science lab. In the first, the addressee requests to test a psi-defense device in the field. A village on the outskirts of the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone was chosen as one of the test sites. The second letter gives a detailed report on the success of the trials.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psi_vision_name">
		<text>Psi Visor documentation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psi_vision_desc">
		<text>A shredded file of documents. Many of the pages inside are missing. After reading the little that survived, we can safely conclude that it describes the principle of operation of the psi-visor, an experimental device of the new generation for survival in the dangerous environment of the Zone. The Psi-Visor is required to search for mobile sources of psi radiation, i.e., psionic beings. Unlike humans, psionic beings have their own unique rhythm of brain activity that is not yet fully understood by modern science. The device scans the area for rhythmic bioelectric brain activity and informs its owner of the psionic's presence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outfit_name">
		<text>Radiation protection suit documentation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_outfit_desc">
		<text>An old folder covered in a layer of dust. The yellowed pages have a schematic of an anti-radiation protective spacesuit and instructions for its use. The documentation says that the spacesuits of this limited series arrived at the laboratory from the Radiation Safety Research Institute earlier than scheduled, so they have not yet undergone all the necessary tests. Among the advantages: a closed breathing system and a new-generation insulation coating that can partially stop the flow of hot particles. From the disadvantages: low mobility due to the weight of oxygen tanks behind the back, low resistance to mechanical damage. There are notes in the appendix of the documentation, in which it is stated that a new version of the anti-radiation spacesuit has been created, in the design of which all the disadvantages of the previous samples have been corrected.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="visual_device_name">
		<text>Visual detector documentation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="visual_device_desc">
		<text>Documentation for an experimental software package that is being built into the PDAs of expeditionary units of military stalkers. It was found near one such group in the dungeons of the MedPribor Research Institute. Their devices have been smashed to pieces and can no longer function, so they are of little value. The documentation says that the complex allows you to scan the area around its owner in a radius of 50 meters for the presence of other devices, read, analyze and display the resulting information about the stalker who owns them. Based on this data, a picture is drawn of the stalker's affiliation with certain groups, his reputation in the stalker community, or his approximate relationship to the owner of the visual detector.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="activator_deznt_name">
		<text>Activator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_detector_activator_deznt">
		<text>Disintegrator artifact activator. Can activate the active particles of an artifact, turning it into jelly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="med_injector_name">
		<text>Diagnostic first aid kit with injector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="med_injector_name_s">
		<text>HEALTH-13</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_med_injector">
		<text>Universal Medical Kit.\nAllows you to treat injuries of varying degrees of complexity (wounds, burns, poisoning, disease, etc.).\nAllows you to diagnose various diseases of the body, as well as treat them\nTo work you need: special medical capsules</text>
	</string>
	<string id="med_injector_empty_desc">
		<text>Empty Universal Medical Kit. Special medical capsules are required for operation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="med_injector_capsule">
		<text>Medical capsules</text>
	</string>
	<string id="med_injector_capsule_desc">
		<text>Medical capsules for diagnostic first aid kit with injector.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_massive_gruz_name">
		<text>A load for the Professor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_massive_gruz_desc">
		<text>A container for the Professor. Special delivery from the big city.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_boots_mg">
		<text>Safety boots</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_boots_desc">
		<text>Safety boots made of a special material that can protect against corrosive acids.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_case_esc_desc">
		<text>A briefcase full of documents. Made of fire-resistant material.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_detector_yantar_desc">
		<text>A device for certain psi-field measurements.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_detector_yantar_name">
		<text>Universal psi-field meter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_dec_doc_desc">
		<text>A polyethylene file of documents.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_dec_doc_name">
		<text>Transcripts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_doc_x16_desc">
		<text>Psi Brain installation documents.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_doc_x16_name">
		<text>Lab documents</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_doc_x18_desc">
		<text>A thick stack of research papers. Solid terms, formulas and diagrams. It's hard to understand anything about them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_doc_x18p1_name">
		<text>Documents from X-18, part 1.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_doc_x18p2_name">
		<text>Documents from X-18 part 2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_doc_x18p3_name">
		<text>Documents from X-18 part 3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_doc_x18p4_name">
		<text>Documents from X-18, part 4.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_doc_x18p5_name">
		<text>Documents from X-18, part 5.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_dynamite_esc_desc">
		<text>A heavy wooden box, labeled Explosive in several languages.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_dynamite_esc_name">
		<text>A crate of dynamite</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_flash_gslinger_agro_desc">
		<text>A flash disk is a handy device for carrying information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_flash_gslinger_agro_name">
		<text>Mini PDA Strelok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_deserter_desc">
		<text>Pocket personal computer. An indispensable device in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_quest_case_02_desc">
		<text>A briefcase full of documents. Made of fire-resistant material.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_quest_case_02_name">
		<text>Military documents</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_case_esc_name">
		<text>The documents from the roadblock</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_bad_psy_helmet_desc">
		<text>A prototype developed by scientists to protect against psi radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_bad_psy_helmet_name">
		<text>Experimental Brainwave Emulator (BRAIN-4)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_good_psy_helmet_desc">
		<text>A customized prototype designed by scientists to protect against psi radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_good_psy_helmet_name">
		<text>Experimental Brainwave Emulator (BRAIN-6)</text>
	</string>



	<string id="ecolog_outfit_description">
		<text>Built for the Zone, the EX-04 chemical defense suit. Used by expeditions of scientists and cooperating environmental stalkers.\nBuilt-in air filtration and air conditioning system.\nNot designed for combat operations.\nNa is designed for long-term use.\nSpecificity: with prolonged use it becomes unusable - damaged and torn.\nProtection level against radiation - high\nProtection level against damage and shock - medium\nProtection level against bullets - low\nProtection level against anomalous activity - high</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog_outfit_name">
		<text>Scientific EX-04</text>
	</string>



	<string id="exo_outfit_description">
		<text>A sample military exoskeleton. Produced in small batches in clandestine factories. This exoskeleton belongs to the third generation. Does not give protection against bullet and shrapnel hits, nor does it guarantee resistance to anomalies, but it allows you to carry more weight, move faster and jump higher. A special battery is required for operation.\nProtection level against radiation - medium\nProtection level against damage and impact - medium\nProtection level against bullets - medium\nProtection level against anomalous activity - medium\nProtection level against anomalous activity - medium</text>
	</string>
	<string id="exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>



	<string id="killer_outfit_description">
		<text>A stalker's jumpsuit from a group of Assassins. The samples of special forces equipment of Western armies are taken as a basis. Due to special fabric processing, the stability of the armor in case of physical displacement of the plates is strengthened. In terms of protective characteristics, it is slightly superior to the army armored vests of the PSZ-7 series.\nProtection level against radiation - low\nProtection level against damage and shock - medium\nProtection level against bullets - medium\nProtection level against anomalous activity - low</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer_outfit_name">
		<text>Killer jumpsuit</text>
	</string>



	<string id="outfit_novice_description">
		<text>Protects the body from weak anomalies and light damage. No oxygen mask. Specificity: with prolonged use, it becomes unusable - damaged and torn.\nProtection level against radiation - low\nProtection level against damage and shock - low\nProtection level against bullets - low\nProtection level against anomalous activity - none</text>
	</string>
	<string id="outfit_novice_name">
		<text>Protective suit</text>
	</string>



	<string id="outfit_soldier_description">
		<text>A soldier's standard set of equipment is a lightweight army body armor vest. Protects against pistol bullets and shrapnel quite effectively. But poor protection from anomalous influences.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="outfit_soldier_name">
		<text>Light body armor</text>
	</string>


	<string id="protection_outfit_description">
		<text>Features: Protects the body from severe chemical damage. Specificity: with prolonged use, it becomes unusable - damaged and torn.  High quality modified Scientific EX-04 jumpsuit. Added torso protection from bullet and shrapnel damage. Designed to outfit the guards of scientific expeditions. Effective protection against radiation and biological anomalies. Resistant to chemically aggressive environments and other harmful effects to the body.\nProtection level against radiation - high\nProtection level against damage and shock - medium\nProtection level against bullets - low\nProtection level against anomalous activity - high</text>
	</string>
	<string id="protection_outfit_name">
		<text>Scientific EXP-4</text>
	</string>


	<string id="scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>Features: Protects against fire, acid, gases, a variety of anomalous effects and burning fluff. Increases protection against physical damage. Carries two oxygen tanks.  Specificity: with prolonged use, it becomes unusable - damaged and torn.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>Protective overalls</text>
	</string>



	<string id="stalker_outfit_description">
		<text>A hazmat suit. Features: Special coating that protects against jelly and burning fluff. Protects the body from anomalousities and damage. There is no sealed helmet. Specificity: with prolonged use, it becomes unusable - damaged and torn.\nProtection level against radiation - medium\nProtection level against damage and impact - medium\nProtection level against bullets - medium\nProtection level against anomalous activity - medium\nProtection level against anomalous activity - medium</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_name">
		<text>Average stalker gear</text>
	</string>



	<string id="mp_exo_outfit_description">
		<text>Features: Special coating that protects against jelly and burning fluff. The chest and back are protected by internal bio - metal plates. Protects the body from anomalousities and damage. Sealed metal-plastic helmet. Carries two oxygen tanks. Specificity: with prolonged use, it becomes unusable - damaged and torn. The exoskeleton provides excellent protection against bullet and shrapnel damage, but reduces mobility. Vulnerable to armor-piercing rounds.\nProtection level against radiation - medium\nProtection level against damage and impact - medium\nProtection level against bullets - medium\nProtection level against anomalous activity - medium\nProtection level against anomalous activity - medium</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_exo_outfit_name">
		<text>Exoskeleton</text>
	</string>


	<string id="mp_scientific_outfit_description">
		<text>This jumpsuit is designed for exploratory activities in the Zone. Equipped with a closed-circuit breathing system, as well as a built-in anomalous field suppression system, making it an excellent defense against anomalies. Due to weak defenses, he's very vulnerable. Features a built-in container for carrying artifacts.\nProtection level against radiation - high\nProtection level against damage and shock - medium\nProtection level against bullets - low\nProtection level against anomalous activity - high</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mp_scientific_outfit_name">
		<text>Science jumpsuit</text>
	</string>

</string_table>
